. >> GOOD AFTERNOON.
WELCOME TO THE MARCH 10TH 2026 REGULAR MEETING OF THE SAN
FRANCISCO BOARD OF SUPERVISORS. MADAM CLERK, WILL YOU PLEASE
CALL THE ROLL? >> THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT.
SUPERVISOR CHAN CHAN PRESIDENT SUPERVISOR CHEN CHEN PRESENT
SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY PRESENT SUPERVISOR FIELDER
FIELDER PRESENT SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD PRESENT
SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN PRESIDENT MANDEL MEN PRESENT SUPERVISOR
MELGAR MELGAR PRESENT SUPERVISOR SADR SADR PRESENT
SUPERVISOR CHERYL SHERRELL PRESENT SUPERVISOR WALTON
WALTON PRESENT AND SUPERVISOR WONG WONG PRESENT MR. PRESIDENT
ALL MEMBERS ARE PRESENT. >> THANK YOU MADAM CLERK.
THE SAN FRANCISCO BOARD OF SUPERVISORS ACKNOWLEDGES THAT
WE ARE ON THE UNCEDED ANCESTRAL HOMELAND OF THE ROMA TO SALONI
WHO ARE THE ORIGINAL INHABITANTS OF THE SAN
FRANCISCO PENINSULA. AS THE INDIGENOUS STEWARDS OF
THIS LAND AND IN ACCORDANCE WITH THEIR TRADITIONS THE RAW
MATERIAL AND WE HAVE NEVER CEDED LOST NOR FORGOTTEN THEIR
RESPONSIBILITIES AS THE CARETAKERS OF THIS PLACE AS
WELL AS FOR ALL PEOPLES WHO RESIDE IN THEIR TRADITIONAL
TERRITORY. AS GUESTS WE RECOGNIZE THAT WE
BENEFIT FROM LIVING AND WORKING ON THEIR TRADITIONAL HOMELANDS.
WE WISH TO PAY OUR RESPECTS BY ACKNOWLEDGING THE ANCESTORS,
ELDERS AND RELATIVES OF THE RAW MATERIAL OWNING COMMUNITY
AND BY AFFIRMING THEIR SOVEREIGN RIGHTS AS FIRST
PEOPLES. COLLEAGUES, WILL YOU JOIN ME
IN RECITING THE PLEDGE OF ALLEGIANCE?
I PLEDGE ALLEGIANCE TO THE FLAG OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA
AND TO THE REPUBLIC FOR WHICH IT STANDS ONE NATION UNDER GOD
INDIVISIBLE WITH UNITY AND JUSTICE FOR ALL.
>> ON BEHALF OF OUR BOARD I'D LIKE TO ACKNOWLEDGE THE STAFF
AT S.F. GOV TV TODAY THAT IS ESPECIALLY SUE'S ENOS.
THEY RECORD EACH OF OUR MEETING, EACH OF OUR MEETINGS
AND MAKE THEM TRANSCRIBED TRANSCRIPTS AVAILABLE TO THE
PUBLIC ONLINE. >> MADAM CLERK, WHY DON'T WE GO
TO OUR 2 P.M. SPECIAL ORDER? >> THE MAYOR'S APPEARANCE?
YES. THE SPECIAL ORDER AT 2 P.M. IS
THE APPEARANCE BY THE HONORABLE MAYOR DANIEL LURIE.
THERE BEING NO QUESTIONS SUBMITTED FROM ELIGIBLE MEMBERS
REPRESENTING DISTRICTS FIVE THROUGH EIGHT.
THE MAYOR MAY ADDRESS THE BOARD FOR UP TO FIVE MINUTES.
>> WELCOME, MR. MAYOR. THANK YOU.
BOARD PRESIDENT. GOOD AFTERNOON, EVERYONE.
MEMBERS OF THE BOARD YOU ALL KNOW THAT OUR CITY CHARTER IS
ONE IS ONE OF THE LONGEST IN THE COUNTRY.
IT'S BLOATED AND IT'S BROKEN. THAT'S WHY PRESIDENT MANDELL
MEN AND I ARE PROPOSING REFORMS TO CLEAN UP OUR CHARTER
AND MAKE OUR CITY'S GOVERNMENT MORE ACCOUNTABLE TO THE
RESIDENTS WE SERVE. FIRST WE ARE GOING TO FIX THE
CITY'S BROKEN CONTRACTING SYSTEM TO MAKE SURE THAT OUR
TAX DOLLARS ARE SPENT EFFICIENTLY AND TRANSPARENTLY.
RIGHT NOW CITY CONTRACTING IS TOO EXPENSIVE, TOO SLOW AND TOO
POLITICAL. NOT ONLY DO DIFFERENT
DEPARTMENTS HAVE DIFFERENT RULES BUT MORE THAN A DOZEN
DEPARTMENTS CAN BE INVOLVED IN APPROVING JUST ONE CONTRACT.
THIS SLOWS DOWN PROJECTS AND DRIVES UP COSTS AND WE ALL
KNOW WE CAN DO BETTER BY BRINGING CONTRACTING UNDER THE
CITY ADMINISTRATOR. WE CAN SET CONSISTENT CITYWIDE
STANDARDS THAT WILL CUT RED TAPE.
REDUCE DELAYS AND SAVE TAXPAYER DOLLARS.
SECOND, WE'RE GOING TO MAKE OUR BALLOTS SHORTER AND SIMPLER.
IN 2024 OUR SAN FRANCISCO HAS CONSIDERED 15 BALLOT MEASURES
IN THE SAME ELECTION. OAKLAND HAD THREE, SAN JOSE HAD
ONE. OUR PROPOSED CHANGES WOULD
ALLOW A MAJORITY OF THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS TO PUT A MEASURE
ON THE BALLOT AND BRING US CLOSER TO STATE AND OTHER BAY
AREA CITY STANDARDS ON SIGNATURE REQUIREMENTS.
AND IT WOULD ELIMINATE THE MAYOR'S ABILITY TO UNILATERALLY
PLACE A MEASURE ON THE BALLOT. THESE REFORMS WILL MOVE US
IN THE RIGHT DIRECTION AND ENSURE THAT BALLOT MEASURES
REFLECT CITYWIDE PRIORITIES. THIRD ACCOUNTABILITY.
SAN FRANCISCANS EXPECT OUR CITY TO DELIVER WORLD CLASS SERVICES
. BUT RIGHT NOW OUR CHARTER
REWARD REWARDS BUREAUCRACY AND SCATTERS RESPONSIBILITY.
THESE REFORMS WOULD CHANGE THAT TO ENSURE THAT WHEN SAN
FRANCISCANS ELECT A MAYOR THEY KNOW WHO IS RESPONSIBLE FOR
DELIVERING RESULTS. THEY WILL ALLOW THE MAYOR TO
HIRE AND REMOVE DEPARTMENT HEADS WHILE ENSURING THAT
UNELECTED COMMISSIONERS ARE ACCOUNTABLE TO THE LEADERS WHO
APPOINT THEM. THEY WOULD ALSO CREATE
FLEXIBILITY TO REORGANIZE DEPARTMENTS WHEN GOVERNMENT
ISN'T WORKING AS IT SHOULD. SAN FRANCISCANS ELECT PEOPLE TO
RUN THEIR GOVERNMENT AND THOSE LEADERS SHOULD BE ACCOUNTABLE
FOR WHETHER IT WORKS. IF IT DOESN'T.
VOTERS SHOULD KNOW EXACTLY WHO TO HOLD RESPONSIBLE.
THAT'S WHY WE HOLD ELECTIONS. THIS PACKAGE OF REFORMS IS
ABOUT RESULTS. IT'S ABOUT ACCOUNTABILITY.
IT'S ABOUT MAKING CITY HALL WORK FOR SAN FRANCISCO.
THANK YOU. THANK YOU.
BOARD PRESIDENT. I APPRECIATE THE TIME.
THANK YOU, MR. MAYOR. THANK YOU FOR YOUR REMARKS.
THANK YOU FOR THE COLLEGIAL WAY IN WHICH YOU AND YOUR TEAM HAVE
WORKED ON THESE MEASURES OVER THESE LAST SEVERAL MONTHS.
>> THANK YOU, SIR. ALL RIGHT.
SEE YOU. >> THANK YOU.
>> AND WITH THAT, THIS MEET THIS MATTER HAS BEEN DISCUSSED
AND IS NOW FILED. >> MADAM CLERK, THAT TAKES US
BACK TO COMMUNICATIONS. >> THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT.
THE SAN FRANCISCO BOARD OF SUPERVISORS WELCOMES YOU ALL TO
ATTEND THE BOARD MEETING IN PERSON IN THE BOARD'S
LEGISLATIVE CHAMBER ROOM 250 WITHIN CITY HALL ON THE SECOND
FLOOR. AND WHEN YOU'RE NOT ABLE TO BE
HERE YOU CAN CATCH THE LIVE STREAM AT W W W DOT S.F. GOV TV
DOT ORG OR WATCH THE LIVE SHOWING ON S.F. GOV TV'S
CHANNEL 26. IF YOU NEED TO SUBMIT PUBLIC
COMMENT IN WRITING YOU CAN SEND AN EMAIL TO BOSSI AT S.F. GOV
DAWG. OR SEND AN EMAIL TO OR USE THE
U.S. POSTAL SERVICE. ADDRESS THE ENVELOPE TO THE SAN
FRANCISCO BOARD OF SUPERVISORS. THE NUMBER ONE DR. CARLTON.
BE A GOOD LITTLE PLACE CITY HALL ROOM TWO FOR FOUR SAN
FRANCISCO, CALIFORNIA 94102. IF YOU NEED TO MAKE A
REASONABLE ACCOMMODATION FOR A FUTURE MEETING UNDER THE
AMERICANS WITH DISABILITY ACT OR TO REQUEST LANGUAGE
ASSISTANCE, CONTACT THE CLERK'S OFFICE AT LEAST A TWO BUSINESS
DAYS IN ADVANCE BY CALLING (415) 554-5184 AND THROUGH A
PRIOR ARRANGEMENT MR. PRESIDENT.
TODAY THE FIRST SPEAKER DURING GENERAL PUBLIC COMMENT WILL BE
A CALLER WHO HAS REQUESTED AN ADA ACCOMMODATION.
THANK YOU MEMBERS. THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK.
LET'S GO TO APPROVAL OF OUR MEETING MINUTES.
>> YES. APPROVAL OF THE FEBRUARY 3RD,
2026 BOARD MEETING MINUTES. COLLEAGUES, COULD I HAVE A
MOTION TO APPROVE THE MINUTES AS PRESENTED MOVED BY CHAN
SECONDED BY DORSEY. >> MADAM CLERK, COULD YOU
PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON THE MINUTES AS PRESENTED?
SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I.E. SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER I.E.
SUPERVISOR OF MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I SUPERVISOR MANDOLIN II MANDOLIN
I SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SADR SADR I
SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I
SUPERVISOR ONE WONG I SUPERVISOR CHAN CHIN I
AND SUPERVISOR CHEN CHIN EITHER ARE LEBANESE WITHOUT OBJECTION
THE MINUTES WILL BE APPROVED AFTER PUBLIC COMMENT AS
PRESENTED MADAM CLERK LET'S GO TO OUR CONSENT AGENDA PLEASE
CALL ITEMS ONE THROUGH FOUR ITEMS ONE THROUGH FOUR ARE ON
CONSENT. THESE ITEMS ARE CONSIDERED TO
BE ROUTINE IF A MEMBER OBJECTS AN ITEM MAY BE REMOVED
AND CONSIDERED SEPARATELY. >> PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON
ITEMS ONE THROUGH FOUR SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I
SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER I SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I
SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN HI MANDEL MEN I'M SUPERVISOR MELGAR
MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SADR SADR I SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I
SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I SUPERVISOR WANG WONG I
SUPERVISOR CHAN CHEN I AND SUPERVISOR CHEN CHEN EITHER
ARE LEBANESE WITHOUT OBJECTION THESE ORDINANCES ARE FINALLY
PASSED MADAM CLERK LET'S GO TO NEW BUSINESS PLEASE CALL ITEM
NUMBER FIVE ITEM NUMBER FIVE THIS IS A RESOLUTION TO APPROVE
THE FOURTH AMENDMENT TO A CONTRACT SFM 2-2 18 DASH 48
ARMED AND UNARMED SECURITY SERVICES AGREEMENT BETWEEN THE
CITY AND COUNTY AND UNIVERSAL PROTECTION SERVICE LP DOING
BUSINESS AS ALLIED UNIVERSAL SECURITY SERVICES TO EXTEND THE
TERM BY ONE YEAR FOR A TOTAL TERM APRIL 1ST 2020 THROUGH
MARCH 31ST 2027 TO INCREASE THE AMOUNT BY APPROXIMATELY 5.9
MILLION FOR A NEW TOTAL AMOUNT OF APPROXIMATE 65 MILLION.
>> LET'S TAKE THIS ITEM SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL.
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED.
MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM NUMBER SIX.
>> ITEM SIX THIS IS A RESOLUTION TO APPROVE
AND AUTHORIZE A GRANT OF A PERMANENT EASEMENT ON SFP USES
SAN FRANCISCO PUBLIC UTILITY COMMISSION'S PROPERTY LOCATED
AT 1800 GERALD AVENUE TO CONSIST OF AN EASEMENT OF
APPROXIMATELY 3000FT2 OF LAND WITHIN AS OF PASSES SOUTHEAST
WATER POLLUTION CONTROL PLANT BETWEEN THE CITY AND PACIFIC
GAS AND ELECTRIC FOR THE PURPOSE OF REPLACING
AND RELOCATING SFP USES EXISTING SOLIDS TREATMENT
FACILITIES AT ITS SOUTHEAST WATER POLLUTION CONTROL PLANT
WITH MORE RELIABLE, EFFICIENT AND MODERN TECHNOLOGIES
AND FACILITIES AT NO COST FOR A TERM EFFECTIVE UPON APPROVAL OF
THE RESOLUTION AND RECORD ATION OF THE AGREEMENT BY THE CITY BY
THE CITY'S ASSESSOR RECORDER UNTIL PGE SURRENDERS OR
ABANDONS THE EASEMENT AREA OR THE AGREEMENT IS TERMINATED
AND TO DETERMINE THAT THE GRANT OF THE EASEMENT AT NO COST WILL
SERVE A PUBLIC PURPOSE BY DELIVERING AN INCREASED NATURAL
GAS SUPPLY TO SFP USES EXISTING SOUTHEAST WATER POLLUTION
CONTROL PLANT AND ITS NEW BIOSOLIDS DIGESTERS FACILITIES
AND TO ADOPT THE APPROPRIATE FINDINGS.
SUPERVISOR FIELDER THANKS PRESIDENT GENTLEMAN NORMALLY
THIS THIS ITEM IS SOMETHING THAT WOULD NOT REALLY CATCH MY
ATTENTION BUT I DO UNDERSTAND THAT ACCORDING TO AS OF P C THE
IMPROVEMENTS THAT THIS EASEMENT WILL GRANT REPLACES OLD SOLIDS
TREATMENT SYSTEMS WITH NEW TECHNOLOGY AND SUPPORTING
BIOGAS WHICH I I THINK MAKES A TON OF SENSE FOR HELPING TO
MEET OUR CLIMATE GOALS. BUT IN ORDER TO MAKE THIS
REGENERATIVE ENERGY WORK, THE PLANT ACTUALLY NEEDS MORE
NATURAL GAS AND PGE ALREADY SUPPLIES GAS TO THE SITE AND SO
THEY'RE GOING TO ALSO BE BE INSTALLING THAT AND THIS
FACILITY NEEDS EXTRA GAS AND KNOWING WHAT OUR CLIMATE
GOALS ARE I JUST CANNOT SUPPORT SUPPORT THE CONCEPT TO THIS.
>> I UNDERSTAND THAT THIS WAS KIND OF BASED ON INFORMATION
FROM 15 AND TECHNOLOGY 15 YEARS AGO BUT UNDERSTANDING WHAT THIS
PUTS, WHAT THIS MEANS FOR OUR CLIMATE GOALS I CANNOT SUPPORT
AND SO I'LL BE NOT SUPPORTING IT.
>> THANK YOU. DO WE HAVE ANYONE FROM THE PSC
HERE? COME ON UP.
>> I'D LIKE TO WELCOME MR. SPENCE.
>> I'D LIKE TO TRY TO ADDRESS THAT CONCERN.
THANK YOU. PRESIDENT AND THEN JEREMY SPITZ
WITH THE SFP U.S. GOVERNMENT AFFAIRS.
THANK YOU. PROFESSOR FIELDER FOR THE
CONCERN. I JUST WANT TO CLARIFY ONE
THING THIS EASEMENT ISN'T FOR THE BIO GAS PORTION OF THE
BIOSOLIDS DIGESTER FACILITIES PROJECT.
IT IS JUST TO PROVIDE ADDITIONAL NATURAL GAS TO HEAT
THE NEW LARGER DIGESTERS WHICH IS IMPORTANT FOR THE BIOSOLIDS
DIGESTION PROCESS. ONE OF THE REASONS WHY WE NEED
ADDITIONAL NATURAL GAS AND SORRY THIS IS GOING TO BE A
LITTLE BIT IN THE WEEDS HERE BUT WE MADE THE DECISION AS
PART OF THE DESIGN PROCESS TO MOVE AWAY FROM A COGENERATION
PROCESS WHERE WE ACTUALLY USED THE NATURAL ARE THE BIO GAS
THAT THE PROCESS CREATES ONSITE TO CREATE ELECTRICITY AND THEN
FEED THAT BACK IN TO CREATE HEAT WHICH IS PART OF THE
PROCESS WE MADE THE DECISION TO MOVE AWAY FROM THAT BECAUSE IT
HAD AN ENVIRONMENTAL JUSTICE IMPACT ON THE COMMUNITY NEARBY
EXCUSE ME. SO WE FULLY UNDERSTAND YOUR
CONCERN WITH HAVING ADDITIONAL NATURAL GAS BUT WE JUST THOUGHT
THAT THIS WAS THE BEST THE BEST SOLUTION FOR THE COMMUNITY
AND THE MOST VALUE FOR THE PROJECT.
THANK YOU, MR. SPITZ. MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL THE
ROLL ON ITEM SIX. >> SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I
SUPERVISOR FIELDER. FIELDER NO.
SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN RIGHT
RANDLEMAN I SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SADR SADR I
SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I
SUPERVISOR WONG WONG I SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN I
AND SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN I THERE ARE TEN EYES AND ONE NO
WITH SUPERVISOR FIELDER VOTING NO THE RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED
MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM SEVEN ITEM SEVEN THIS IS A
MOTION TO APPOINT ELINOR RIVKIN RESIDENCY REQUIREMENT WAIVED TO
THE ASSESSMENT APPEALS BOARD NUMBER THREE TERM ENDING
SEPTEMBER 7TH 2026 PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON ITEM SEVEN
SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I SUPERVISOR FIELDER PEELED HER
EYES SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN HI
MANDELL MAN I SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SAUDER
SAUDER I SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL EYES SUPERVISOR WALTON
WALTON I SUPERVISOR ONE WONG I SUPERVISOR CHEN CHEN I
AND SUPERVISOR CHEN CHEN EITHER ARE LEBANESE WITHOUT OBJECTION
THE MOTION IS WITHOUT OBJECTION.
>> YES THE MOTION IS APPROVED MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM
EIGHT ITEM EIGHT WAS REFERRED WITHOUT RECOMMENDATION FROM THE
RULES COMMITTEE. IT'S AN ORDINANCE TO APPROVE
THE POLICE SURVEILLANCE TECHNOLOGY POLICY FOR
ELECTRONIC LOCATION TRACKING DEVICES AND TO MAKE THE
REQUIRED FINDINGS. >> CHAIR WALTON, THANK YOU SO
MUCH. PRESIDENT MET AND COLLEAGUES AS
YOU KNOW THIS WAS REFERRED TO THIS BODY WITHOUT
RECOMMENDATION FROM COMMITTEE AT THE TIME THE COMMITTEE
MEETING THEIR WERE QUESTIONS THAT I HAD AND THERE ARE ALSO
QUESTIONS THAT OTHER COLLEAGUES AND COMMUNITY HAVE ABOUT THIS
ORDINANCE. SO I WOULD LIKE TO CONTINUE
THIS ORDINANCE UNTIL OUR MARCH 24TH MEETING.
FEW OF THE MAJOR REASONS IS BECAUSE THERE ARE CONCERNS
ABOUT WARRANTLESS TRACKERS, LACK OF DATA, COST CONCERNS,
RELIABILITY AND OF COURSE ALWAYS THE PROTECTION OF CIVIL
LIBERTIES. >> AND I WOULD LIKE TO MAKE A
MOTION TO CONTINUE TO THE 24TH CHAIR.
WALTON'S MADE A MOTION TO CONTINUE THIS UNTIL THE 24TH.
IS THERE A SECOND SECONDED BY FIELDER SUPERVISE THE CHAIR
THANK YOU PRESIDENT AMEND DOMAIN AND THANK YOU SUPERVISOR
WALTON FOR MAKING THAT MOTION. I AM IN SUPPORT OF THE MOTION
TO FOR CONTINUANCE ALLOWING A COUPLE OF THINGS.
I HAVE SOME QUESTIONS BOTH ON THE EXISTING TECHNOLOGY THAT IS
AVAILABLE STAR CHASE SEEMS TO BE THE TECHNOLOGY IN QUESTION
AND ALSO THE ONLY TECHNOLOGY THAT IS CURRENTLY AVAILABLE FOR
A PILOT USE. I HAVE SOME QUESTIONS ABOUT THE
TECHNOLOGY ITSELF. I WOULD LIKE TO HAVE SOME MORE
TIME HELP ME UNDERSTAND BETTER UNDERSTAND THE TECHNOLOGY.
I CERTAINLY ALSO HAVE QUESTIONS ABOUT THE YOU KNOW, BASICALLY
ALSO THE POLICY INSURING WHETHER THIS POLICY ALSO ENSURE
THE RIGHTS TO FOURTH AMENDMENT ALLOWING A TRACKER FOR A MOVING
VEHICLE. AND SO THOSE ARE SOME OF MY
QUESTIONS. I HOPE TO HAVE ANSWERS TO.
BUT BY THE TIME WE MEET AGAIN AND VOTE ON THIS LEGISLATION.
>> BUT I CERTAINLY HOPE THAT IN EVENTS THAT WE I DO HAVE
THOSE ANSWER. I STILL HOPE THAT WHEN WE VOTE
ON THIS I KNOW THAT TODAY WE'RE NOT READY TO HAVE PERHAPS
PERCENTERS IN THE CHAMBER TO ANSWER THOSE QUESTIONS PUBLICLY
OR ARE WE DO WE HAVE SOMEONE THAT'S HERE NOW THAT'S ABLE TO
ANSWER? >> WE DO.
GREAT. GOOD AFTERNOON PRESIDENT
RANDALL MIN SUPERVISORS I'M CARL MACEDO GOVERNMENT AFFAIRS
MANAGER FOR THE POLICE DEPARTMENT.
IF YOU'D LIKE SUPERVISOR CHAN I CAN JUST JUMP RIGHT IN AND
EXPLAIN A LITTLE BIT ABOUT THE POLICIES IN QUESTION WHICH IS
STAR CHASE YOU'RE CORRECT. STAR CHASE IS A PURSUIT
MITIGATION TOOL. IT'S NOT A PURSUIT ENHANCEMENT
TOOL. IT'S OVERALL GOAL IS TO REDUCE
DANGEROUS HIGH SPEED PURSUITS WITHIN THE CITY.
IT IS A JEEPS PROJECTILE LAUNCHER THAT WOULD AFFIX TO A
CAR REGARDING FOURTH AMENDMENT RIGHTS UNDER EXIGENT
CIRCUMSTANCES ONLY WOULD THE POLICE DEPARTMENT BE ABLE TO
USE STARR CHASE TO TAG A VEHICLE SO THAT IT WOULDN'T
HAVE TO PURSUE THE VEHICLE AND WOULD BE ABLE TO TRACK IT
IN OTHER SCENARIOS THE DEPARTMENT WOULD REQUEST A
WARRANT OBVIOUSLY APPROVED BY A JUDGE TO CONTINUE TRACKING BUT
IN EXIGENT CIRCUMSTANCES INCLUDING HOT PURSUITS OF
VEHICLES, THE DEPARTMENT WOULD BE ALLOWED UNDER THE POLICY
AND IT IS MY UNDERSTANDING THAT AS I'M LEARNING THAT OAKLAND
POLICE DEPARTMENT HAS DETERMINED THAT STAR CHASE IS
NOT A FUNCTIONING TECHNOLOGY WELL I SHOULDN'T SAY THE
TECHNOLOGY ITSELF. IS THAT JUST THE START?
CHASE IS SELF AS AS EQUIPMENT THAT THEY PROVIDE IS NOT
MEETING THE STANDARDS OR MEETING THE GOAL TO TO BE FULLY
UTILIZED. >> COULD YOU WALK US THROUGH SO
I CAN'T SPEAK TO OAKLAND'S EXPERIENCE DIRECTLY THOUGH I
DID READ SOME PUBLIC REPORTING ABOUT THEIR USE OF STAR CHASE
AND THERE ARE A COUPLE OF DIFFERENCES BETWEEN OPIOID USE
POLICY AS WELL AS SS PD POLICY IN OAKLAND THEY REQUIRED A
WARRANT AFTER TAGGING THE VEHICLE IN ORDER TO TRACK IT AT
ALL. >> THAT WAS THEIR POLICY.
THAT SORT OF DEFEATS THE PURPOSE OF IT IN THESE EXIGENT
CIRCUMSTANCES THAT DELAYED TIME WOULD NOT ALLOW POLICE TO BE
ABLE TO APPREHEND A VEHICLE CONTEMPORANEOUSLY WHICH IS THE
GOAL HERE. SO THAT'S THE MAJOR DIFFERENCE
I KNOW IN PUBLIC REPORTING OAKLAND SAID THAT THEY ONLY USE
STAR CHASING FIVE YEARS A HANDFUL OF TIMES AND ONLY WERE
ABLE TO SUCCESSFULLY TAG ONE VEHICLE.
AS YOU MENTIONED, THIS IS A PILOT PROGRAM OR PILOT
TECHNOLOGY UNDER PROP E SO THE DEPARTMENT FIRST DEPLOYED STAR
CHASE IN DECEMBER 2020 FOR THROUGHOUT THE CALENDAR YEAR OF
2025 THE DEPARTMENT HAD 22 DEPLOYMENTS OF STAR CHASE
AND 17 SUCCESSFUL TAGS ON VEHICLES DURING THAT TIME SOME
OF THOSE DID LEAD TO EITHER VEHICLE RECOVERY OR THE SAFE
APPREHENSION OF SUSPECTS. SO THE PURPOSE OF THE PILOT IS
TO SEE WHETHER OR NOT IT WOULD WORK FOR THE SPEEDY.
SO FAR WITHIN THAT ONE YEAR PILOT WE HAVE SEEN SUCCESS
AND AGAIN IT IS A PURSUIT MITIGATION TOOL TO REDUCE THE
NEED FOR HIGH SPEED PURSUITS THROUGHOUT THE CITY OBVIOUSLY
BECAUSE OUR DEPLOYMENT IS LIMITED WE ONLY HAVE SIX
MOUNTED ON VEHICLES. IT WON'T WORK IN EVERY
SITUATION BUT IT WILL MITIGATE SOME.
>> THANK YOU. I DO APPRECIATE COLLEAGUES.
I HOPE THAT I MAY IF I MAY HAVE JUST TWO WEEKS TIME PERIOD.
>> I DO HAVE MORE QUESTIONS BUT I ALSO WOULD LIKE TO DO A
LITTLE BIT MORE OF A HOMEWORK AGAIN AROUND THE FOURTH
AMENDMENT AND POLICY WISE AND HELP ME ALLOW ME TO HAVE
THAT TIME SO I APPRECIATE THE POTENTIAL TWO WEEKS CONTINUANCE
ALLOWING US TO HAVE MORE IN-DEPTH CONVERSATION AND THANK
YOU SEE NO ONE ELSE ON THE ROSTER.
I AM INCLINED TO SUPPORT THE REQUEST FOR A TWO WEEK
CONTINUANCE. I THINK YOU KNOW AS A MATTER OF
COLLEGIALITY THAT'S A REASONABLE THING FOR COLLEAGUES
TO REQUEST AND THERE ISN'T ANY PARTICULAR REASON WHY THIS
NEEDS TO GET DEALT WITH SOONER. I FULLY ANTICIPATE THAT I AT
LEAST WILL BE SUPPORTING THIS THIS ITEM IN TWO WEEKS.
I DID SUPPORT PROP B I THINK YOU KNOW SAN FRANCISCO
AND OAKLAND CAN TAKE DIFFERENT PATHS ON PUBLIC SAFETY AND YOU
KNOW IN THIS CASE I THINK SHOULD BUT WE CAN TALK ABOUT
THAT MORE IN TWO WEEKS. MADAM CLERK COULD YOU CALL THE
ROLL ON THE MOTION TO CONTINUE ON THE MOTION TO CONTINUE TO
ITEM EIGHT TO MARCH 24TH? SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I
SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER I'S SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I
SUPERVISOR MANDOLIN RIGHT MANDOLIN I SUPERVISOR MELGAR
MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SADR SADR I SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I
SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I SUPERVISOR WONG WONG EYES
SUPERVISOR CHEN CHAN I AND SUPERVISOR CHEN CHEN EITHER
ARE LEBANESE WITHOUT OBJECTION THE MOTION IS APPROVED MADAM
CLERK LET'S GO TO OUR COMMITTEE REPORTS ITEMS 13 THROUGH 19
WERE CONSIDERED BY THE GOVERNMENT AUDIT AND OVERSIGHT
COMMITTEE AT A REGULAR MEETING ON THURSDAY MARCH FIFTH, 2026
AND WERE FORWARDED AS COMMITTEE REPORTS ITEM 13 THROUGH 19 AH
SEVEN ORDINANCES THAT AUTHORIZE THE SETTLEMENT OF LAWSUITS
FILED BY VARIOUS ENTITIES AGAINST THE CITY FOR ITEM 13.
THIS IS THIS LAWSUIT INVOLVES AN EMPLOYMENT DISPUTE FILED BY
KEESHA HENDERSON FOR 55,000 FOR ITEM 14.
THIS LAWSUIT INVOLVES AN EMPLOYMENT DISPUTE FILED BY
RENEE OWENS FOR 800,000 FOR ITEM 15.
THE LAWSUIT INVOLVES ALLEGED ELDER ABUSE FILED BY LAND FARM
AT ALL 4 OR 500,000. THIS ITEM 16 IS AN UNMITIGATED
CLAIM FILED BY WPP GROUP USA INC FOR 350,000.
THIS CLAIM INVOLVES A REFUND OF GROSS RECEIPTS AND HOMELESSNESS
GROSS RECEIPTS, TAXES FOR ITEM 17.
IT'S AN ON LITIGATED CLAIM FILED BY ROBERT TYPHOON FOR
32,500. THIS CLAIM INVOLVES PROPERTY
DAMAGE ARISING FROM FLOODING ALLEGED TO BE CAUSED BY A WATER
SERVICE LINE RUPTURE FOR ITEM 18 THIS IS AN UNMITIGATED CLAIM
FILED BY EVER IN CAPITAL CORPORATION FOR APPROXIMATELY
2.2 MILLION. THE CLAIM INVOLVES A REFUND OF
GROSS RECEIPTS AND HOMELESSNESS GROSS RECEIPTS TAXES AND FOR
ITEM 19 THIS IS A SETTLEMENT OF A SITUATION SETTLEMENT OF A
CITATION ISSUED BY THE BAY AREA AIR QUALITY MANAGEMENT DISTRICT
FOR $30,450. THIS CITATION INVOLVES AN
ALLEGED A PUBLIC NUISANCE STEMMING FROM THE DISCHARGE OF
CHEMICAL AGENTS. >> PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON
THESE ITEMS ON ITEMS 13 THROUGH 19 SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY
EYES SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER I SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I
SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN ALL RIGHT MANDEL MAN I SUPERVISOR MELGAR
MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SAUTER SAUTER I SUPERVISOR CHERYL
CHERYL I SUPERVISOR WALTON HI WALTON I SUPERVISOR WONG WONG I
SUPERVISOR CHEN CHEN I AND SUPERVISOR CHIN CHEN I
THERE ARE 11 EYES WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTIONS ARE
ADOPTED MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM 20 ITEM 20 THIS ITEM WAS
CONSIDERED BY THE LAND USE AND TRANSPORTATION COMMITTEE AT
A REGULAR MEETING ON MONDAY MARCH 9TH, 2026 AND WAS
RECOMMENDED AS AMENDED WITH A NEW TITLE.
ITEM 20 IS A RESOLUTION ADDING THE COMMEMORATIVE STREET NAME
JAMES RICHARDS WAY ON OAKDALE AVENUE BETWEEN THIRD STREET TO
NEWHALL STREET AND WE CAN TAKE THIS ITEM OH NO WE CANNOT.
SUPERVISOR WALTON THANK YOU SO MUCH PRESIDENT MADAM AND I JUST
WANT TO ONE THANK THE LAND USE COMMITTEE FOR HEARING THIS ITEM
ON YESTERDAY AND THANK ALL THE CO-SPONSORS FOR MAKING SURE
THAT THIS MOVE FORWARD TO TODAY'S MEETING.
THANK YOU. ALL RIGHT.
AND NOW YOU CAN TAKE THIS ITEM SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT
OBJECTION THE RESOLUTIONS ADOPTED.
>> AND MADAM CLERK, LET'S GO TO OUR 230 SPECIAL ORDER YES.
>> THE 230 SPECIAL ORDER IS THE RECOGNITION OF COMMENDATIONS
FOR MERITORIOUS SERVICE TO THE CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN
FRANCISCO AND I THINK TODAY WE'RE STARTING WITH DISTRICT
TEN SUPERVISOR WALTON. I WOULD THANK YOU SO MUCH,
PRESIDENT MADAM AND COLLEAGUES TODAY I RISE TO RECOGNIZE
AND COMMEND JESSICA CAMPOS FOR HER EXTRAORDINARY COMMITMENT TO
COMMUNITY EQUITY AND PUBLIC SERVICE HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO
AS THE DAUGHTER OF MEXICAN IMMIGRANTS, JESSICA BRINGS NOT
ONLY PROFESSIONAL EXPERTISE BUT DEEPLY ROOTED LIVED EXPERIENCE
TO HER WORK. >> BORN AND RAISED ALONE IN SAN
FRANCISCO AND DALY CITY BORDER NEAR THE COW PALACE, SHE
UNDERSTANDS FIRSTHAND THE CHALLENGES MANY FAMILIES FACE
WHEN NAVIGATING SYSTEMS AND INSTITUTIONS THAT WERE NOT
BUILT WITH THEIR CULTURES, VALUES AND IDENTITIES IN MIND.
THAT PERSPECTIVE GROUNDS HER LEADERSHIP AND CULTURAL
HUMILITY, COMPASSION AND A DEEP RESPECT FOR COMMUNITY.
JESSICA CURRENTLY SERVES AS THE DIRECTOR OF OUTREACH
AND ENGAGEMENT FOR THE SAN FRANCISCO HUMAN RIGHTS
COMMISSION WHERE SHE LEADS COMMUNITY CENTERED STRATEGIES
THAT STRENGTHEN THE TRUST BETWEEN RESIDENTS
AND GOVERNMENT THROUGH HER WORK .
SHE ENSURES THAT CITY INITIATIVES ARE INFORMED BY
LIVED EXPERIENCE AND THAT EQUITY IS NOT JUST SOMETHING
TALKED ABOUT BUT SOMETHING THAT IS ACTIVELY IMPLEMENTED TO
CREATE REAL AND LASTING CHANGE ACROSS OUR MULTIRACIAL
AND MULTILINGUAL COMMUNITIES. >> BEFORE THIS ROW, JESSICA
SERVED AS A COMMUNITY ENGAGEMENT LEAD AT THE SAN
FRANCISCO OFFICE OF RACIAL EQUITY WHERE SHE WORKED TO
CONNECT RESIDENTS DIRECTLY TO POLICY EFFORTS FOCUSED ON
ELIMINATING RACIAL DISPARITIES AND PRIOR TO HER WORK IN CITY
GOVERNMENT SHE SERVED AS THE SENIOR MANAGER OF A HEAD START
AND EARLY HEAD START PROGRAM IN DISTRICT TEN SUPPORTING SOME
OF SAN FRANCISCO'S MOST VULNERABLE FAMILIES.
THROUGH HER LEADERSHIP SHE CREATED ENVIRONMENTS WHERE
CHILDREN EDUCATORS AND FAMILIES WERE EMPOWERED WHILE ALSO
BUILDING CROSS-SECTOR PARTNERSHIPS TO CONNECT
FAMILIES TO HOUSING STABILIZATION, FOOD ACCESS
AND OTHER ESSENTIAL RESOURCES. BUT JESSICA'S COMMITMENT TO
COMMUNITY DOES NOT STOP AT HER JOB TITLE.
SHE CONTINUES TO SERVE AS A BOARD MEMBER FOR ADVANCE
COLLEGE AND HOLDS SEAT 12 ON THE SAN FRANCISCO CHILD CARE
PLANNING AND ADVISORY COUNCIL. SHE SUPPORTS EARLY CARE
EDUCATORS IN SAN FRANCISCO AND VOLUNTEERS HER TIME WITH
NUMEROUS COMMUNITY ORGANIZATIONS IN PARTNERSHIP
WITH SAN FRANCISCO STATE UNIVERSITY.
SHE HELPED DEVELOP PROFESSIONAL LEARNING CIRCLES FOR EDUCATORS
AND TAUGHT COURSE FOCUSED ON COMMUNITY ENGAGEMENT, CIVIC
LEADERSHIP AND ADVOCACY. >> AND ANYONE WHO HAS ATTENDED
ANY COMMUNITY EVENT ACROSS THE CITY KNOWS SOMETHING ELSE ABOUT
JESSICA. SHE SHOWS UP WHETHER IT'S A
NEIGHBORHOOD GATHERING, A COMMUNITY MEETING, A CULTURAL
CELEBRATION OR A RESOURCE FAIR .
JESSICA IS THERE ALWAYS PRESENT ,ALWAYS HELPING?
ALWAYS ADVOCATING FOR ALL OF OUR COMMUNITIES.
JESSICA YOUR LEADERSHIP DEDICATION AND UNWAVERING
PRESENCE IN OUR COMMUNITIES DO NOT GO UNNOTICED.
ON BEHALF OF THE CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN FRANCISCO, IT
IS OUR HONOR TO RECOGNIZE YOU AND THANK YOU FOR THE
INCREDIBLE WORK YOU CONTINUE TO DO FOR OUR CITY.
CONGRATULATIONS AND THANK YOU FOR YOUR SERVICE AND WE MUST
USE OUR LIVES TO MAKE THE WORLD A BETTER PLACE TO LIVE NOT JUST
TO ACQUIRE THINGS. THAT IS WHAT WE ARE PUT ON
EARTH FOR. >> DOLORES HUERTA GOOD
AFTERNOON SUPERVISORS. HAPPY WOMEN'S MONTH.
SUPERVISOR WALTON THANK YOU FOR YOUR ACKNOWLEDGMENTS AND TRULY
HONORED TO BE RECOGNIZED BY SOMEONE WHO HAS GIVEN US AN
EXAMPLE OF WHAT IT IS TO NOT ALLOW PREVIOUS CIRCUMSTANCES TO
DETERMINE OUR FUTURE DESTINATIONS.
AS A DAUGHTER OF MEXICAN MIGRANTS WHO LEFT THEIR HOME
SEEKING FOR A BETTER POSSIBILITY, BOTH MY PARENTS
FOUND THEMSELVES HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO ON BRIGHTON STREET
WHERE THEY MET AND THEN MARRIED TO MY DAD UPON THANK YOU FOR
TEACHING US HOW TO HAVE IMPECCABLE WORK ETHIC
AND COMMUNITY ORGANIZING THROUGH THE YEARS OF YOUR
LEADERSHIP IN THE HISPANIC GROUP OF OUR LADY OF VISITATION
AND SUNNYDALE AVENUE. TO MY MOM I'M A GRACIOUS FATHER
RICARDO THAT MOVIE THAT NOSOTROS POR LA NOT JUST GET
THE KIDS I WAS INSPIRED TO INTERACT NOSOTROS BY THE
TERMINAL LETTERING ON CANVAS AREAS COMO YOU THAT KNOWS
ETIQUETTE I WAS GOING TO THIS GENERAL THESAURUS BUILDING WITH
THAT INTENT THE LOOK ESTABA SIENDO YOU ARE THE REASON WHY I
BECAME AN EDUCATOR I LEARNED VERY YOUNG THAT LIFE IS FULL OF
HARDSHIPS BUT ALSO A LOT OF PEOPLE WHO EXTEND THEIR HANDS
TO HELP. IT TRULY TAKES A VILLAGE.
THESE ARE THE ROOTS THAT I THAT ANCHORED ME TO THE PASSION
AND DEDICATION OF SERVING OUR COMMUNITIES.
I TOO WANT TO BECOME THAT HELPING HAND AND EXPRESS WITH
ACTIONS NOT ONLY WITH WORDS THE IMPACT THAT IT IS TO SHOW UP
AND HAVE AND SUPPORT PEOPLE. MANY OF US HAVE THE PRIVILEGE
TO BE IN SPACES AND TABLES WHERE DECISIONS ARE MADE.
LET'S ALWAYS REMEMBER THAT OUR ROLE IS TO ALWAYS CENTER
COMMUNITY VOICES AND KEEP DOORS THAT WERE ONCE CLOSE TO US WIDE
OPEN FOR OTHERS TO ENTER. THANK YOU TO MY FRIENDS
FAMILIES AND TEAM WHO JOINED US TODAY.
YOU ALL ARE AMAZING AND I AM TRULY FORTUNATE TO HAVE SUCH
DEDICATED AND PASSIONATE COMMUNITY ADVOCATES TO LIVE, TO
LOOK UP TO AND TO WORK ALONGSIDE OF.
THANK YOU AGAIN SUPERVISOR
WRITES NEXT UP FROM DISTRICT 11 SUPERVISOR CHEN.
>> THANK YOU, BOB. PRESIDENT JERRY, MAY I HAVE YOU
GO UP TO THE PODIUM? SHE IS BATHROOM OKAY.
OH, ARE WE MY HONOR IS IN THE LET'S LET'S WELL SO CAN I COME
BACK? >> YEAH.
THANK YOU. >> UM, DISTRICT TWO SUPERVISOR
CHERYL THANK YOU. >> PRESIDENT MANDEL MIN COULD I
WELCOME DANIELLE BURRIS UP TO THE LECTERN, PLEASE?
COLLEAGUES IT IS MY ABSOLUTE HONOR TODAY TO COMMEND DANIELLE
BURRIS FOR HER OUTSTANDING LEADERSHIP AS ONE OF THE
PRESIDENTS OF THE SACRAMENTO STREET MERCHANTS ASSOCIATION
WHERE VERY RECENTLY SHE COMMITTED AND AH COMPLETED AN
ARDUOUS JOURNEY THROUGH GETTING LIGHTS UP ALONG THE CORRIDOR.
AND AS A NEIGHBOR I CAN'T TELL YOU HOW HAPPY I AM FOR YOUR
HARD WORK BUT MORE IMPORTANTLY IT IS AN HONOR TO BE ABLE TO
RECOGNIZE YOU AND YOUR LEADERSHIP TODAY.
>> DANIELLE IS A SAN FRANCISCO NATIVE, AN ENTREPRENEUR, A
RETAILER COMMUNITY BUILDER WHO HAS SPENT MORE THAN 26 YEARS
CREATING INDEPENDENT RETAIL CONCEPTS, SUPPORTING DESIGNERS,
ARTISTS AND SMALL BUSINESSES. A PROUD PRODUCT OF DISTRICT TWO
DANIELLE ATTENDED CONVENT OF THE SACRED HEART UNTIL THIRD
GRADE ÉCOLE NOTRE-DAME DE VICTOIRE THEN UNIVERSITY HIGH
SCHOOL HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO BEFORE GOING ON TO BUILD A
REMARKABLE CAREER ROOTED IN THIS CITY AND IN ITS
NEIGHBORHOODS. DANIELLE BEGAN HER RETAIL
CAREER IN 1999 WHEN SHE OPENED BROWN EYED GIRL ON SACRAMENTO
STREET A DESTINATION THAT BLENDED FASHION INTERIORS
AND LIFESTYLE AND HELPED ESTABLISH PRESIDIO HEIGHTS AS A
HUB FOR INDEPENDENT RETAIL. IN 2004 SHE EXPANDED INTO THE
BRIDAL WORLD WITH AN SOMETHING BLUE A BOUTIQUE KNOWN FOR ITS
HEART AND FOR ITS PERSONALIZED STYLING AND FOR WELCOMING
AND CELEBRATING COUPLES EXCUSE ME FROM ACROSS THE COUNTRY AS
MARRIAGE EQUALITY EXPANDED IN 2009, DANIELLE FOUNDED THE
BAR CODE FIRST ON PIER THREE BRINGING TOGETHER INTERNATIONAL
DESIGNERS, ARTISTS, RETAILERS AND INNOVATORS THROUGH ROTATING
RETAIL RESIDENCIES, MERGING FASHION CULTURE AND MOST
IMPORTANTLY COMMUNITY. BUT BEYOND HER OWN VENTURES,
DANIELLE IS QUIETLY MENTORED COUNTLESS WOMEN ENTREPRENEURS
SHARING THE LESSONS SHE LEARNED FROM BUILDING INDEPENDENT
RETAIL BRANDS IN SAN FRANCISCO. >> YOUR WORK HAS LONG CONNECTED
RETAIL PHILANTHROPY CIVIC ENGAGEMENT THROUGH YOUR
PARTNERSHIP WITH DESIGNERS, NON-PROFITS AND COMMUNITY
ORGANIZATIONS TO SUPPORT CAUSES RANGING FROM ARTS CULTURE TO
SOCIAL JUSTICE AND NEIGHBORHOOD REVITALIZATION.
AND TODAY DANIELLE IS ACTIVELY STRENGTHENING SACRAMENTO STREET
AND HELPING SHAPE THE EMERGING PRESIDIO HEIGHTS FASHION DESIGN
DISTRICT BRINGING TOGETHER MERCHANTS, ARTISTS AND CIVIC
LEADERS TO SUPPORT SMALL BUSINESSES AND NEIGHBORHOOD
EVENTS. AS CO-PRESIDENT OF THE
SACRAMENTO STREET MERCHANTS ASSOCIATION.
YOU HAVE FOSTERED AN INCREDIBLE COMMUNITY AMONG THE SMALL
BUSINESS OWNERS ON THE STREETS AND BROUGHT THE STREET TO LIFE
ESPECIALLY THE NEW STRING LIGHTS.
>> AS WE MENTIONED, DANIELLE EMBODIES WOMEN LEADERSHIP
IN THE BUSINESS WORLD AND I'M SO HONORED TO HAVE HER JOIN US
IN THE CHAMBERS DURING THIS WOMEN'S HISTORY MONTH TO BE
CELEBRATED FOR ALL THAT YOU DO FOR OUR NEIGHBORHOOD AND FOR
OUR CITY. SO DANIELLE, ON BEHALF OF THE
BOARD OF SUPER ADVISORS AND MORE IMPORTANTLY JUST ME
PERSONALLY, THANK YOU FOR BEING SUCH A WONDERFUL FRIEND.
THANK YOU FOR BEING SUCH A WONDERFUL LEADER IN OUR CITY
AND THANK YOU FOR BEING YOU. AND WITH THAT THE FLOOR IS
YOURS. >> WELL, FIRST OFF, THANK YOU
SUPERVISOR CHERYL AND THE ENTIRE BOARD FOR THIS HONOR
DURING WOMEN'S HISTORY MONTH. AND JUST AFTER INTERNATIONAL
WOMEN'S DAY. TO BE HONEST, I'M EXPERIENCING
NOW WHAT IT'S LIKE TO BE A ROOM WITH ALL OF YOUR HEROES.
>> WHAT YOU GUYS DO FOR THIS CITY MEANS SO MUCH TO US EVERY
SINGLE DAY AND I SAY THAT FOR EVERY MERCHANT ESPECIALLY
IN THIS LAST YEAR AND A HALF YEAR, YEAR AND A HALF ALMOST
IN 1999 ENCOURAGED BY MY GIRLFRIENDS, I TOOK A RISK
AND OPENED MY FIRST STORE BROWN EYED GIRL.
MY MOM BELIEVED I SHOULD START MY OWN BUSINESS PARTLY BECAUSE
I'M DYSLEXIC AND SHE KNEW I HAD A GIFT FOR IDEATION AND THAT
WORKING IN A RIGID MAN'S CORPORATE STRUCTURE WORLD MIGHT
CRUSH MY CREATIVITY. >> SHE WAS RIGHT WHEN I OPENED
BROWN EYED GIRL I WROTE A MISSION STATEMENT THAT STILL
GUIDES ME TODAY. >> I WANTED TO OFFER THE WOMEN
OF SAN FRANCISCO SOMETHING GREATER THAN OFF THE RACK
RETAIL A PLACE WHERE WOMEN COULD TRULY GATHER AND SHARE
THEIR STORIES. >> BECAUSE WOMEN HAVE STORIES
AND UNLESS THEY ARE TOLD WE LOSE OUR VOICE AS A COMMUNITY.
>> THE IDEA CONTINUED WITH MY BRIDAL STORE AND SOMETHING BLUE
I EXPANDED FROM SELLING BRIDESMAID DRESSES TO FULL
BRIDAL SALON IN 20 12 DURING A MOMENT IN TIME WHEN MARRIAGE
EQUALITY BECAME THE LAW OF THE LAND.
>> I ALMOST NEVER FORGET THE FIRST TIME TWO BRIDES WALKED
INTO MY STORE TOGETHER HAND IN HAND.
>> SUDDENLY I COULD STYLE BOTH OF THEM FOR THEIR WEDDING DAY
NO MATTER WHAT STATE THEY CAME FROM.
WATCHING THAT SHIFT HAPPEN IN REAL TIME WAS INCREDIBLY
POWERFUL. >> TODAY WITH THE BARCODE THE
MISSION CONTINUES TO EVOLVE. >> IT'S ULTIMATELY ABOUT
RAISING THE BAR FOR CREATIVITY, ENTREPRENEURSHIP, CO-CREATION
AND COMMUNITY ESPECIALLY ON SACRAMENTO STREET.
>> ALONG THE WAY I'VE LIVED WITH AN AUTOIMMUNE DISEASE THAT
DISPROPORTIONATELY AFFECTS WOMEN.
BUT THAT EXPERIENCE HAS ONLY STRENGTHENED MY BELIEF THAT
WHEN WOMEN SUPPORT ONE ANOTHER THERE'S VERY LITTLE THAT CAN
STOP US. SO TODAY AND EVERY DAY MY GOAL
IS SIMPLE TO KEEP RAISING THAT BAR FOR CREATIVITY
ENTREPRENEURSHIP AND WOMEN'S VOICES IN A CITY I LOVE SO SO
MUCH
. DISTRICT THREE SUPERVISOR
SAUTER THANK YOU PRESIDENT RANDLEMAN.
COLLEAGUES TODAY I HAVE THE HONOR OF WELCOMING STAFF
AND EIGHTH GRADE STUDENTS FROM ST PETER AND PAUL SCHOOL.
AS WE CELEBRATE THEIR 100TH ANNIVERSARY DR. HARRIS AND THE
STUDENTS WOULD YOU COME ON UP PLEASE?
>> THERE'S A LOT OF THEM SO I'LL START WITH THE HISTORY.
IT WAS IN SEPTEMBER OF 1925. THAT'S THE LEGION GRAMMAR
SCHOOL FOR BOYS FIRST OPENED ITS DOORS WITH TWO CLASSES OF
FIFTH AND SIXTH GRADERS. >> STUDENTS STUDIED ACADEMICS
SUBJECTS ALONGSIDE ALONGSIDE RELIGION, MUSIC AND THE ITALIAN
LANGUAGE. IN 1950 THE SCHOOL WOULD BECOME
COED AFTER A NEARBY ALL GIRLS SCHOOL CLOSED TODAY.
SINCE PETER AND PAUL SCHOOL CONTINUES TO FOLLOW THE
EDUCATIONAL METHOD OF SAINT JOHN BOSCO PROVIDING STUDENTS
WITH A STRONG SPIRITUAL FORMATION GROUNDED IN REASON,
RELIGION AND KINDNESS. FROM PRE-K TO JUNIOR HIGH,
STUDENTS AT SAINTS PETER AND PAUL ARE PART OF A SCHOOL
THAT MODELS AND PROMOTES SOCIAL JUSTICE, COMPASSION, INCLUSION
AND TOLERANCE. SINCE PETER AND PAUL SCHOOL HAS
STOOD FOR ACADEMIC EXCELLENCE IN THE HEART OF NORTH BEACH
SINCE 1925, IT'S LOCATED RIGHT ON WASHINGTON SQUARE PARK.
BUT BEYOND ACADEMICS IT HAS BUILT COMMUNITY.
WHEN ASKED ABOUT THEIR MEMORIES, ALUMNI INCLUDING MY
OFFICE'S OWN VERY OWN EMILY WHO GOT TO SEE HER EIGHTH GRADE
PICTURE LAST WEEK HAVE OFFERED THESE MEMORIES SELLING CASES OF
THE WORLD'S FINEST CHOCOLATE TO HELP PAY TUITION.
>> SIGNATURE EMERALD PLAID UNIFORMS WHICH I'M SURE ALL OF
THE STUDENTS HAVE ALWAYS LOVED .
VISIBLE THROUGHOUT THE NEIGHBORHOOD AS THE KIDS MAKE
THEIR WAY TO SCHOOL AFTER SCHOOL HOURS NEXT DOOR AT
SOLUTIONS BOYS AND GIRLS CLUB WITH RANDY AND FRIDAY MASS WITH
PEERS I WITNESSED THE ENERGY AND CURIOSITY OF THE STUDENTS
FIRSTHAND LAST WEEK WHEN I JOINED THE FOURTH, FIFTH
AND SIXTH GRADE STUDENTS TO READ IN RECOGNITION OF READ
ACROSS AMERICA DAY. AFTER WE READ I ASKED THE
STUDENTS FOR IDEAS ON HOW THE CITY COULD BE IMPROVED AND WHAT
LAWS WE SHOULD CONSIDER. AND I WAS BLOWN AWAY WITH THEIR
IDEAS AND HOW IN-TUNE THEY WERE WITH THE CITY.
THEY SHARED IDEAS ABOUT MUNI BUS STOPS, TRAFFIC TRASH CANS
AND THEY EVEN KNEW ABOUT THE FIRE SPRINKLER MANDATE.
I WAS VERY IMPRESSED. AND COLLEAGUES I WAS LAST
TUESDAY AND I MIGHT HAVE JOKED WITH THEM THAT THEY SHOULD COME
WITH ME AND BE MY NEW COLLEAGUES ON THE BOARD.
NO OFFENSE BUT THEY ARE READY AND THEY'RE COMING FOR OUR JOBS
VERY, VERY SOON. SO 100 YEARS IS AN INCREDIBLE
FEAT. WE'RE REALLY GLAD THAT YOU WERE
ABLE TO COME IN TO HELP CELEBRATE THIS.
AND WITH THAT, DR. HARRIS. PRINCIPAL HARRIS, I'LL ASK IF
YOU MIGHT SHARE A FEW WORDS PLEASE.
>> FIRST OF ALL, I WOULD LIKE TO THANK YOU SUPERVISOR SAUTER
AND ALL OF OUR LOCAL LEADERS AND I DID HEAR YOU BE CALLED
HEROES. WE THANK YOU FOR ALL THE WORK
AND SERVICE THAT YOU OFFER OUR BEAUTIFUL SAN FRANCISCO AND WE
ARE SO DELIGHTED TO BE CELEBRATING 100 YEARS OF
SERVICE TO YOUTH IN SAN FRANCISCO.
AND DANNY, I'M SO PROUD OF ALL THAT YOU KNOW ABOUT THE
SOLUTION WORLD. >> YOU TOOK AWAY A LOT OF MY
SPEECH. SO I THINK WHAT YOU REALLY NEED
TO KNOW AS THESE YOUNG PEOPLE ARE EIGHTH GRADERS AND THEY ARE
ABOUT TO HEAD OFF TO HIGH SCHOOL AND THAT'S WHERE THEY'RE
GOING TO REALLY START THINKING ABOUT WHAT THE FUTURE HOLDS FOR
THEM. AND I KNOW THAT AS EDUCATORS WE
HAVE ONE OF THE MOST PRIVILEGED JOBS BECAUSE EVERY DAY WE TOUCH
A PIECE OF THE FUTURE. >> AND SO AS WE'RE EXPERIENCING
THIS BEAUTIFUL LIFE LIFETIME LESSON I WANT THE CHILDREN TO
REALLY THINK HARD ABOUT WHAT IT MEANS TO CHOOSE A JOB THAT
REALLY HELPS THE WORLD BECAUSE ONE OF OUR SAYINGS THAT I WAS
REALLY THANKFUL THAT YOU MISSED WAS THAT WE HOPE ALL OF OUR
GRADUATES WILL BECOME GOOD CITIZENS OF THE EARTH.
AND SO THAT IS OUR PRIMARY PHILOSOPHY AT SAINT PETER
AND PAUL SCHOOL. WE THANK YOU FOR YOUR GRACIOUS
WELCOME HERE TO OUR BEAUTIFUL CITY HALL.
AND WE WANT YOU TO KNOW THAT WE SUPPORT YOUR EFFORTS AS WE MOVE
SAN FRANCISCO INTO THE NEXT 100 YEARS.
>> THANK YOU
. YEAH.
OKAY. I'M GOING TO CUT IN FRONT OF
YOU. THAT'S A GOOD THING ABOUT BEING
SURE
. YOU JUST DISPLACED.
YEAH. YEAH.
>> ALL RIGHT. DISTRICT FOUR SUPERVISOR WONG
KAY MAY HAVE MARIA LUIZ TORREY COME UP WITH THE ENTIRE GANG
OVER HERE. GOT TO BE.
>> THANK YOU. PRESENT, GENTLEMEN.
COLLEAGUES. I THINK WE'RE ALL FAMILIAR WITH
MARIA LUIZ TORREY AS SHE'S BEEN TO MANY, MANY PART A
SUPERVISORS MEETINGS AND IN SACRAMENTO TOO IF ANYBODY HERE
ENDS UP GOING TO SACRAMENTO, SHE'LL BE SHOWN UP TO VISIT
YOUR OFFICES. IT IS MY HONOR TO PRESENT THIS
COMMENDATION CELEBRATING MARIA LUIZ TORREY ON THE MOMENTOUS
OCCASION OF HER 30TH WORK ANNIVERSARY WITH PARENT VOICES
CAL FORNIA. FOR THREE DECADES MARIA HAS
BEEN A SOURCE OF WISDOM, LEADERSHIP AND UNSHAKABLE
COMMITMENT TO THE CHILD CARE JUSTICE MOVEMENT.
MARIA IS NOT ONLY A DEVOTED MOTHER OF TWO BUT ALSO A
COURAGEOUS IMMIGRANT WHO CAME TO THE UNITED STATES FROM THE
PHILIPPINES AS A LAWYER AND ENVIRONMENTAL ADVOCATE
SEEKING POLITICAL ASYLUM IN 1992.
HER OWN STRUGGLES TO SECURE CHILD CARE FUELED A PASSIONATE
ADVOCACY THAT HAS UPLIFTED CHILDREN, FAMILIES
AND ESPECIALLY WOMAN LED HOUSEHOLDS.
FOR SAN FRANCISCO AND ACROSS CALIFORNIA, SHE'S REGARDED AS A
RESPECTED PRINCIPLED LEADER WHOSE LIVED EXPERIENCES
CONTINUES TO SHAPE MEANINGFUL CHANGE.
>> AS A LONGTIME ORGANIZER OF PARENT VOICES SAN FRANCISCO,
MARIA PLAYED A VITAL ROLE IN ADVANCING POLICIES THAT
SUPPORT WORKING FAMILIES. HER LEADERSHIP WAS INSTRUMENTAL
IN THE PASSAGE OF SAN FRANCISCO'S BABY PROP C A
GROUNDBREAKING COMMERCIAL RENT TAX DEDICATED TO EXPANDING
CHILDCARE AND EARLY EDUCATION. >> MARIA LIKES TO SAY SINCE I
GOT PUT ON THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS THAT SHE I BECAME
SUPERVISOR BUT SHE LOST HER SUPERVISOR BEFORE STEPPING UP
TO THIS ROLE. >> ACTIONS COUNCIL OF SAN
FRANCISCO. I WAS A SHE WAS PART OF MY TEAM
THE ADVOCACY TEAM AT ACTION'S COUNCIL AND IS SO SO HONORED TO
HAVE HAD HER BE A PART OF THAT EXPERIENCE THAT I HAD THERE
WHERE WHEN I JOINED THE ORGANIZATION SHE REALLY TAUGHT
ME, GAVE ME HER WISDOM, TOOK ME ON LOBBY TRIPS TO CITY HALL
AND TO THE STATE CAPITOL MANY, MANY OF THEM TO ADVOCATE FOR
CHILDCARE AND WORKING FAMILIES .
>> HER IMPACT, HOWEVER, EXTENDS FAR BEYOND CHILDCARE.
UNDER HER LEADERSHIP, PARENT VOICES SAN FRANCISCO RECEIVED A
RECOGNITION FROM THE UNITED STATES ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION
AGENCY FOR ITS ASTHMA RELIEF FOR KIDS INITIATIVE WHICH
ENSURED THAT ALL SCHOOL BUSSES MEET CLEAN AIR STANDARDS.
MARIA ALSO SERVED MULTIPLE TERMS ON THE BOARD OF COLEMAN
ADVOCATES FOR CHILDREN AND YOUTH AND HAS BEEN A VALUED
ADVISORY COMMITTEE MEMBER OF THE SAN FRANCISCO HEALTH PLAN
FOR MANY YEARS. HER LEGACY IS VISIBLE LITERALLY
AND SYMBOLICALLY THROUGH HER INCLUSION AND I'M PROBABLY SPOT
SET FRANCINE STRONG. K HI YEAH YEAH.
>> KAY HAGAN A PERMANENT STAINED GLASS INSTALLATION AT
THE CHILDREN'S CREATIVITY MUSEUM THAT HONORS
FILIPINO-AMERICAN COMMUNITY LEADERS THE WORD MEANING
VISIBILITY OR BRINGING TRUTH TO LIGHT PERFECTLY CAPTURES HER
LIFELONG MISSION TO MAKE THE EXPERIENCES, STRENGTHS
AND VOICES OF CHILDREN FAMILIES AND CAREGIVERS IMPOSSIBLE TO
IGNORE IN PUBLIC POLICY AND COMMUNITY SPACES.
DEFINITELY IMPOSSIBLE TO IGNORE.
SHE'S PROBABLY GOING TO SIGN SOME SORT OF COMMITMENT CARD
SOMEWHERE TODAY DURING WOMEN'S HISTORY MONTH WE PROUDLY HONOR
AND CELEBRATE MARIA LU'S STORY FOR HER EXTRAORDINARY SERVICE,
TRANSFORMATIONAL LEADERSHIP AND IMMEASURABLE IMPACT.
WE EXTEND OUR HEARTFELT APPRECIATION FOR HER CONTINUED
COMMITMENT TO THE CHILDCARE JUSTICE MOVEMENT AND TO
COMMUNITIES SHE HAS TIRELESSLY SERVED AS PARENT VOICE AS
CALIFORNIA ALSO MARKS ITS OWN 30 YEARS OF POWERFUL PARENT
ORGANIZING, I LIKE TO INVITE MARY IGNATIUS ALSO UP HERE
EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR APPARENT VOICES CALIFORNIA TO SAY A FEW
WORDS. >> THANK YOU SUPERVISOR WANG
MARIA LUCE HAS ALWAYS PRACTICE AND UPLIFTED COLLECTIVE
LEADERSHIP. IN FACT, AS AN ORGANIZER SHE'S
TRAINED TO BE IN THE BACKGROUND AND LET THE PARENTS LEAD.
SO ALL OF THIS ATTENTION MAKES HER VERY UNCOMFORTABLE.
THIS IS A COMPLETE SURPRISE TO HER.
SHE DIDN'T KNOW THIS WAS HAPPENING BUT IT'S EXACTLY WHY
WE WANTED TO DO THIS BECAUSE THE CITY AND COUNTY SHOULD KNOW
MARIA'S NAME AND THANK YOU AND AND AT THE CELEBRATION THAT
WE JUST HAD PRIOR TO THIS, THE PARENTS SAID THAT ALL SHE NEEDS
TO DO IS PICK UP A PHONE OR SEND A TEXT AND THEY RESPOND
BECAUSE THEY WILL FOLLOW HER WHEREVER SHE GOES.
AND THAT IS A TESTAMENT TO THE TRUST THAT SHE HAS BUILT WITH
THEM AND THAT ONLY HAPPENS THROUGH DEEP RELATIONAL PARENT
ORGANIZING THAT MARIA HAS HARNESSED FOR 30 YEARS.
AND AS WE AT PARENT VOICES CALIFORNIA CELEBRATE OUR 30
YEARS, WE WANT TO EXPRESS OUR DEEPEST GRATITUDE FOR MARIA
LUCE'S RELENTLESS ADVOCACY, MORAL COURAGE AND DECADES LONG
DEDICATION TO LOVE POWER, DIGNITY AND JUSTICE.
AND AS IT IS WOMEN'S HISTORY MONTH WE ARE PROUD THAT PARENT
VOICES STANDS ON THE SHOULDERS OF TWO GIANTS PATTI SIEGEL REST
IN POWER AND MARIA TAKING US INTO OUR NEXT CHAPTER AS WE WIN
UNIVERSAL CHILD CARE HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO ACROSS THE
STATE AND ACROSS THE COUNTRY. >> SO IT IS MY HONOR TO
INTRODUCE MARIA LOU'S STORY. >> BUT FIRST I KNOW WE HAVE
PEOPLE UP HERE WHO WANT TO SAY MORE NICE THINGS ABOUT YOU
SUPERVISOR MELGAR. >> THANK YOU, MARIA LUCE.
HAPPY WOMEN'S HISTORY MONTH. SO YOU ARE ONE OF THE FIERCEST
PINAY WARRIOR WOMEN I KNOW. I AM SO GLAD WE'RE DOING THIS.
THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR WANG YOU ARE AN
AMAZING, RELENTLESS, COURAGEOUS ORGANIZER STRATEGIST JUST LIKE
I HAVE WATCHED YOU FOR DECADES DOING YOUR THING AND MAKING
PROGRESS EVERY STEP OF THE WAY TO GET US WHERE WE ARE TODAY
WHICH IS FARTHER THAN WE HAVE EVER BEEN IN THIS MOVEMENT.
SO I AM GRATEFUL FOR YOU AND GRATEFUL FOR NOT JUST FOR
YOUR HEART AND THE WAY THAT YOU MOBILIZE PEOPLE BUT YOUR BRAINS
LIKE YOU ARE AN AMAZING STRATEGY JUST AND YOU HAVE
GOTTEN US SO FAR WITH THE WORK. SO I THANK YOU.
I'M GRATEFUL FOR YOU. I'M ALSO GRATEFUL THAT WE CAN
DO THIS TO HONOR YOU. AND MAKE NO MISTAKE EVERYBODY
HERE KNOWS SOMEBODY WHO STARTED CITY HALL KNOWS OUR NAME
AND WE'RE HOPING THAT EVERYONE IS THAT YOUR MENTOR KNOWS YOUR
NAME TOO AND THAT WE DO GET TO THAT PROMISE OF UNIVERSAL
CHILDCARE IN OUR STATE IN OUR COUNTRY BECAUSE THAT IS THE
TRUE SOCIAL JUSTICE THAT WE'RE ALL FIGHTING FOR.
SO THANK YOU MARIA LUIZ FOR EVERYTHING YOU'VE DONE.
I'M SO GLAD THAT WE'RE RECOGNIZING YOU AND YOU GO GIRL
YEAH. SUPERVISOR CHEN THANK YOU FOR
PRESIDENT MY RIGHT MARIA OVER HERE.
THANK YOU. I JUST WANT TO THANK YOU FOR
REALLY DEMONSTRATING AS AN IMMIGRANT, AS A MOM AND THE
MONTH OF WHERE WE CELEBRATE WOMEN'S HISTORY MONTH YOU ARE
DEMONSTRATING WHAT IT'S IMPOSSIBLE TO BECOME POSSIBLE.
SO THANK YOU. THANK YOU FOR YOUR WORK OF
FIGHTING FOR OUR CHILDREN. FIGHTING FOR OUR YOUTH
AND FIGHTING FOR OUR ENVIRONMENT.
THANK YOU FOR ALWAYS SHARING YOUR LOVE, YOUR LEADERSHIP
AND YOUR TRUST AND YOUR DEDICATION WITH US AND VERY
GRATEFUL AND VERY PROUD TO BE HERE CELEBRATING WITH YOU FOR
YOUR 30 YEARS OF 30 YEARS OF SERVICE IN OUR COMMUNITY.
>> THANK YOU. I'M SO PROUD OF YOU.
THANK YOU. THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR WALTON. >> THANK YOU, PRESIDENT MADAM
AND MARIA LUIZ, I JUST WANT YOU TO KNOW THAT I AM SO GLAD THAT
THIS IS HAPPENING. YOUR COMMITMENT, YOUR ADVOCACY,
THE WAY YOU FIGHT FOR OUR YOUNGEST AND MOST VULNERABLE
AND THE CHILDREN WHO NEED YOU THE MOST.
I WANT YOU TO KNOW WE SEE YOU. WE APPRECIATE YOU.
>> AND I JUST WANT EVERYBODY TO KNOW THAT IF THERE WAS EVER A
PERSON WHO WAS MORE FIERCE FIGHTING FOR A CAUSE, THIS IS
IT. THIS IS DEFINITELY IT.
AND I WANT YOU TO KNOW THAT I APPRECIATE WATCHING YOU
ORGANIZE BRING PEOPLE TOGETHER AND JUST EXCITED THAT THIS IS
HAPPENING HERE IN THIS CHAMBER TODAY.
>> SO CONGRATULATIONS. WELL DESERVED.
AND NOW MARIA LUCE, THE FLOOR IS YOURS.
>> THANK YOU FOR SOME ADVISORS AND HAPPY INTERNATIONAL WOMEN'S
HISTORY MONTH SO EVERYONE TO ALL THE WOMEN SUPERVISORS THIS
IS ALSO A GREAT EVENT TO COMMEMORATE OUR VOICES 30TH
ANNIVERSARY YEAR. THAT GOES WITHOUT SAYING I AM A
FOUNDING ORGANIZER. >> I'M GLAD I'M WITNESSING THIS
WHILE I'M STILL ALIVE BECAUSE THE LAST TIME I WAS HERE WAS
RECOMMENDATIONS WERE ABOUT SULLIVAN AND I HONOR ALL THE
WOMEN CHILDCARE WORKERS WHO I STAND ON THEIR SHOULDERS ROSIE
KENNEDY, PAT SULLIVAN, CAROLE STEVENSON, PADDY SEGAL, THE
FOUNDER OF CHILDREN'S COUNCIL AND PARENT VOICES AND SOMEONE
WHO IS STILL VERY MUCH ALIVE WHO WAS ALSO MY MENTOR ASPIRANT
VOICES ADVOCATE FOR YOUTH MARGARET BRODKIN AND ALL THE
PARENT VOICE LEADERS WHO ARE HERE BEHIND ME TODAY.
>> THANK YOU FOR THIS VERY THOUGHTFUL AND INSPIRING
COMMENDATION. >> THANK YOU.
YEAH, FOR YOU I GUESS MARY OVER HERE, BABY.
YOU CAN DO THIS. I CAN'T MISS MY WAY HERE.
YEAH, YOU'RE RIGHT. OKAY.
OKAY. OH YEAH.
AND THEN WE GO. WE YOU TELL THEM WHAT TO.
>> DISTRICT FIVE SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD CALL UP MIKE LONG TO
THE FRONT. COLLEAGUES, TODAY I HAVE THE
HONOR OF RECOGNIZING MICHAEL VONN, THE CLUBHOUSE DIRECTOR OF
THE TENDERLOIN CLUBHOUSE FOR HIS DEEP COMMITMENT TO THE
YOUNG PEOPLE OF SAN FRANCISCO AND FOR NEARLY TWO DECADES OF
SERVICE ADVANCING THE MISSION OF THE BOYS AND GIRLS CLUB OF
SAN FRANCISCO. TODAY'S RECOGNITION IS
ESPECIALLY MEANINGFUL BECAUSE MIKE IS CONCLUDING HIS TIME
WITH THE BOYS AND GIRLS CLUB MOVEMENT AS HE CLOSES THIS
CHAPTER OF SERVICE. WE WANT TO TAKE A MOMENT AS A
BOARD TO ACKNOWLEDGE THE IMPACT HE HAS MADE ON COUNTLESS YOUNG
PEOPLE AND FAMILIES ACROSS OUR CITY.
>> THOSE WHO KNOW MIKE KNOW HE LIKE ME IS OBSESSED WITH BATMAN
AND NOT JUST BECAUSE OF HIS BATMAN TATTOOS BUT BECAUSE OF
HIS FOCUS AND DEDICATION TO STAND BESIDE THE COMMUNITY
AND PROTECT THE PEOPLE WHO NEED IT MOST.
>> SO I APOLOGIZE MIKE I'M GOING TO MAKE SOME COMIC BOOK
REFERENCES THROUGHOUT THIS STATEMENT.
>> MIKE'S JOURNEY WITH THE CLUB BEGAN ALMOST 20 YEARS AGO NOT
AS A STAFF MEMBER BUT AS A YOUNG PERSON WALKING THROUGH
ITS OWN DOORS AT JUST 12 YEARS OLD.
HE JOINED THE COLUMBIA PARK CLUBHOUSE.
FROM THERE HE BECAME A FOUNDING MEMBER OF THE EXCELSIOR
CLUBHOUSE AND LATER A FOUNDING MEMBER OF THE NEWLY RENOVATED
COLUMBIA PARK CLUBHOUSE. EVEN AT A YOUNG AGE, MICHAEL
STOOD AS A LEADER THROUGH PROGRAMS LIKE KEYSTONE CLUB.
>> HE BUILT THE SKILLS AND CONFIDENCE THAT WOULD SHAPE
HIS PATH FORWARD. >> HIS DEDICATION EARNED HIM
THE HONOR OF BEING NAMED YOUTH OF THE YEAR.
A RECOGNITION RESERVED FOR YOUNG PEOPLE WHO DEMONSTRATE
EXCEPTIONAL LEADERSHIP AND SERVICE.
>> THAT SAME SPIRIT CARRIED FORWARD INTO HIS PROFESSIONAL
LIFE OVER THE COURSE OF NEARLY TWO DECADES.
MIKE SERVED IN MULTIPLE ROLES ACROSS SEVERAL CLUBHOUSE SITES
WITHIN THE BOYS AND GIRLS CLUB OF SAN FRANCISCO.
>> IN EACH POSITION HE BECAME KNOWN AS A MENTOR
AND COLLABORATOR SOMEONE WHO HELPED COLLEAGUES STRENGTHEN
THEIR PROGRAMS AND BUILD ENVIRONMENTS WHERE YOUNG PEOPLE
FELT TRULY SUPPORTED. >> LOOK BACK TO WHAT BATMAN
SAID IN THE DARK KNIGHT RISES THAT A HERO CAN BE ANYONE EVEN
A MAN DOING SOMETHING AS SIMPLE AND REASSURING AS PUTTING A
COAT AROUND A YOUNG BOY SHOULDERS TO LET THEM KNOW THE
WORLD HASN'T ENDED. AND FOR THE CHILDREN OF THE
TENDERLOIN THAT IS THE REASSURANCE THAT MIKE HAS GIVEN
TO THE KIDS THAT LIVE THERE AS WELL.
>> AS CLUBHOUSE DIRECTOR OF THE TENDERLOIN CLUBHOUSE MIKE HAS
LED WITH PURPOSE AND COMPASSION.
HE HAS GUIDED POLICY DEVELOPMENT PROGRAM SCHEDULING
AND THE LONG TERM VISION FOR THE CLUBHOUSE WHILE ENSURING IT
REMAINS A SAFE AND WELCOMING SPACE FOR YOUTH AND A
NEIGHBORHOOD THAT FACES REAL CHALLENGES.
>> MIKE HAS HELPED CREATE STABILITY AND OPPORTUNITY FOR
THE YOUNG PEOPLE WHO WALK THROUGH THOSE DOORS EVERY DAY.
>> HIS LEADERSHIP THOUGH, EXTENDS FAR BEYOND THE
CLUBHOUSE WALLS. >> MIKE HAS SERVED THE
COMMUNITY AS A BOARD MEMBER OF THE TENDERLOIN NEIGHBORHOOD
DEVELOPMENT CORPORATION AS AN ADVISORY BOARD MEMBER FOR THE
HEALING WELL AND AS A SENIOR STRATEGIC ADVISOR TO THE CEO OF
THE TENDERLOIN COMMUNITY BENEFIT DISTRICT WHERE HE ALSO
SERVED PREVIOUSLY AS ITS BOARD CHAIR AND WHERE HE HAS
CONTRIBUTED TO INITIATIVES AS THE TENDERLOIN YOUTH VIOLENCE
PREVENTION PROGRAM. >> ACROSS ALL OF THIS WORK.
MIKE HAS HELD A SIMPLE BUT POWERFUL BELIEF WHEN WE BUILD
STRONG FUNDAMENTALS AND STRONG COMMUNITY CONNECTIONS, YOUNG
PEOPLE ARE ABLE TO ACHIEVE INCREDIBLE THINGS.
>> MIKE IS ALSO A POWERFUL TESTAMENT OF WHAT HAPPENS WHEN
WE INVEST IN YOUNG PEOPLE. >> THE OC IS MIKE AS A KID ONCE
WALKED INTO A CLUBHOUSE SEEKING OPPORTUNITY GREW INTO A LEADER
WHO HELPED CREATE OPPORTUNITY FOR THOUSANDS OF OTHERS.
THAT FULL CIRCLE JOURNEY REPRESENTS THE VERY BEST OF
WHAT YOUTH DEVELOPMENT ORGANIZATIONS STRIVE TO
ACHIEVE. >> MIKE AS YOU CONCLUDE YOUR
TIME WITH THE BOYS AND GIRLS CLUB OF SAN FRANCISCO, WE WANT
YOU TO KNOW THAT YOUR LEADERSHIP AND COMPASSION HAVE
LEFT A LASTING MARK ON OUR CITY.
JUST TODAY YOU ACTUALLY REMINDED ONE OF MY TEAM MEMBERS
OF A LINE FROM AVENGERS ENDGAME WHERE TONY STARK SAYS PART OF
THE JOURNEY IS THE END. >> IT FEELS ESPECIALLY FITTING
TODAY BECAUSE WHILE THIS CHAPTER OF YOUR WORK WITH THE
BOYS AND GIRLS CLUB IS COMING TO A CLOSE, THE JOURNEY YOU
HELPED SHAPED AND BUILD FOR SO MANY YOUNG PEOPLE IN THIS CITY
IS JUST BEGINNING AND WILL CONTINUE FOR YEARS TO COME.
>> SO THANK YOU MIKE FOR YOUR DEDICATION TO THE YOUTH
AND FAMILIES OF SAN FRANCISCO. OUR CITY IS STRONGER AND MORE
CONNECTED BECAUSE OF YOUR SERVICE.
>> WE ARE GRATEFUL FOR EVERYTHING YOU HAVE DONE
AND EXCITED TO SEE THE IMPACT YOU WILL CONTINUE TO MAKE
IN THE YEARS AHEAD. >> AND TO CLOSE OUT I WILL
QUOTE LEGO BATMAN WHICH SAYS LIFE DOESN'T GIVE YOU SEATBELTS
. >> SO LET'S GO.
>> RAMADAN MUBARAK. HAPPY WOMEN'S HISTORY MONTH.
I ALSO WANT TO ACKNOWLEDGE THAT WE ARE ON THE UNCEDED ANCESTRAL
HOMELAND OF THE RAMA TO SALONI WHO ARE AN ORIGINAL INHABITANTS
OF THE SAN FRANCISCO PENINSULA .
>> THANK YOU SUPERVISOR MAHMUD AND THE DISTRICT FIVE OFFICE
FOR THE ACCOMMODATION. I HAVE SPENT OVER 20 YEARS OF
MY LIFE SERVING THE YOUTH AND FAMILIES OF SAN FRANCISCO
THROUGH BOYS AND GIRLS CLUB OF SAN FRANCISCO.
I SPENT OVER A DECADE OF MY LIFE IN A MISSION DISTRICT AT
OUR COLUMBIA PARK IN MISSION CLUBHOUSES.
IN THE PAST TEN YEARS IN THE TENDERLOIN NOT ONLY WORKING FOR
BOYS AND GIRLS CLUBS BUT BEING ON THE BOARD OF THE TENDERLOIN
COMMUNITY BENEFIT DISTRICT TENDERLOIN NEIGHBORHOOD
DEVELOPMENT CORPORATION AND THE ADVISORY BOARD OF THE HEALING
WELL. I AM A PRODUCT OF THE BOYS
AND GIRLS CLUBS AND UNDERSTAND FIRSTHAND WHAT IS POSSIBLE WHEN
YOU COMBINE CARING ADULTS RESOURCES AND OPPORTUNITIES.
>> I AM A PRODUCT OF THE COMMUNITY COMING TOGETHER TO
MAKE SURE FIRST CLASS SERVICES ARE PROVIDED AS AN ADULT.
I WAS ABLE TO STAND ON THE SHOULDERS OF AMAZING PEOPLE WHO
HAVE DONE THIS TYPE OF WORK FAR BEFORE I ENTERED THE PICTURE.
MOST RECENTLY HERE IN THE TENDERLOIN I WAS GIVEN AN
OPPORTUNITY AND A TRUST TO HELP BUILD COALITIONS HELPING TO
FORM AND STEWARD THAT OUR CHILDREN'S YOUTH AND FAMILIES
COALITION AND ITS EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR WORKING GROUP HAVE
BEEN PROUD MOMENTS. OPENING THE RENOVATED BORREGO
PARK A TOP TEN PARK IN THE CITY HAS BEEN A PROUD MOMENT AND TO
BE A PART OF THE GROWTH OF INITIATIVES LIKE THE TENDERLOIN
INVESTMENT BLUEPRINT, THE ICONIC GREENWAY AND OTHER
PROJECTS WILL ALWAYS HOLD A SPECIAL PLACE IN MY HEART.
>> AND I LOVE BEING A LEADER AT THE TENDERLOIN CLUBHOUSE.
WORKING WITH GUIDING AND SUPPORTING ADULT ALLIES WHO
ARE HERE FOR THE RIGHT REASONS I TRY TO REMEMBER THAT I NEED
TO TAKE CARE OF THE ADULTS WHO TAKE CARE OF THOSE KIDS.
I TAKE ALL OF THAT PERSONALLY AND I TAKE THE TRUST PEOPLE
GIVE ME PERSONALLY. >> IT WAS ALWAYS A VERY
DIFFICULT DECISION TO GET TO. >> I STILL LOVE THIS
ORGANIZATION OUR MISSION AND THE TYPE OF IMPACT WE GET
TO MAKE EVERY DAY. >> BUT I ALSO FEEL LIKE THIS IS
THE BEST TIME FOR ME TO SEE WHAT ELSE IS OUT THERE FOR ME.
>> SO MUCH OF WHAT I DO IS PUSH KIDS TO DO THEIR BEST TO GROW
AND LEARN EVERY DAY. MY RESIGNATION IS MY WAY OF
BEING THE ULTIMATE ROLE MODEL PUSHING MYSELF TO FIND WHAT'S
NEXT EVEN WHEN IT'S SCARY. >> IT HAS BEEN AN HONOR TO WORK
IN THIS ORGANIZATION AND IN THE TENDERLOIN THE PAST TEN YEARS
AND IN THE 14 YEARS IN A MISSION BEFORE THAT.
>> THANK YOU FOR ALL THE OPPORTUNITIES, THE TRUST
AND THE MEMORIES. THANK YOU TO ALL MY MENTORS
AND THOUGHT PARTNERS. >> SOME OF THOSE PEOPLE IN THIS
ROOM TODAY. >> THANK YOU TO EVERY PERSON
IN EVERY ORGANIZATION THAT PAVED THE WAY FOR ME TO BE
HERE. THANK YOU TO THE CITY
DEPARTMENT. I GOT TO PARTNER WITH THE
RESIDENTS WHO GUIDED INFORMED ME AND THE MANY ORGANIZATIONS I
GOT TO BUILD WITH FOR SO LONG. AND THANK YOU TO THE BOYS
AND GIRLS CLUB OF SAN FRANCISCO FOR LETTING A 40 YEAR OLD
LIBERTIES DREAM TO BE A CLUBHOUSE DIRECTOR.
>> IF I HAD A CHANCE IF I HAD A CHANCE TO DO IT ALL OVER AGAIN,
I WOULDN'T CHANGE A THING. >> THANK YOU SO MUCH.
COME ON AND WE'LL DO IT ALL FOR YOU.
ALL RIGHT. READY
? AND NOW BACK TO DISTRICT 11
SUPERVISOR CHEN. >> THANK YOU, PROFESSOR AMANDO.
MAN WHAT A BEAUTIFUL DAY TODAY. I AM ALSO HONORING SOMEONE.
>> IT'S VERY, VERY BEAUTIFUL, JERRY.
MAY I HAVE YOU COME OUT TO THE PODIUM TO IT?
IT'S MY ABSOLUTE PLEASURE TO HONOR A WOMAN WHO IS A FIERCE
ADVOCATE, A BEAUTIFUL SOUL, AN AMAZING WARRIOR AND MY OWN
DISTRICT 11 NEIGHBOR. >> SHE IS A WOMAN WHO HAS
QUIETLY YET POWERFULLY LEFT HER MARK ON OUR CITY'S
ENVIRONMENTAL JUSTICE JUSTICE MOVEMENT AND PUBLIC EDUCATION
SYSTEM. AS A YOUNG SAN FRANCISCO AS A
SCHOOL UNIFIED STUDENT, JERRY ALMANZA WAS ALREADY BUILT FOR
GREATNESS. >> SHE HAD GREAT STREET SMARTS,
COMPASSION, VISION AND A DESIRE TO DO RIGHT BY HER COMMUNITY.
AS ONE OF THE EARLIEST STAFF MEMBERS OF PODER PEOPLE
ORGANIZING TO DEMAND ENVIRONMENTAL AND ECONOMIC
RIGHTS RUFO JERRY WORK HAND IN HAND WITH YOUNG LEADERS TO
FIGHT ENVIRONMENTAL RACISM. >> SHE HELPED TO LEAD A
SIGNATURE CAMPAIGN TO RECLAIM A TOXIC BROWNFIELD ON FOLSOM
AND 23RD STREETS AND TRANSFORM IT INTO A BEAUTIFUL
MULTIGENERATIONAL PART AND GATHERINGS SPACE TO SERVE
THE NEIGHBORHOOD'S DIVERSE WORKING CLASS RESIDENTS TODAY.
>> PARK USERS MAY NOT KNOW ABOUT ALL THE PEOPLE WHO HAVE
FOUGHT FOR OVER A YEAR TO TURN THE EMPTY LOT INTO OUR PART
THEY MAY NOT KNOW ABOUT THE CITY'S NEGOTIATE SHIFTS WITH
PROPERTY OWNER OR THE SOIL TESTS OR MANY MANY COMMUNITY
MEETING WHERE YOUTH IMMIGRANT FAMILIES AND NEIGHBORS HELPED
DESIGN THE PARTY. >> THEY ARE GRATEFUL FOR THE
OPPORTUNITY TO PLAY IN A SAFE SPACE IN THEIR OWN NEIGHBORHOOD
. >> THE SCHOOLCHILDREN AT CESAR
CHAVEZ ELEMENTARY SCHOOL LEFT THEIR MARK BY NAMING THIS NEW
PART PARK PACKING IN NO NEEDLES.
OUR CHILDREN UNITING PARTY THROUGH IT ALL.
>> JERRY ALMANZA WAS THERE MAKING IT ALL HAPPEN.
>> JERRY ALSO PART HER HOT INTO THE SOUTHWEST NETWORK FOR
ENVIRONMENTAL AND ECONOMIC JUSTICE.
AUSTIN EACH SERVING AS THE DELEGATE AND JOINING FORCE.
WHAT OVER WITH OTHER ENVIRONMENTAL JUSTICE
COMMUNITIES FROM CALIFORNIA TO NORTHERN MEXICO TO LIVE FOR
COMMUNITY SOLUTIONS TO COME BACK CORPORATE AND STATE
SPONSOR AND STATE SPONSORED ENVIRONMENTAL RACISM.
JERRY WENT ON TO GET HER TEACHING CREDENTIAL
IN BILINGUAL EDUCATION AND SPENT THE NEXT SIX YEARS AS
AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL TEACHER AT CESAR CHAVEZ ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
IN THE MISSION DISTRICT. >> DURING THAT DURING THAT TIME
SHE TAUGHT BILINGUAL EDUCATION AND EVERYTHING FROM MATH TO
GEOGRAPHY TO SCIENCE. >> USING HANDS ON TECHNIQUES TO
ENGAGE STUDENTS TO SHOP IN CRYING MINDSET WE CAREFULLY
BASED WE CULTURALLY BASED PRACTICES AND A LOT OF LOVE
IN 2021. >> JERRY WAS ELECTED BY HER
PEERS TO SERVE AS THE TREASURER OF THE GOVERNING BOARD OF THE
UNITED EDUCATORS OF SAN FRANCISCO TOGETHER WITH OTHER
ELECTED OFFICERS JERRY HAS WORKED HARD TO BUILD AN
ORGANIZATION WHOSE HIGHLIGHTS WITH BUILDING STRONG SCHOOLS
FOR STUDENTS WITH ALL THE NECESSARY RESOURCES
AND SUPPORTING KIDS AND THEIR FAMILY IN THE WAYS THAT ARE THE
MOST NEEDED. IN HER ROLE AS A UNICEF
TREASURE, SHE HAS SUPPORTED AND HOUSED IN S.F. USD FAMILIES
WHO ORGANIZED IN THE FAITH IN ACTION BAY AREA TO GAIN
RESOURCES FOR FAMILIES SO THAT NO CHILD SLEEPS ON THE STREET
AND HELP START A LEGAL DEFENSE FUND FOR S.F. USD STUDENTS
AND FAMILY WHO ARE SEEKING OPPORTUNITIES FOR A BETTER LIFE
FOR THEIR CHILDREN. >> IT IS MY GREATEST PLEASURE
AND MY HONOR TO HONOR JERRY TODAY.
THANK YOU FOR ALL THAT YOU DO TO HELP CREATE SAN FRANCISCO
SAN FRANCISCO WHERE THE LIGHTS OF OUR YOUTH AND OUR DIVERSE
WORKING CLASS FAMILY SHINE BRIGHT.
>> THANK YOU, JERRY AND JERRY. >> NOT ONLY DO YOU HAVE BEFORE
YOU FAN CLUB IN THE AUDIENCE YOU ALSO HAVE ONE OVER HERE
SUPERVISOR MELGAR AND CONFESS IT UP JERRY.
>> I HAVE HAD THE PLEASURE OF WORKING WITH JERRY AND ALSO
WATCHING HER NOT QUIET, FIERCE PASSIONATE ORGANIZING SKILLS
IN ENVIRONMENTAL JUSTICE THAT BLED AS A FANTASTIC TEACHER AT
CESAR CHAVEZ. AND NOW HAVING SEEN YOU STEP UP
TO THIS LEADERSHIP ROLE AT UCSF IN ADDITION TO BEING A GREAT
TEACHER ORGANIZER UNION LEADER, YOU'RE ALSO AN AMAZING FRIEND
AND A MOTHER AND I ADMIRE YOUR PASSION BUT ALSO YOUR LOVE
AND YOUR DEEP COMMITMENT TO COMMUNITY AND ALSO YOUR FAMILY
AND THE PEOPLE AROUND YOU THAT YOU'RE RESPONSIBLE FOR AND YOU
ARE JUST BREATHTAKING IN THE WAY YOU APPROACH LIFE.
YOU'RE AN AMAZING HUMAN BEING. JERRY THIS IS WHY YOU HAVE SUCH
A BIG SUPPORT NETWORK. I WILL SAY THAT WHATEVER YOU DO
YOU DO WELL. YOU PUT YOUR HEART AND SOUL
INTO IT AND YOU YOUR AMAZING BRAIN.
AND WE ARE SO LUCKY TO HAVE HAD YOU LEAD SO MANY DIFFERENT
CAMPAIGNS INITIATIVES BECAUSE EVERYTHING YOU DO I KNOW WILL
TURN OUT BECAUSE JERRY IS IN CHARGE.
>> SO THANK YOU SUPERVISOR CHEN FOR DOING THIS FOR HONORING
THIS AMAZING WOMAN. THE FLOWERS LOOK GOOD ON YOU
AND I AM SO GLAD WE'RE DOING IT.
THANK YOU, JERRY. >> THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR WALTON. >> THANK YOU, PRESIDENT
AND JERRY, I JUST WANT TO SAY AND I KNOW THAT SUPERVISOR CHAN
AND SUPERVISOR MELGAR HAVE SAID A LOT AND ALMOST EVERYTHING BUT
I DO WANT YOU TO KNOW ONE THAT I APPRECIATE YOU AS AN EDUCATOR
AND I ALSO APPRECIATE YOU FOR ALL THE WORK YOU DID
COORDINATING AND ORGANIZING EVERYONE TO MAKE SURE THAT OUR
STUDENTS STILL HAD A PLACE TO GO DURING THE STRIKE AND THAT
THEY WOULD LOOK AFTER AND JUST BE AN AMAZING LEADER THAT YOU
ARE. AGAIN, THIS IS WELL-DESERVED
AND SO I'M HAPPY TO BE HERE TO SEE THIS HAPPEN.
>> THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR FIELDER THANK YOU
JERRY. YOU HAVE BEEN THERE FOR SOME OF
THE MOST VULNERABLE PEOPLE IN SAN FRANCISCO SPECIFICALLY
OUR IMMIGRANTS STUDENTS, THEIR FAMILIES, OUR STUDENTS WHO
DON'T HAVE HOMES TO GO INTO AT NIGHT.
THEIR FAMILIES AND I JUST REALLY AM IN AWE OF HOW MUCH
YOU STICK BY AND WORK ALONGSIDE PEOPLE WHO ARE IN IN IN IN
STRUCTURAL INJUSTICES AND YOU PUT YOUR ALL INTO IT AND YOUR
COMPASSION FOR YOUR COLLEAGUES AND YOUR MEMBERS COMES OUT VERY
CLEARLY AND I JUST WANT TO APPRECIATE YOU FOR EVERYTHING
THAT YOU'VE DONE FOR OUR STUDENTS AND THEIR FAMILIES
ESPECIALLY THOSE WHO HAVE MIGRATED HERE AND WHO ARE NOT
SURE WHERE THEY'RE SLEEPING AT NIGHT.
>> SO THANK YOU SO MUCH. THE FLOOR IS YOURS.
THANK YOU. THANK YOU.
>> SUPERVISOR CHEN FIELDER MITCHELL GARY WATSON.
CONNIE. >> I WANT TO FIRST OF ALL
APPRECIATE SUPERVISOR CHEN. SHE IS MY NEIGHBOR AND I'M
VERY, VERY PROUD THAT SHE IS GETS TO BE THE PERSON THAT
REPRESENTS OUR DISTRICT AS A WOMAN OF COLOR, AS A MOTHER.
AND SO I WANT TO APPRECIATE YOU AND THANK YOU AND OF COURSE
YOUR AMAZING AID. >> CHARLIE SCHAMUS, I KNOW HE
DOESN'T LIKE TO BE CALLED OUT BUT HE'S AWESOME TO.
>> SO I WANT TO GIVE A BIG SHOUT OUT TO EVERYBODY THAT'S
HERE TODAY YOU ALL CHEN AND ALL OF YOU TALKED ABOUT THIS,
RIGHT? MY BROTHER FAMILY IS HERE, MY
SISTER CHINESE FAMILIES HERE, MY FATHER NACHSHON FAMILY, MY
FAMILY MY DAUGHTER EATS AND MY MOTHER IN LAW AND MY PARTNER
AD-ROCK AND MY GOOD BEST FRIENDS FOR SINCE I WAS 19
YEARS OLD THAT I FIRST CAME TO SAN FRANCISCO AND GOT TO MEET
AND STILL FRIENDS WITH ALONG WITH ME AND LISA, MY MENTOR,
SOME OF MY MENTORS FROM EARLY ON FROM THERE.
AND SO I'M REALLY EXCITED TO BE HERE WITH YOU ALL TODAY AND I
WANT TO JUST SAY THAT I COULDN'T DO THIS WORK WITHOUT
ANY WITH YOUR SUPPORT. >> WITHOUT YOUR SUPPORT.
RIGHT? SO ALL OF YOU HAVE BEEN HAVE
GIVING ME STRENGTH YOU HAVE LISTENED TO MY RANTS IN MY
CRAZY IDEAS YOU PROVIDED ME WITH LOVE.
>> YOU HELPED ME RAISE MY CHILD.
YOU'VE GIVEN ME COURAGE TO FOLLOW MY HEART TO KEEP
ORGANIZING FOR A DIFFERENT WORLD THAT WE KNOW IS POSSIBLE
. >> AS OUR RECENT EDUCATORS
STRIKE SHOWED, SDF IS A UNION TOWN AND I AM SO PROUD TO STAND
BEFORE YOU AS A UNION LEADER WHO IS ACTIVELY WORKING TO MAKE
THE WORLD THE WORLD THAT WE ARE THAT WORLD THE REALITY WE'RE
WORKING CLASS FAMILIES CAN CONTINUE TO LIVE HERE BECAUSE
OF RENT CONTROL, RIGHT? LIKE TO BE HONEST THAT'S WHY
I'M STILL HERE BECAUSE I'VE BEEN LIVING IN RENT CONTROLLED
PLACES AS A TEACHER I CAN'T AFFORD ANYTHING ELSE.
>> RIGHT AS AS AS SS. I STRIVE TO WORK FOR AN S.F.
THAT WELCOMES NEWCOMERS FROM DIVERSE BACKGROUNDS BECAUSE WE
KNOW IT'S POSSIBLE WE KNOW THAT S.F. CONTINUES TO SUPPORT
INNOVATION AND CREATIVITY RIGHT ?
>> THAT'S SHOWN TO BE POSSIBLE. S.F. CAN CONTINUE TO INVEST
IN SOCIAL SERVICES FOR OUR YOUTH AND OUR FAMILIES.
>> WE KNOW THAT WE CAN MAKE THAT A POSSIBILITY SO I'M
SORRY. >> OKAY, SO S.F. IS ONE OF THE
RICHEST CITIES IN THE WORLD WHICH GIVES US A RESPONSIBILITY
TO ENSURE THAT WE ARE INVESTING IN THOSE OF US WHO ARE THE
BACKBONE OF THIS CITY AND MAKE THIS CITY CULTURALLY RICH.
WE HAVE A RESPONSIBILITY TO ENSURE THAT THOSE WHO HAVE
BENEFITED FROM THE GENEROUS TAX INCENTIVES PAY THEIR FAIR
SHARE. >> I LOOK FORWARD TO CONTINUE
TO CONTRIBUTE TO WORK TOWARDS AN S.F. THAT IS DIVERSE
AND SUPPORTIVE OF WORKING CLASS FAMILIES AND STRENGTHENING OUR
PUBLIC SCHOOLS. I URGE ALL OF YOU HERE WHO WERE
ELECTED BY YOUR PEERS TO USE YOUR PUBLIC SERVICE TO CHAMPION
A SAN FRANCISCO THAT IS DIVERSE CULTURALLY AND ECONOMICALLY.
>> SO LET'S MAKE IT HAPPEN GUYS.
LET'S KEEP DOING IT. THANK YOU.
OKAY. AND I THE THING
ALL RIGHT, MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL OUR 3 P.M. SPECIAL ORDER
ITEMS NINE THROUGH 12 TOGETHER ITEMS NINE THROUGH 12 WERE
CONTINUED OPEN FROM FEBRUARY 10TH 2026.
>> ITEM NINE IS A PUBLIC HEARING OF PERSONS INTERESTED
IN THE DE FACTO DENIAL OF A CONDITIONAL USE AUTHORIZATION
FOR A PROPOSED PROJECT AT 524 THROUGH 526 VALLEJO STREET
AND 4-4A AND TO SAN ANTONIO PLACE TO LEGALIZE THE MERGER OF
THREE DWELLING UNITS ON SECOND AND THIRD FLOORS INTO ONE
DWELLING UNIT AND TO REINSTATE ONE DWELLING UNIT ON THE GROUND
FLOOR WITHIN AN EXISTING FOUR UNIT RESIDENTIAL BUILDING
LOCATED WITHIN R-1 RESIDENTIAL AND MIXED LOW DENSITY ZONING
DISTRICT TELEGRAPH HILL NORTH BEACH RESIDENTIAL STUDY.
ITEM TEN IS THE MOTION TO APPROVE THE PLANNING
COMMISSION'S DECISION DE FACTO DENYING AND CONDITIONAL USE
AUTHORIZATION. >> ITEM 11 IS THE MOTION TO
DISAPPROVE OF THE PLANNING COMMISSION'S DECISION.
AND ITEM 12 IS THE MOTION TO DIRECT THE PREPARATION OF
FINDINGS. >> THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK.
WE CONTINUED THIS ITEM FROM FEBRUARY 10TH.
I BELIEVE WE HAVE RECEIVED ANOTHER CONTINUANCE REQUEST
FROM THE APPELLANT WHO'S ALSO THE PROJECT SPONSOR.
I SEE SUPERVISOR SAUTER IN THE QUEUE.
SUPERVISOR SAUTER THANK YOU. PRESENT GENTLEMEN.
YES PLEASE. I'D LIKE TO ASK FOR THIS ITEM
TO BE CONTINUED ONCE MORE. ALL PARTIES INCLUDING THE
APPELLANT'S DEPARTMENT BUILDING INSPECTION AND PLANNING ARE ON
BOARD WITH THIS REQUEST AND THIS ADDITIONAL TIME WILL
ALLOW FOR AN INSPECTION FROM DTI WHICH WE BELIEVE IS
IMPORTANT TO BRING MORE CLARITY TO THE SITUATION.
SO I'D LIKE TO MAKE A MOTION FOR THESE ITEMS TO BE CONTINUED
TO APRIL 7TH. >> ALL RIGHT.
AS MOTION TO CONTINUE THESE ITEMS APRIL 7TH.
>> IS THERE A SECOND SECONDED BY DORSEY?
WE WILL NEED TO TAKE PUBLIC COMMENT ON THE CONTINUE SO
BEFORE WE ACT ON THAT MOTION I ,I, I GUESS I WILL.
>> MADAM CLERK, CAN YOU PLEASE CALL FOR PUBLIC COMMENT ON THE
CONTINUANCE? RIGHT.
WELL YES, SIR. I NEED THE OVERHEAD PLEASE.
>> WE'RE SETTING THE TIMER FOR TWO MINUTES.
>> THANK YOU. MY NAME IS JERRY DE RATTLER.
I'M OPPOSED TO CONTINUING THIS MATTER IN A CHRONICLE ARTICLE
YESTERDAY THE HOMEOWNERS ACKNOWLEDGED THEY KNEW THE
HOUSE WAS ZONED A MULTI-UNIT BUILDING COULD SEE THE PROPERTY
HAD A SINGLE FLOOR FLOOR PLAN OR SINGLE FAMILY FLOOR PLAN
AND RELIED ON ASSURANCES FROM THE SELLER AND REAL ESTATE
AGENTS THAT THE DISCREPANCIES WERE NOT A BIG DEAL.
>> THE CHRONICLE ARTICLE CONTRADICTED IMPORTANT
REPRESENTATION IN THEIR 98 PAGE APPEAL.
>> THE HOMEOWNERS ARE ASKING THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS ORDERS
TO OVERRIDE THE PLANNING COMMISSION AND GRANT THEM A SEE
YOU A AND A HOUSING CRISIS. THERE IS NO SOUND RATIONALE FOR
THEIR REQUEST. IF YOU GRANTHAM A C YOU A THE
OWNER OF THIS PROPERTY ONE OF 4 TO 114 PRESIDIO AVENUE WILL
CONVERT SEVEN HOUSING WHO CONVERTED SEVEN HOUSING UNITS
INTO A $32,000,000.20 6000 SQUARE FOOT PRIVATE ESTATE WILL
BE RIGHT BEHIND HIM. THE CRITERIA FOR OVERTURNING
THE PLANNING COMMISSION DECISION HAS NOT BEEN MET.
>> THERE WERE NO ERRORS IN INTERPRETING THE PLANNING
CODE OR ABUSE OF DISCRETION BY THE PLANNING COMMISSION.
AS MY MOTHER USED TO TELL ME TO WRONGS DON'T MAKE IT RIGHT.
>> THANK YOU. THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
>> ARE THERE ANY OTHER MEMBERS OF THE PUBLIC WHO ARE
INTERESTED IN THE CONTINUANCE OF ITEMS NINE THROUGH 12 THE
PUBLIC HEARING OF PERSONS INTERESTED IN THE DE FACTO
DENIAL OF A CONDITIONAL USE AUTHORIZATION FOR THE VALLEJOS
AND STREET AND ANTONIO PLACE PROJECTS?
>> ALL RIGHT, MR. PRESIDENT. >> ALL RIGHT.
PUBLIC COMMENT ON THE CONTINUANCE IS CLOSED.
>> AND SO COLLEAGUES, WE HAVE THIS MOTION TO CONTINUE THE
HEARING OPEN TO THE APRIL 7TH, 2026 BOARD OF SUPERVISORS
MEETING. I IMAGINE THAT WE CAN TAKE THAT
WITHOUT OBJECTION. >> MR. PRESIDENT, WE HAVE A
DIFFERENT HOUSE. >> OH, NOPE.
WE GOT TO DO A ROLL CALL. >> THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK.
ON THE MOTION TO CONTINUE ITEMS NINE THROUGH 12 OPEN TO APRIL
7TH SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY EYES SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER
I SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN HI
MENDELSON I SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SADR SADR I
SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I
SUPERVISOR WONG WONG I SUPERVISOR CHAN I I CHAN I
AND SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN I THERE ARE 11 EYES WITHOUT
OBJECTION THIS APPEAL HEARING AND ITS ASSOCIATED MOTIONS ARE
CONTINUED OPEN TO APRIL 7TH 2026 AND I THINK MADAM CLERK
THAT TAKES US TO ROLL CALL YES THE FIRST MEMBER TO INTRODUCE
ROLL CALL FOR INTRODUCTIONS IS SUPERVISOR DORSEY.
THANK YOU MADAM CLERK. COLLEAGUES I HAVE A COUPLE OF
THINGS TODAY BOTH RELATING TO AN EMAIL I SENT LAST WEEK
OUTLINING THE BASIS FOR MY OPPOSITION TO A PROPOSED LEASE
FOR OUR EMPLOYEES RETIREMENT SYSTEM IN ITS BID TO RELOCATE
FROM ITS LONGSTANDING LOCATION IN THE CIVIC CENTER AREA TO A
LUXURY OFFICE HIGH RISE IN THE FINANCIAL DISTRICT.
AS YOU MAY RECALL, I HAD A FEW REASONS FIRST, LEAVING ASIDE MY
FEELINGS ABOUT THAT AGENCY'S RATIONALE TO IMPROVE ITS
PROXIMITY TO FINANCIAL SERVICES VENDOR VENDORS TO THE DETRIMENT
OF PROXIMITY TO THE CITY EMPLOYEES WHOSE RETIREMENT
DOLLARS IT MANAGES. THIS MOVE IS INCONSISTENT WITH
THE BOARD LEGISLATED POLICIES ENSHRINED IN OUR GENERAL PLAN.
IN PARTICULAR IT WOULD ABANDON CIVIC CENTER AREA PLAN
OBJECTIVES TO MAINTAIN AND REINFORCE THE CIVIC CENTER
AS QUOTE THE FOCUS OF COMMUNITY GOVERNMENT AND TO DEVELOP THE
CIVIC CENTER AS A COHESIVE AREA FOR THE ADMINISTRATIVE
FUNCTIONS OF CITY, STATE AND FEDERAL GOVERNMENT.
THESE BOARD ENACTED PLANNING PRIORITIES WILL BE ESSENTIAL IF
WE ARE TO RESTORE THE VIBRANCY AND WELL-BEING OF
NEIGHBORHOODS. I REPRESENT INCLUDING
MID-MARKET CIVIC CENTER WEST SOMA THE HUB IN PORTIONS OF
HAYS VALLEY MOST OF WHICH WERE DISPROPORTIONATELY HARMED BY
CITY GOVERNMENT POLICIES DURING THE COVID PANDEMIC.
IN MY VIEW ANY CITY AGENCY'S PROPOSED MOVE OUT OF CIVIC
CENTER REPRESENTS THE EXACT OPPOSITE OF WHAT OUR CITY
SHOULD BE DOING TO REINVEST AND REINVIGORATE OUR ADJACENT
NEIGHBORHOODS WITH STRATEGIC INVESTMENTS OF OUR CITY'S OWN
REAL ESTATE ASSETS. AND I WILL HAVE MORE TO SAY ON
THAT IN THE NEXT WEEK OR TWO. SECOND, GIVEN THESE POLICY
IMPLICATIONS OF OUR GENERAL PLAN EVEN BEYOND THE CHARTER
PROVISIONS THAT ASSURE THIS WILL BE SUBJECT TO BOARD
APPROVAL ANYWAY, THIS BOARD OF SUPERVISORS DESERVES TO BE
CONSULTED MUCH SOONER THAN IT WAS IN MY VIEW.
WE SHOULD NEVER BE PUT INTO SITUATIONS WHERE SUNKEN COSTS
AND ADMINISTRATIVE PRESUMPTIONS RISK UP BEING UPENDED BECAUSE
WE AS A BOARD DECLINED TO BEHAVE LIKE POTTED PLANTS.
WE ARE ELECTED TO DO OUR DUTIES UNDER THE CITY CHARTER WHICH
INCLUDES POLICYMAKING AUTHORITY AND THIS PROPOSED MOVE WAS A
POLICY MATTER BEFORE IT WAS ANYTHING.
THIRD, I REMAIN UNCONVINCED THAT THIS AGENCY'S SEARCH FOR A
NEW LAKE LOCATION WAS A GOOD FAITH EXERCISE TO MAXIMIZE
VALUE FOR THE EMPLOYEES PENSION TRUST.
THE REPRESENTATION IN THE BUDGET AND LEGISLATIVE
ANALYST'S REPORT AND TO ME DIRECTLY WAS THAT FIRST TOURED
AND EVALUATED A TOTAL OF 20 BUILDINGS FOR THEIR NEW SITE
ONLY AFTER OBTAINING THE ACTUAL LIST OF 20 BUILDINGS.
DID IT BECOME EVIDENT TO ME THAT 19 OF THE 20 BUILDINGS
WERE IN THE FINANCIAL DISTRICT? ONLY ONE OPTION WAS IN THE
CIVIC CENTER AND DESPITE ITS COST SAVINGS IT WAS REJECTED.
ACCORDINGLY, I AM TODAY ANNOUNCING TWO ITEMS FIRST A
LEGISLATIVE DRAFTING REQUEST FOR A PROPOSED AMENDMENT TO OUR
ADMINISTRATIVE CODE TO ENSURE THAT THERE IS AN EARLY POLICY
MAKING ROLE FOR THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS WHENEVER CITY REAL
ESTATE DECISIONS INTEND TO DEPART FROM BOARD ENACTED
POLICIES ENSHRINED IN OUR CIVIC CENTER AREA PLAN.
AND SECOND A LETTER OF INQUIRY REQUESTING THAT THE CITY
ADMINISTRATOR'S OFFICE DIRECT ITS REAL ESTATE DIVISION TO
SURVEY ALL POSSIBLE ALTERNATIVES FORCE FIRMS
RELOCATION WITHIN THE MID-MARKET AND CIVIC CENTER
AREA AND TO DO SO IN CONFORMANCE WITH THE SPIRIT
OF OUR GENERAL PLAN. AND ON BEHALF OF MY MID-MARKET
AND CIVIC CENTER AREA NEIGHBORS, PLEASE KNOW HOW MUCH
I APPRECIATE EVERYONE'S CONSIDERATION ON THIS AND THE
REST I SUBMIT. >> THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR DORSEY SUPERVISOR FIELDER.
>> THANK YOU MADAM CLERK. COLLEAGUES TODAY I AM
REQUESTING THAT THE BUDGET AND LEGISLATIVE ANALYST'S
OFFICE COMPLETE AN AUDIT OF THE SHERIFF'S OFFICE.
THIS AUDIT IS NOT AN INDICTMENT OF ANY ONE PERSON OR WORKFORCE
. >> THE SHERIFFS ARE ESTEEMED
AND VALUED PUBLIC SERVANTS WHO SECURE OUR CITY BUILDINGS
AND PROTECTS PUBLIC SAFETY. >> I KNOW ALL OF US AT THE
BOARD ARE GRATEFUL EVERY DAY WE HAVE THE SHERIFFS SECURING THIS
BUILDING AND MANY OTHERS AROUND THE CITY.
WITH THAT SAID, IT IS A PART OF OUR JOB ON THE BOARD TO ENSURE
THAT PUBLIC FUNDS ARE USED EFFICIENTLY AND DUTIFULLY ON
BEHALF OF TAXPAYERS. ESPECIALLY DURING A BUDGET
DEFICIT AND WHEN MANY SAN FRANCISCANS ARE WANTING
COMMUNITY POLICING. THERE ARE SEVERAL REASONS I'M
CALLING FOR THIS AUDIT THIS YEAR.
>> FIRSTLY, THE SHERIFF'S DEPARTMENT IS PROJECTED TO
OVERRUN ITS OVERTIME BUDGET BY $19 MILLION.
WE ALL RECENTLY RECEIVED A MEMO FROM THE COMPTROLLER'S OFFICE
NOTING THAT FROM JULY 1ST, 2025, THE START OF THIS FISCAL
YEAR TO FEBRUARY 13TH 2026 SHERIFF EXPENDITURES ESPECIALLY
ON OVERTIME HAS BALLOONED SO MUCH THAT ACCORDING TO THE
COMPTROLLER, IF THE RATE OF EXPENDITURES CONTINUES TO
EXCEED THE BUDGET, EVEN SAVINGS ON VACANT POSITIONS DRAWING
FROM RESERVES, EQUIPMENT, CAPITAL PROJECTS AND FACILITIES
MAINTENANCE WILL NOT BE ENOUGH TO FUND THE SHORTFALL AND COULD
MATERIALLY IMPACT OPERATIONS. >> AT THE SAME TIME THAT OUR
PUBLIC HEALTH DEPARTMENT FUNDING IS BEING CUT BY $40
MILLION, THIS DISPARITY RAISES SERIOUS QUESTIONS ABOUT OUR
CITY'S PRIORITIES AND COMMITMENT TO FISCAL
OVERSIGHT. >> SECONDLY, THE SHERIFF'S
DEPARTMENT HAS BEEN THE CENTER OF A NUMBER OF TROUBLING
INCIDENTS FURTHER DEEPENING THE PUBLIC'S CONCERNS ABOUT
TRANSPARENCY AND MANAGEMENT. THERE HAVE ALREADY BEEN COSTLY
CONSEQUENCES. >> THE CITY WAS SUED BY THE BAY
AREA QUALITY MANAGEMENT DISTRICT AFTER PEPPER BALL
LAUNCHER GAS DRIFTED ON TO THE CAMPUS OF PORTOLA ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL FROM A SHERIFF'S DEPARTMENT TRAINING EXERCISE
WITH THE CITY ULTIMATELY SETTLING THE CASE FOR THOUSANDS
OF DOLLARS THIS PAST FISCAL YEAR.
AND WE JUST APPROVED THAT SETTLEMENT HERE AT BOARD.
SEPARATELY MISSION LOCAL REPORTED DISTURBING ALLEGATIONS
FROM WOMEN INCARCERATED IN THE SAN FRANCISCO JAIL WHO SAY
DEPUTIES FORCED THEM TO UNDRESS DURING SEARCHES WHILE FILMING
THEM. CLAIMS THAT HAVE SPARKED
OUTRAGE AND CALLS FOR ACCOUNTABILITY FROM OUR
CONSTITUENTS. >> FINALLY, DESPITE SAN
FRANCISCO'S SANCTUARY POLICIES ,ICE CONTINUES TO OPERATE HERE
IN SAN FRANCISCO AND THE SHERIFF'S DEPARTMENT HAS
AUTHORITY OVER WHICH INDIVIDUALS IN COUNTY JAILS MAY
BE HANDED OVER TO FEDERAL IMMIGRATION AUTHORITIES.
>> THE PUBLIC DESERVES TO KNOW IF THE SHERIFF'S DEPARTMENT IS
HONORING OUR SANCTUARY CITY POLICY IN GOOD FAITH.
>> SAN FRANCISCANS DESERVE ACCOUNTABILITY WHEN IT COMES TO
HOW PUBLIC FUNDS ARE SPENT ESPECIALLY WHEN SERIOUS
ALLEGATIONS OF ABUSE AND POTENTIALLY FISCAL
NEGLIGENCE ARE AT HAND. TAXPAYERS HAVE A RIGHT TO KNOW
HOW THEIR MONEY IS BEING USED AND WHETHER PUBLIC RESOURCES
ARE BEING DIRECTED RESPONSIBLY, ESPECIALLY AMID OUR CITY'S
BUDGET DEFICIT. >> AND THAT IS WHY I AM
ANNOUNCING AN AUDIT OF THE SAN FRANCISCO SHERIFF'S DEPARTMENT.
>> SECONDLY, TODAY I HAVE AN IN MEMORIAM FOR DIAMOND DAVE
WHITAKER WHO DIED AT AGE 88 ON MARCH 2ND.
>> DIAMOND DAVE WAS A UBIQUITOUS CHARACTER IN SAN
FRANCISCO HAVING MOVED HERE AT AGE 19 IN 1957.
HE WAS THE QUINTESSENTIAL LIFELONG HIPPIE BEAT POET, PUNK
ROCKER AND POLITICAL ACTIVIST WHO MOVED IN AND OUT OF ART
AND ADVOCACY ACROSS THE CITY AND CONNECTED WITH EVERYONE HE
MET ALONG THE WAY OFFERING POETIC MUSINGS A GIANT SMILE
AND ALWAYS A TWINKLE IN HIS EYE.
>> DIAMOND DAVE WAS HONORED BY THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS
IN 2016 WITH A RESOLUTION COMMENDING HIM FOR HIS
CONTRIBUTIONS TO THE ARTS, CULTURE, SOCIAL WELL-BEING
AND PEACE AND DECLARING FEBRUARY 2ND, 2016 MEAN DIAMOND
DAVE WHITAKER DAY. THE LORE AROUND DIAMOND DAVE IS
ENDLESS. HE WAS AN EARLY MENTOR TO BOB
DYLAN TURNING HIM ON TO WOODY GUTHRIE AND JACK KEROUAC
AND ALLEGEDLY MARIJUANA TO SESSIONS FROM DYLAN'S THROUGH
THE OPEN WINDOW BOOTLEG SERIES WERE RECORDED AT DIAMOND DAVE'S
HOUSE IN MINNEAPOLIS. >> HE SHARED HIS PERSONAL
ACCOUNTS OF MANY MAJOR HISTORICAL EVENTS HE WITNESSED
IN PERSON WHICH HE CALLED HIS HIP STORY.
MARTIN LUTHER KING JR IS I HAVE A DREAM SPEECH IN D.C. AS A
PASSENGER ON THE FURTHER BUS TO THE HUMAN BEING IN 1967
AND LATER THAT YEAR AT THE DEATH OF HIPPIES FUNERAL AND SO
MANY MORE PIVOTAL MOMENTS IN OUR NATION'S AND OUR CITY'S
HISTORY. >> HE SEEMED TO ALWAYS BE
EVERYWHERE IN SAN FRANCISCO'S COUNTERCULTURE HISTORY.
HE COOKED FREE FOOD WITH THE DIGGERS IN THE SUMMER OF LOVE
AND FOOD NOT BOMBS IN THE 1990S THROUGH THE 20 TENS.
HE WAS ONE OF THE FOUNDERS OF COWPOKE RADIO IN THE 1970S
AND HOSTED A LONG RUNNING LIVE MUSIC AND POETRY SHOW ON PIRATE
CAT RADIO WHICH WOULD LATER BECOME MUTINY RADIO IN DISTRICT
NINE AT THE CORNER OF FLORIDA AND 24TH STREET.
WHILE THAT RADIO STATION CLOSED A FEW YEARS AGO, HE DID NOT
STOP WRITING AND RECITING POETRY HERE AND THERE
AND REALLY EVERYWHERE. >> HE WAS A MEMBER OF THE
FLOWER SHOP ART COLLECTIVE NEXT TO THE ALEMANY FARMERS MARKET.
HE WAS A LIFELONG STUDENT AT CITY COLLEGE AND FOR MANY YEARS
WAS CELEBRATED AS THE OLDEST SENATOR OF CITY COLLEGE'S
ASSOCIATED STUDENT COUNCIL. >> HIS LEGACY IS A LONG WINDING
ROAD OF POETRY MUSIC, ART AND PROTEST AND I EXPRESS MY
CONDOLENCES TO HIS FAMILY, FRIENDS AND THE BROADER
COMMUNITY OF HUNDREDS OF SAN FRANCISCANS WHO KNEW HIM SO
WELL. AND THERE IS COMFORT IN KNOWING
HE LEFT A LASTING MARK ON SAN FRANCISCO BY ALWAYS LIVING HIS
LIFE IN LINE WITH HIS TRADEMARK POEM THAT SO MANY OF US KNOW BY
HEART CAST A WIDE NET FIND THE COMMON THREAD LET LIFE FLOURISH
AND DON'T PANIC KEEP IT ORGANIC REST IN PEACE AND POWER DOWN
DAVE. >> THE REST I SUBMIT.
THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR FIELDER.
SUPERVISOR MUHAMMAD SUBMIT. THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK.
I HAVE A FEW ITEMS TODAY. FIRST AN UPDATE FOR THOSE
WHO'VE BEEN FOLLOWING OUR EFFORTS TO PUSH FOR MORE EV
CHARGERS ON THE SIDEWALKS OR IN ON CURBSIDE IN SAN FRANCISCO
ESPECIALLY MEMBERS OF THE LAND USE COMMITTEE AND CHAIR MELGAR
AND OTHERS WHO PARTICIPATED IN OUR DEC NOT ENTIRELY
SATISFYING AT THE TIME HEARING I THINK WE WERE HEARD AND SO
TODAY THE MAYOR AND I ARE INTRODUCING LEGISLATION TO
ESTABLISH A PERMITTING PATHWAY AND PROGRAM TO ALLOW CURBSIDE
CHARGING TO GO FROM THE PILOT THAT IT IS NOW TO TO SCALE.
IT'LL CREATE A NEW PROCESS FOR BUILDING ON THAT TEMPORARY
CURBSIDE PILOT PROGRAM THAT HAS GOTTEN TWO CURBSIDE CHARGERS
AND TO BOTH TRIANGLE AND WILL BE GETTING MORE INTO OTHER
NEIGHBORHOODS IMMINENTLY AND THE ADDITION OF THESE
CURBSIDE CHARGERS WOULD MAKE IT EASIER FOR RESIDENTS WHO LIVE
IN APARTMENTS AND MAY NOT HAVE ACCESS TO A CHARGER IN THEIR
BUILDING TO TO HAVE AN ELECTRIC VEHICLE.
>> SO I'M GRATEFUL TO ALL THE FOLKS ESPECIALLY THE FOLKS AT
THE MTA, KATE TRAN AND OTHERS WHO'VE MADE THAT HAPPEN.
>> SECONDLY, TODAY SUPERVISOR WALTON AND I ARE INTRODUCING A
RESOLUTION TO RECOGNIZE MARCH 28TH, 2026 AS JOHN AND INA
DEARMAN DAY IN THE CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN FRANCISCO.
MARCH 28TH WILL BE JOHN'S 95TH BIRTHDAY AND WILL MARK 48 YEARS
FROM THE DATE WHEN HE WAS FIRST APPOINTED TO THE MUNICIPAL
COURT OF SAN FRANCISCO AND SIX YEARS FROM THE DATE OF HIS
RETIREMENT FROM THE BENCH. HE WAS BORN ON MARCH 28TH,
1931. INA WAS BORN ON FEBRUARY 4TH,
1936 AND DIED IN JANUARY 24TH OF LAST YEAR ON JANUARY 24TH OF
LAST YEAR. IT HAS BEEN MY GREAT HONOR AS A
SUPERVISOR TO HAVE REPRESENTED THESE TWO EXTRAORDINARY MUCH
ADMIRED AND MUCH BELOVED LEADERS WHO BROKE BARRIERS
AND DEDICATED THEIR LIVES TO ADVANCING CIVIL RIGHTS
AND JUSTICE WHO WERE ALWAYS COMMITTED TO DOING THE RIGHT
THING AND STANDING UP FOR THOSE WHOSE VOICES TOO OFTEN GO
UNHEARD. BORN INTO POVERTY IN TEXAS,
JOHN GREW UP ATTENDING SEGREGATED PRIMARY SCHOOLS
AND SPENT PART OF HIS CHILDHOOD PICKING COTTON AS A
SHARECROPPER. DESPITE INTENSE DISCRIMINATION
AMONG A NUMBER OF CHALLENGES, JOHN EXCELLED ACADEMICALLY
THROUGHOUT HIS SCHOOLING IN TEXAS AND LATER IN MICHIGAN.
HE COMPLETED HIS UNDERGRADUATE STUDIES AT WILEY COLLEGE
AND EARNED A LAW DEGREE FROM WAYNE STATE UNIVERSITY.
HIS EXPERIENCES GROWING UP INSPIRED HIS LIFELONG FIGHT FOR
JUSTICE AND HIS ADVOCACY FOR VULNERABLE AND MARGINALIZED
COMMUNITIES. AS A BLACK LAWYER IN DETROIT,
JOHN WAS REPEATEDLY DENIED OPPORTUNITIES AT LAW FIRMS
AND SUPPLEMENTED HIS INCOME THROUGH SOCIAL WORK.
WHEN IT BECAME CLEAR THAT IT WOULD NOT BE FEASIBLE FOR HIM
TO PURSUE A LAW CAREER IN MICHIGAN, HE MOVED TO
CALIFORNIA IN 1959. CALIFORNIA, OF COURSE HAD
PLENTY OF ITS OWN BARRIERS TO BLACK ADVANCEMENT.
RACIAL MINORITIES FACED IMMENSE ECONOMIC DISADVANTAGE
AND EXTREME WEALTH INEQUALITY AND MANY LANDLORDS IN THE 50S
WERE REFUSING TO RENT OR SELL HOMES TO AFRICAN-AMERICANS.
SHORTLY AFTER HE ARRIVED IN SAN FRANCISCO, HE MET WILLIE BROWN.
THE TWO QUICKLY ROSE TO PROMINENCE DEMONSTRATING
AGAINST DISCRIMINATION IN HOUSING DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS
IN FOREST KNOLLS WHERE DEVELOPERS HAD REFUSED TO SELL
HOMES TO AFRICAN-AMERICANS. THEIR CIVIL DISOBEDIENCE
AND CONTEMPORARY CONTEMPORANEOUS COMMUNITY
ACTIVISM HELPED CONTRIBUTE TO THE PASSAGE OF THE FAIR HOUSING
ACT OF 1968. >> IN 1965 JOHN AND WILLIE
BROWN FOUNDED THE BROWN, DEARMAN AND SMITH LAW FIRM THAT
OPERATED OUT OF THE HEART OF THE FILLMORE AND AMONG OTHER
THINGS INTO REPUTATION FOR REPRESENTING CIVIL RIGHTS
PROTESTERS. ON MARCH 28TH, 1977, FORMER
GOVERNOR JERRY BROWN APPOINTED JOHN TO THE MUNICIPAL COURT OF
SAN FRANCISCO. HE WOULD LASER LATER RISE TO
THE SUPERIOR COURT IN 1979 WHERE HE SERVED AS PRESIDING
JUDGE FROM 1990 TO 1991. HE THEN WENT ON TO SPEND NINE
YEARS OVERSEEING THE SAN FRANCISCO PROBATE COURT BEFORE
OFFICIALLY RETIRING FROM THE BENCH ON MARCH 28TH, 2009.
HE WAS ONE OF THE LONGEST SERVING JUDGES IN SAN
FRANCISCO. >> HIS BACKGROUND INSPIRED HIS
LIFELONG DEDICATION TO ADVOCATING FOR THE UNDERDOG,
THE VULNERABLE AND MARGINALIZED COMMUNITIES.
HE CREDITS PART OF HIS SUCCESS TO THOSE IN HIS LIFE WHO SAW
WHAT HE COULD ACHIEVE AND WHO OPENED HIS EYES TO WHAT HE WHAT
WOULD BE POSSIBLE. CHIEF AMONG THOSE INDIVIDUALS
WAS HIS EXTRAORDINARY WIFE INA .
INA WAS BORN INA FLEMING. SHE GRADUATED HIGH SCHOOL AT
AGE 16 AND EARNED A BACHELOR'S DEGREE FROM THE COLLEGE OF
PACIFIC NOW UNIVERSITY PACIFIC AND A MASTER'S IN SOCIAL WORK
FROM UC BERKELEY IN 1961, JUST A FEW MONTHS AFTER SHE MARRIED
JOHN AND FOUND OUT SHE WAS PREGNANT.
SHE WAS DIAGNOSED WITH MULTIPLE SCLEROSIS.
SHE WOULD SURVIVE 70 MORE YEARS WITH THE DISEASE AS WELL AS
RECOVER FROM TWO KINDS OF CANCER AND A BROKEN BACK.
ALL THE WHILE RAISING HER FAMILY AND CONTRIBUTING TO HER
COMMUNITY. SHE WAS A WOMAN OF UNYIELDING
OPTIMISM, DISCIPLINE AND GRIT. IN 1969 SHE CO-FOUNDED THE
CROSS-CULTURAL FAMILY CENTER WHICH FOR 55 YEARS HAS PROVIDED
MENTAL HEALTH AND EARLY EDUCATION SERVICES TO CHILDREN
AND FAMILIES ACROSS SAN FRANCISCO, INCLUDING IN THE
WESTERN EDITION TENDERLOIN METRO HILL, CASTRO, HAYS
VALLEY, THE RICHMOND DISTRICT AND VISITATION VALLEY.
INA ALSO SERVED ON LOCAL NATIONAL INTERNATIONAL BOARDS
OF THE YWCA, WORKED AS A TREASURER AND VOLUNTEER FOR
NUMEROUS POLITICAL CAMPAIGNS INCLUDING I THINK SOME OF OURS
AND SERVED ON MANY SAN FRANCISCO BOARDS INCLUDING THE
PLANNING COMMISSION AND THE LANDMARK'S PRESERVATION
ADVISORY BOARD. EVEN IN HER LATER YEARS WITH
LIMITED MOBILITY, SHE REMAINED COMMITTED TO SOCIAL ACTION.
ONE OF HER FINAL PROJECTS INVOLVED DELIVERING FOOD FROM
FARMERS MARKETS TO HOMEBOUND SENIORS PATIENTLY EXPLAINING
THE MISSION TO ANY CONCERNED NEIGHBORS WHO MIGHT QUESTION
THE TEMPORARY DOUBLE PARKING. INA WAS FORMIDABLE, PURPOSE
DRIVEN, THOUGHTFUL OF OTHERS UNAFRAID TO SPEAK THE TRUTH
AND A RELENTLESS SOLDIER FOR GOOD.
SHE SHARED WITH JOHN A LOVE FOR SAN FRANCISCO, A CITY THEY
CALLED HOME FOR OVER 7060. FOR OVER 64 YEARS.
AND THIS BOARD HONORED HER WITH A SPECIAL COMMENDATION ON JULY
NINTH, 2019. THIS RESOLUTION IS A SHOW OF
GRATITUDE FOR JOHN AND INA FOR THEIR WORK AND AN OPPORTUNITY
FOR THIS BOARD TO HONOR THEIR ACHIEVEMENTS AND LEGACY.
SO I'M HOPING YOU'LL ALL BE I KNOW YOU'LL ALL BE SUPPORTING
MAKING MARCH 28TH 2026 JOHN AND INA DEARMAN DAY IN THE CITY
AND COUNTY OF SAN FRANCISCO. AND FINALLY I'M INTRODUCING AN
ORDINANCE TO EXTEND FOR AN ADDITIONAL FIVE YEARS OUR
EXISTING DELEGATION OF AUTHORITY TO THE SAN FRANCISCO
PUC TO ENTER INTO GRANTS OF UP TO 20 YEARS FOR THEIR GREEN
INFRASTRUCTURE GRANT PROGRAM. >> SAN FRANCISCO'S WASTEWATER
AND STORMWATER FLOW THROUGH THE SAME PIPES.
SO IT'S ESPECIALLY IMPORTANT THAT WE MANAGE STORMWATER
EFFECTIVELY TO PROTECT THE RELIABILITY AND PERFORMANCE OF
OUR SEWER SYSTEM. SFP USES GREEN INFRASTRUCTURE
GRANT PROGRAM FACILITATES THIS BY SUPPORTING PROJECTS THAT
CAPTURE AND ABSORB RAINWATER USING NATURE BASED SOLUTIONS
SUCH AS PERMEABLE PAVEMENT RAIN GARDENS AND VEGETATED ROOFS.
THROUGH THESE PROJECTS THE PROGRAM REDUCES PRESSURE ON THE
SEWER SYSTEM WHILE DELIVERING COMMUNITY BENEFITS LIKE
NEIGHBORHOOD GREENING, CLIMATE RESILIENCE AND IMPROVED PUBLIC
SPACES. THE EFFECTIVE LIFECYCLE AND THE
EFFECTIVE LIFECYCLE AND REQUIRED MAINTENANCE PERIOD
OF MOST GREEN INFRASTRUCTURE PROJECTS IS ROUGHLY 20 YEARS SO
THE PUC'S GRANT LENGTH REFLECTS THAT AS GRANT AGREEMENTS
IN EXCESS OF TEN YEARS REQUIRED DELEGATION OF AUTHORITY WE MADE
THIS DELEGATION TO THE SFP U.S. GENERAL MANAGER IN 2019
AND HAVE EXTENDED IT ROUGHLY EVERY TWO YEARS SINCE.
THIS AUDIENCE SIMPLY EXTENDS THAT DELEGATION FOR ANOTHER
FIVE YEARS, REDUCING THE NUMBER OF TIMES THE PUC WILL HAVE TO
RETURN TO THIS BODY TO IMPLEMENT IMPLEMENT A PROGRAM
THAT BENEFITS OUR SEWER SYSTEM, OUR NEIGHBORHOODS AND OUR
ENVIRONMENT. I WANT TO THANK JEREMY SPITZ
AND HIS COLLEAGUES AT THE SFP WHO HAVE WORKED ON THIS
LEGISLATION AS WELL AS MY LEGISLATIVE AIDE RON LBJ
AND THE REST I SUBMIT. >> THANK YOU MR. PRESIDENT.
SUPERVISOR MELGAR SUBMIT SUBMIT.
THANK YOU SUPERVISORS ORDER. >> THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK.
COLLEAGUES TODAY I HAVE TWO RESOLUTIONS IN SUPPORT OF STATE
BILLS THAT I BELIEVE WILL IMPROVE THE HEALTH AND SAFETY
OF OUR RESIDENTS IN SAN FRANCISCO.
>> FIRST I AM INTRODUCING A RESOLUTION IN SUPPORT OF A BILL
2276 THE STOP SUPER SPEEDERS ACT.
>> THIS BILL FROM ASSEMBLYMEMBER ESMERALDA SORIA
WOULD ESTABLISH A FIVE YEAR STATEWIDE PILOT REQUIRING
CERTAIN RECKLESS SPEEDERS TO INSTALL ACTIVE INTELLIGENT
SPEED ASSISTANT ASSISTANCE DEVICES BEFORE RETURNING TO THE
ROAD. UNDER THIS BILL, INDIVIDUALS
WHO HAVE OFFENSES INCLUDING RECKLESS DRIVING, ENGAGING
IN SPEED CONTESTS OR DRIVING MORE THAN 100MPH COULD BE
REQUIRED TO INSTALL DEVICES WHICH ACTIVELY LIMIT A
VEHICLE'S SPEED. A RECENT PILOT OF A SIMILAR
PROGRAM IN NEW YORK CITY IS SHOWING PROMISE WITH A 64%
REDUCTION IN TOTAL TIME SPENT SPEEDING AND A 37% DROP
IN HEARTBREAKING THE TRAGEDIES OF THE LAST WEEK HERE IN SAN
FRANCISCO IN WHICH WE SAW THREE PEDESTRIAN FATALITIES ON OUR
STREETS ONLY UNDERSCORED THE URGENCY IN WHICH WE MUST ACT
FOR SAFER STREETS. I WANT TO THANK SUPERVISOR
MAHMOOD FOR HIS CO-SPONSORSHIP AND I HOPE MANY OTHERS WILL
JOIN. NEXT, I'M INTRODUCING A
RESOLUTION IN SUPPORT OF STATE SENATE BILL 1218.
THIS BILL WAS INTRODUCED BY SENATOR JESSE ARAGON
IN PARTNERSHIP WITH OAKLAND MAYOR BARBARA LEE AND WILL
REQUIRE THE DEPARTMENT OF MOTOR VEHICLES TO REFUSE TO RENEW THE
REGISTRATION OF A VEHICLE IF THE REGISTERED OWNER OR LEASE
LESSEE HAS OUTSTANDING ILLEGAL DUMPING PENALTIES.
>> MY OFFICE HAS BEEN WORKING WITH CITY DEPARTMENTS TO
SHARPEN OUR ENFORCEMENT TOOLS AGAINST ILLEGAL DUMPING.
BUT THERE'S MORE TO DO THAT REQUIRES HELP FROM THE STATE.
IN 2025 THE DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WORKS ISSUED OVER 500
NOTICES OF VIOLATION AND 250 CITATIONS FOR ILLEGAL DUMPING
BUT ONLY ABOUT 40% OF THOSE FINES HAD BEEN PAID, LEAVING
TENS OR HUNDREDS OF THOUSANDS OF DOLLARS IN FINES
UNCOLLECTED. THE DMV HAS EXISTING AUTHORITY
TO REFUSE TO RENEW THE REGISTRATION OF A VEHICLE IF
THE REGISTERED OWNER OR LISI HAS A DELINQUENT PARKING
TICKET. AND SB 1218 WOULD EXPAND THAT
AUTHORITY TO ALSO CONSIDER OUTSTANDING VIOLATIONS RELATED
TO ILLEGAL DUMPING. I WANT TO THANK SUPERVISOR
WALTON AND SUPERVISOR MAHMUD FOR THEIR CO-SPONSORSHIP ON
THIS ITEM AND THE REST I SUBMIT.
>> THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR SAUTER SUPERVISE
FROM CHERYL. COLLEAGUES TODAY I ASK FOR US
TO ADJOURN IN MEMORY OF LIEUTENANT FRANK SKIP LUCIER, A
DEDICATED MEMBER OF THE SAN FRANCISCO FIRE DEPARTMENT FOR
MORE THAN 23 YEARS. ON THE NIGHT OF THE 1989 LOMA
PRIETA EARTHQUAKE, FRANK WAS ON DUTY AS OUR CITY FACED FIRES,
COLLAPSED BUILDINGS AND A CRITICAL LACK OF WATER AMID THE
DEVASTATION. NEIGHBORS RUSHED IN TO HELP
CARING HOSES PULLING BRICKS FROM THE RUBBLE AND DOING
WHATEVER THEY COULD TO SAVE LIVES.
AS FRANK LATER REFLECTED, PEOPLE WERE WILLING AND READY
TO BE DIRECTED BUT THEY DID NOT YET HAVE THE SKILLS.
FROM THAT EXPERIENCE A VISION WAS BORN.
IN 1990, FRANK BECAME THE FIRST PROGRAM COORDINATOR OF THE
NEIGHBORHOOD EMERGENCY RESPONSE TEAM OR NOT HELPING BRING
STRUCTURE AND LEADERSHIP TO A NEW EFFORT TO TRAIN SAN
FRANCISCANS TO RESPOND SAFELY AND EFFECTIVELY IN DISASTERS.
HE HELPED BUILD NERD FROM THE GROUND UP, SHAPING A MODEL OF
COMMUNITY PREPAREDNESS THAT CONTINUES TO SERVE OUR CITY
TODAY. BY 1996, NEARLY 5000 VOLUNTEERS
HAD BEEN TRAINED AND I'VE HAD THE PRIVILEGE OF ATTENDING A
FEW CLASSES MYSELF AND I CAN TELL YOU FIRSTHAND HOW
DEDICATED THE VOLUNTEERS AND FIRE DEPARTMENT LEADERS ARE
TO ENSURING WE ARE ALL PREPARED TO SERVE OUR CITY IN A TIME OF
CRISIS. NOW FRANK DIDN'T JUST STOP
IN SAN FRANCISCO. HE TRAVELED NATIONWIDE TRAINING
COMMUNITIES IN DISASTER PREPAREDNESS.
FRANK'S LEADERSHIP DEDICATED DEDICATION TO COMMUNITY
EMPOWERMENT AND BELIEF IN SERVICE LEFT A LEGACY THAT
LIVES ON THROUGH EVERY NURSE GRADUATE AND EVERY ACT OF
NEIGHBORS HELPING NEIGHBORS. I EXTEND MY HEARTFELT
CONDOLENCES TO LIEUTENANT LUCAS FAMILY AND FRIENDS WHO KEEP HIS
IMAGE ALIVE ESPECIALLY HIS WIFE KATHLEEN, HIS SONS
AND DAUGHTERS AND HIS MANY GRANDCHILDREN.
REST IN PEACE, LIEUTENANT, AND THANK YOU FOR YOUR SERVICE
TO OUR CITY. >> THE REST I SUBMIT.
THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR CHERYL SUPERVISOR
WALTON. >> THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK.
COLLEAGUES TODAY WE HONOR THE LIFE A VISITATION VALLEY
RESIDENT DR. KOOPMAN BIN MAHENDRA KUMAR DAVE WHO PASSED
AWAY PEACEFULLY AT HOME AT THE AGE OF 85.
DR. DAY WAS NOT SIMPLY A PHYSICIAN.
SHE WAS A PIONEER, A SERVANT, A BRIDGE BETWEEN CULTURES WHO GET
THE FULLEST MEASURE OF HERSELF TO THE COMMUNITIES SHE LOVED.
DR. DAVE BROKE BARRIERS FROM THE BEGINNING.
SHE BECAME THE FIRST DOCTOR IN OUR COMMUNITY AND THE FIRST
WOMAN DOCTOR TO SERVE HER TOWN. SHE WENT ON TO BECOME ONE OF
THE FIRST WOMAN PHYSICIANS FOR BAPS, A SPIRITUAL ORGANIZATION
THAT TODAY SERVES MILLIONS OF PEOPLE ACROSS INDIA AND AROUND
THE WORLD. SHE PRACTICED MEDICINE FOR 45
YEARS AND IN THAT TIME SHE ALSO TOUCHED THE LIVES OF MORE THAN
250 FAMILIES IN THE SAN FRANCISCO PENINSULA.
AMONG HER MANY ACTS OF QUIET GENEROSITY SHE OFFERED HER
MEDICAL SERVICES COMPLETELY FREE OF CHARGE TO A SCHOOL FOR
BLIND GIRLS. HER FAITH AND HER SERVICE WERE
INSEPARABLE. FOR MORE THAN 50 YEARS DR. DAY
VOLUNTEERED WITH BAPS COORDINATING RELIEF EFFORTS
IN THE AFTERMATH OF NATURAL DISASTERS AND SHOWING UP
WHEREVER SHE WAS NEEDED MOST. SHE WAS ALSO INSTRUMENTAL
IN THE FOUNDING OF THE FIRST HINDU TEMPLE IN SAN FRANCISCO.
LOCATED IN DISTRICT TEN AT 333 TUNNEL AVENUE, A PLACE WHERE
THOUSANDS OF PEOPLE HAVE SINCE FOUND PEACE, COMMUNITY
AND SPIRITUAL GROUNDING. DR. DAVE WAS EQUALLY DEVOTED TO
PRESERVING INDIAN CULTURE AND LANGUAGE FOR THE NEXT
GENERATION. SHE ORGANIZED INDIAN CULTURAL
FESTIVALS THROUGHOUT THE SAN FRANCISCO BAY AREA AND WORKED
TIRELESSLY TO ENSURE THAT CHILDREN HERE GREW UP WITH
THEIR CONNECTION TO THEIR HERITAGE AND MOTHER TONGUE.
DR. DAVE'S FUNERAL SERVICES WILL BE HELD THIS SATURDAY,
MARCH 14TH. THE REST I SUBMIT.
>> THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR WALTON.
SUPERVISOR OR ONE CUSTOMER SUBMIT.
THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR CHAN.
SUBMIT. THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR CHAN. SUBMIT.
THANK YOU, SUPERVISOR CHAN. MR. PRESIDENT, SEEING NO NAMES
ON THE ROSTER THAT CONCLUDES THE INTRODUCTION OF NEW
BUSINESS. >> THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK.
LET'S GO TO PUBLIC COMMENT. >> ALL RIGHT.
IF YOU ARE HERE IN THE PUBLIC GALLERY AND YOU'D LIKE TO
PROVIDE PUBLIC COMMENT TO THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS, NOW'S
YOUR OPPORTUNITY TO LINE UP ON YOUR RIGHT HAND SIDE OF THE
CHAMBER. YOU ARE ABLE TODAY TO SPEAK TO
THE MAYORAL APPEARANCE THE MINUTES AS PRESENTED ITEMS 23
THROUGH 32. THE ITEMS UP FOR ADOPTION
WITHOUT COMMITTEE REFERENCE AND OTHER AGENDA CONTENT THAT
UH I SHOULD SAY GENERAL MATTERS THAT ARE NOT ON THE AGENDA BUT
HAVE TO BE WITHIN THE BOARD SUBJECT MATTER JURISDICTION BUT
ALL OTHER AGENDA CONTENT HAS ALREADY BEEN REPORTED OUT BY A
BOARD COMMITTEE WHERE IT HAS HAD PUBLIC COMMENT.
WE ARE SETTING THE TIMER FOR TWO MINUTES.
I DO APOLOGIZE IF I'M INTERRUPTING ANYONE AND I WILL
INVITE THE FIRST SPEAKER WELCOME.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH. THIS COMMISSIONER HAKIMI I AM
HERE OF AN ITEM NUMBER 24. I WANT TO RECOGNIZE THAT WE ARE
ON THE UNCEDED ANCESTRAL HOMELAND OF THE AMATEUR COLONY
AND ORIGINAL PEOPLE INHABITANTS OF A SAN FRANCISCO PENINSULA.
PLEASE BEAR WITH ME. I'M GOING TO BE A LITTLE
EMOTIONAL AS I GO THROUGH THIS ITEM.
I WANT TO START BY THANKING SUPER SUPERVISOR DARCY AND YOUR
TEAM. WITHOUT YOUR SUPPORT WE WOULD
HAVE NOT BEEN HERE TODAY. SO I SINCE YOU ON A PERSONAL
THANK YOU SO MUCH AND I WANT TO ALSO THANK IS SPONSORING
SUPERVISORS PRESIDENT MANDO MIN TOOK OFFICE CHEN WALTON
AND WONG. I STAND HERE TODAY FULL OF
COMPLICATED EMOTIONS AS A PROUD IRANIAN-AMERICAN RESIDENT OF
THE MOST SIGNIFICANT CITY OR NOT KNOWING THAT MAGNIFICENT
CITY ON EARTH SAN FRANCISCO. I STAND IN GRATITUDE
AND APPRECIATION OF EACH AND EVERY ONE OF YOU FOR
CONSIDERING THIS RESOLUTION AT A VERY COMPLICATED MOMENT NOT
JUST FOR THE IRANIAN COMMUNITY BUT ALSO AS ALL OF US AS
AMERICAN AMERICAN COMMUNITY OR AMERICAN PEOPLE.
>> A YEAR AGO WHEN I STARTED TO WORK ON ENGAGING THE CITY HALL
ON A CONVERSATION ABOUT THE DEDICATION OF MONTH OF MARCH AS
THE IRANIAN AMERICAN HERITAGE MONTH I NEVER IMAGINED THAT I'D
BE STANDING IN THIS CHAMBER IN CELEBRATION OF SUCH A
MONUMENTAL MOMENT FOR OUR COMMUNITY COMBINED WITH SUCH A
MONUMENTAL MOMENT OF SORROW AND AGONY AS THE IRANIAN
AMERICAN COMMUNITY. >> AND YET I STAND IN FRONT OF
YOU HUMBLE AND GRATEFUL ON BEHALF OF A COMMUNITY THAT HAS
BEEN PART OF THE FABRIC OF THIS COUNTRY AND CITY FOR THE LAST
FOUR DECADES. A COMMUNITY THAT UNDERSTANDS
THE RESPONSE OF CARRYING A PROUD ANCIENT HERITAGE
IN HARMONY WITH ITS CIVIC AND SOCIAL RESPONSIBILITIES
IN THE COUNTY AND CITY WE CALL HOME.
THIS DECLARATION IS NOT ONLY FOR OUR COMMUNITY AS A
FORMALITY BUT ALSO RECOGNITION AND HOPE THAT WE FINALLY BELONG
IN THE HISTORY OF THE CITY WE PROUDLY CALL HOME.
>> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS AND WELCOME BACK TO THE CHAMBER
SUPERVISOR SAFAI BUT BEFORE I'LL ASK YOU TO BEGIN.
>> THROUGH A PREVIOUS ACCOMMODATION AND WE DO HAVE A
CALLER WHO IS PREPARED TO PROVIDE THEIR PUBLIC COMMENT
WHO'S ASKED TO GO NEXT. ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR PATIENCE. ALL RIGHT.
TO MY TEAM, CAN WE PLEASE SEND THE CALLER THROUGH?
>> WELCOME, PATRICK MANAGER. >> YEAH.
CAN YOU HEAR ME? YES.
I'LL SET THE TIME YOU BEGIN SPEAKING.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH. >> THIS IS PATRICK AT CHOP.
I AM HEARING FROM MY COLLEAGUES THAT UNLESS MAJOR CHANGES ARE
MADE BY THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS TWO RECOMMENDATIONS
FOR STREAMLINING TASK FORCE'S FINAL REPORT AND THE PROPOSED
LEGISLATION FOR THE CHARTER AMENDMENT.
THEY AND THEIR CONSTITUENTS WILL VOTE NO ON NEXT NOVEMBER.
I FULLY AGREE AND SHOULD THE MOTION ADD AGENDA ITEM 31 TODAY
PASS BEFORE THE STREAMLINING FINAL REPORT AND LEGISLATION
BACK FROM THE RULES COMMITTEE WITHOUT ADEQUATE REVIEW
AND COMMITTEE LEVEL HEARINGS BACK TO THE FULL BOARD FOR A
COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE HEARING THAT WILL ADD MORE FUEL TO THE
FIRE TO ENCOURAGE VOTERS TO REJECT ANY AND ALL CHARTER
CHANGE MEASURES ON THE NOVEMBER BALLOT.
YOU'VE BEEN WARNED DON'T PULL THIS OUT OF THE RULES COMMITTEE
ORDINANCE SECTION 3.22 THE 30 DAY RULE SPECIFICALLY STATES
THAT MEASURES INTRODUCED THAT WOULD CREATE OR REVISE MAJOR
CITY POLICY. THE COMMITTEE TO WHICH THE
MEASURE IS ASSIGNED SHALL NOT CONSIDER THE MEASURE UNTIL AT
LEAST 30 DAYS. SUPERVISOR MADELINE'S MOTION
HIJACKED THE LEGISLATIVE INTENT AND SPIRIT OF A 30 DAY RULE THE
BOARD OF SUPERVISORS SHOULD ALTHOUGH NO AMENDMENTS MOTION
TODAY SHOULD ALLOW THE RULES COMMITTEE REVIEW PROCESS TO
PLAY OUT AMENDMENTS MOTION TO PULL THE MATTER FROM THE RULES
COMMITTEE TO THE FULL BOARD APPEARED MAGICALLY JUST FOR
WORKING DAYS AFTER THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS RECEIVED THE TWO
PIECES OF LEGISLATION TRANSMITTED ON FEBRUARY 27TH.
BUT IT TOOK UNTIL MARCH 3RD FOR THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS TO
INTRODUCE THE PROPOSED LEGISLATION THROUGH A
SUBSTITUTE ASSIGNED PROCEDURE FOR THE RULES COMMITTEE ON
TUESDAY MARCH 3RD ASSIGNED TO BOARD FILE NUMBER 260147.
SUPERVISOR MANDEL MAN MUST SURELY KNOW THAT A 14 DAY
PERIOD BETWEEN ASSIGNING THE LEGISLATION TO THE RULES
COMMITTEE AND HOLDING A COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE HEARING
14 DAYS LATER ON MARCH 17TH IS NOT A FULL 30 DAY MORE WAITING
PERIOD. THERE'S NO NEED TO RUSH THIS
PROCESS. CHARTER AMENDMENTS FOR THE
NOVEMBER BALLOT FACE A DEADLINE OF JULY 24TH, 2026.
THERE'S NO NEED TO ELIMINATE THE RULES COMMITTEE HEARINGS OR
MULTIPLE HEARINGS AT THE RULES COMMITTEE.
AFTER ALL, JULY IS STILL FOUR MONTHS AWAY.
VOTE NO ON THE MOTION IN FILE NUMBER 260225 AT AGENDA ITEM
NUMBER 31 SEVEN MANDOLINS MOTION FROM THE ADOPTION
WITHOUT COMMITTEE REFERENCE AGENDA ITEM AND CONSIDER IT
SEPARATELY FROM THE OTHER ITEMS.
IF YOU DON'T AND YOU PULL IT FROM THE RULES COMMITTEE VOTERS
WILL REMEMBER THIS AND THEY REJECT THE BALLOT MEASURE
IN NOVEMBER. >> THANK YOU.
RIGHT. >> YOU TURN THEM OFF.
THANK YOU SO MUCH. THANK YOU FOR WAITING.
AND PLEASE WELCOME BACK TO THE CHAMBER SUPERVISOR SOPHIE.
>> THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK. THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT
AND MEMBERS OF THE BOARD HERE. WHEN I FIRST THANKED SUPERVISOR
DORSEY FOR SPONSORING THIS RESOLUTION ABOUT
IRANIAN-AMERICAN HERITAGE MONTH THE FIRST TIME WHEN I
SPECIFICALLY THANK MESA AND ALL OF THE WONDERFUL WOMEN BEHIND
HER AND HER COMMUNITY HER MOM IS HERE WITH HER TODAY.
>> I WANT TO ALSO WANT TO RECOGNIZE ALSO THE HARD WORK OF
MUHANDIS ON SUPERVISOR DORSEY STAFF FOR PUTTING THIS
TOGETHER. AS SHE SAID, I COULDN'T IMAGINE
THE PAIN AND SUFFERING THAT THE COMMUNITY WOULD BE FEELING
RIGHT NOW AROUND THE WORLD PARTICULARLY DURING THIS MONTH
OF RAMADAN WHEN PEOPLE ARE SUPPOSED TO BE SPIRITUAL
INTROSPECTION, FASTING AND RECOGNIZING ALL OF THE
TRANSGRESSIONS OF THE PAST YEAR.
>> WE'RE COMING UPON THE MOST IMPORTANT MONTH IN THE PERSIAN
CULTURE IRANIAN AMERICAN CULTURE IS THE NOWRUZ OR THE
NEW YEAR. SO IT'S GOING TO BE EXTREMELY
DIFFICULT TIME FOR EVERYTHING THAT'S GOING ON AND ALL THE
PEOPLE THAT ARE SUFFERING. BUT I KNOW AS MANNERS AND I
WERE TALKING EARLIER IT'S NOT JUST IRANIANS THAT ARE
SUFFERING AROUND THE WORLD. IT'S IMMIGRANTS COMING FROM
CENTRAL AMERICA AND ALL OVER THE WORLD.
IT'S PALESTINIANS, IT'S SUDANESE, IT'S MUSLIMS IS JEWS,
IT'S CHRISTIANS. IT'S IT'S EVERYONE RIGHT NOW
SUFFERING AT THE HANDS UNFORTUNATELY OF THIS COUNTRY
AND IT'S OKAY TO BE PROUD AMERICAN BUT ALSO BE CRITICAL
OF THE TRANSGRESSION OF THIS COUNTRY ON THE FIRST DAY OF
THIS SO-CALLED WAR, A SCHOOL OF 150 CHILDREN WERE KILLED.
AND SO THERE ARE THERE ARE NO WINNERS IN WAR.
BUT I WANTED TO COME HERE TODAY SPECIFICALLY TO SUPPORT THE
COMMUNITY, SUPPORT THIS RESOLUTION AND WHAT IT MEANS
FOR IRANIAN-AMERICANS RIGHT NOW DURING THIS TIME OF PAIN
AND SUFFERING. SO THANK YOU MEMBERS OF THE
BOARD. I HOPE YOU ALL I KNOW THERE'S
FIVE SPONSORS. I HOPE YOU ALL WILL UNANIMOUSLY
SIGN ON TO THIS. I KNOW IT'S SYMBOLIC BUT IT'S
EXTREMELY IMPORTANT FOR THIS CHAMBER AND THIS BOARD AND THIS
BODY TO SUPPORT THIS AT THIS TIME.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH. THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
I WILL JUST SAY BEFORE THE NEXT SPEAKER WE DO HAVE A BOARD RULE
IN THE CHAMBER WHERE THERE ARE NO SOUNDS OF OR THAT ARE
AUDIBLE TO THE BOARD WHETHER YOU SUPPORT OR DISAGREE.
BUT THANK YOU. I KNOW IT'S A CELEBRATORY
MOMENT TO HAVE THE SUPERVISOR HERE AND TO SPEAK OF THESE VERY
IMPORTANT ISSUES. ALL RIGHT.
SO WE'LL WELCOME OUR NEXT SPEAKER.
WELCOME TO THE CHAIR TO THE PODIUM SUPERVISES I WANT TO
TALK ABOUT THE SAN FRANCISCO PUBLIC UTILITIES COMMISSION.
>> IT STARTED WITH A BUDGET FOR THIS SEWER SYSTEM IMPROVEMENT
PROJECT FROM $6 BILLION. >> IT'S GONE TO $15 BILLION
HEADING TOWARDS $25 BILLION. >> SOME TIME AGO I CAME
AND TOLD YOU ALL THAT THREE WORKERS WERE FIRED FOR TELLING
THEIR SUPERVISORS TO DO THE RIGHT THING CONFINED SPACES
THEN IN A PROJECT WHERE YOU HAVE CONFINED SPACE THERE ARE
CERTAIN RULES AND REGULATIONS AND BECAUSE YOU ARE WORKING
UNDER VERY DIFFICULT SITUATIONS ON THE GROUND.
>> NOW I WAS AT THE SUPERVISORS SAN FRANCISCO PUBLIC UTILITIES
COMMISSION MEETING TODAY. I WAS HERE IN THIS CHAMBERS
TWICE AND I HEAR ABOUT SAN FRANCISCO PUBLIC UTILITY
COMMISSION WHERE THEY'RE SPENDING MONEY ON THINGS
WITHOUT ANY ACCOUNTABILITY. >> THE MAYOR ALLUDED TO IT IN A
WAY BUT LET ME TELL YOU THIS WE HAVE OUR RATIONAL LAWS AND YOU
WOULDN'T LIKE TO KNOW THAT THEY ARE FILTHY.
>> THEY HAVEN'T BEEN CLEANED. SO I'M ASKING THE BOARD OF
SUPERVISORS BECAUSE I BROUGHT IT TO THEIR ATTENTION.
I WANT SOMEBODY TO CONTACT THE HEALTH DEPARTMENT AND ALSO
AND SEE WHETHER IT IS RIGHT OR WRONG BECAUSE I GOT PHOTOGRAPHS
AND I GOT THE EMPIRICAL DATA. I'LL DRINKING WATER SHOULD BE
CLEAN OUT DRINKING WATER COMES FROM CHARITY.
>> IT'S SUPPOSED TO BE CLEAN BY THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS BY
JULY JOB AND DO DUE DILIGENCE AND GET THIS THING ON TRACK.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH. THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS,
MR. ACOSTA. >> WELCOME TO THE NEXT SPEAKER
. >> HELLO, PRESIDENT MANDOLIN
BOARD OF SUPERVISORS. MADAM CLERK.
ON FOUR DECEMBER 24TH SOME CITY GENERATED SOME PAPERWORK
AGAINST ME THE NEXT DAY ON THE FIFTH.
I TRIED TO GET THIS CLARIFIED AND CLEARED UP AND RESOLVED.
I WAS TOLD TO GO AWAY. >> FIVE DEPUTIES WERE SUMMONED
. MOVING ON.
OVER THE NEXT 13 MONTHS I WOULD CONTINUE TO TRY TO GET THIS
ISSUE RESOLVED. I REACHED OUT TO CITY
ATTORNEY'S OFFICE. >> THERE'S ONE.
TWO MAYORS THE OUTGOING THE INCOMING THREE LIBRARY
COMMISSIONERS AND FOUR SUPERVISORS.
>> I RECEIVED NO RELIEF. >> NOT AN INTERESTED EAR.
>> WAS REJECTED BY ALL. >> YOU'LL NOTICE THAT OF THE
FOUR THAT I JUST MENTIONED FOUR GROUPS THREE ARE ELECTED
OFFICIALS. MOVING ON.
SO OCTOBER MORE RECENTLY LAST YEAR, OCTOBER 31ST PRESIDENT
MENEM AND ONE OF YOUR STAFFERS ASSISTED ME BY REACHING OUT.
>> SIR, CAN YOU HELP ME AS A WHOLE?
THIS IS NOT A MEETING BETWEEN YOU AND THE BOARD PRESIDENT.
THIS IS A MEETING OF THE BOARD TO ADDRESS THE BOARD AS A
WHOLE. >> I JUST WANT TO SPECIFY THAT
ONE OF YOUR STAFFERS ASSISTED ME BY REACHING OUT TO TRY TO
HELP RESOLVE THIS ISSUE. THIS IS ON THE 31ST OF OCTOBER.
>> I TOOK THREE PAGES OF NOTES. WENT OUT OF TOWN FOR TWO
MONTHS, CAME BACK JANUARY. >> WHEN I RE CONNECTED WITH
THIS PERSON THEY SAID NO, I NEVER SPOKE TO THE PERSON AT
THE LIBRARY. >> WE NEVER THANK YOU FOR YOUR
COMMENTS. >> I'M BACK.
THANK YOU, SIR. THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
CAN WE HEAR FROM THE NEXT SPEAKER PLEASE?
WELCOME. >> HI.
MY NAME IS ROSHI AGHA. AS AN IRANIAN-AMERICAN
COMMUNITY MEMBER, I'M HERE TO THANK SUPERVISOR MATT DORSEY
AND HIS TEAM FOR SPONSORING THE IRANIAN AMERICAN HERITAGE MONTH
RECOGNITION. >> I ARRIVED IN SAN FRANCISCO
IN SEPTEMBER OF 1977 AS A 17 YEAR OLD STUDENT TO GO TO
SCHOOL AND WHAT 50 YEARS LATER ALMOST I'M FLABBERGASTED THAT
WE'RE GETTING THIS RECOGNITION HERE.
THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR ALL YOUR WORK.
THANK YOU. MAHNAZ, FOR ALL YOUR HELP
AND MY SO WHEN MASA APPROACHED ME A COUPLE OF YEARS AGO WITH
THIS IDEA I SAID JUST YEAH WOULD SIGN ME UP.
>> I'M HERE TO HELP. AND AGAIN, THANK YOU SO MUCH TO
THE BOARD AND ESPECIALLY TO THIS SUPERVISOR MATT DORSEY.
THANK YOU. THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
JUST REMIND YOU TO HOLD YOUR APPLAUSE IF YOU DO ABSOLUTELY
NEED TO SHOW SUPPORT. >> JUST WAVE YOUR HANDS LIKE
THAT. THE BOARD MEMBERS WILL SEE YOU.
>> WELCOME TO THE NEXT SPEAKER .
>> GOOD EVENING. BOARD PRESIDENT MANAGEMENT
AND BOARD OF SUPERVISORS. MY NAME IS RICHARD SD PETERSON.
I'M GOING TO BE REALLY QUICK. I HAVE TWO QUICK ISSUES.
ONE I'VE BEEN ASKED IN MY DISTRICT TO RUN WHICH IS
DISTRICT EIGHT TO RUN AS A BOARD OF SUPERVISOR AND I SAID
NO, I'M TOO OLD. I'M A YEAR YOUNGER THAN THAT
THAN BERNIE SANDERS BUT I'M STILL A LITTLE TOO OLD BUT I'M
LOOKING FOR IS A YOUNG COUPLE IN DISTRICT EIGHT THAT HAS
CHILDREN AND OR A CHILD AND THE SAN FRANCISCO DISTRICT SCHOOLS.
THAT'S WHAT WE WANT IN OUR DISTRICT AT THIS PARTICULAR
TIME. SECOND ISSUE AS YOU KNOW I HAVE
ALWAYS BEEN AGAINST PARCEL TAXES BUT I'M COMING AROUND I
THINK FAIR PARCEL TAXES ARE GOING TO BE NEEDED TO SAVE THE
MUNI. MUNI IS A LIFELINE FOR SAN
FRANCISCO WHEN THE MUNI GOES DOWN THIS TOWN IS GOING TO GO
DOWN. NOBODY IS GOING TO BE ABLE TO
GET ANYWHERE. I RIDE THE MUNI MAYBE EVERY
SINGLE DAY. MAYBE EVERY OTHER DAY BUT IT'S
INDISPENSABLE TO MYSELF TO MANY OTHER ELDERS THAT DON'T DRIVE
AND TOO MANY YOUNG PEOPLE WHO REQUIRE WORK TO GET AROUND TOWN
TO GET TO SCHOOL OR TO GET WHERE THEY NEED TO GO.
THANK YOU. >> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
WELCOME TO THE NEXT SPEAKER. GOOD AFTERNOON.
MY NAME IS PORNOGRAPHIC ARIANNA AND I'M A RESIDENT OF DISTRICT
SIX AND I AM A PROUD SAN FRANCISCAN.
WE ALL HAVE MOST AMERICANS HAVE AN IMMIGRATION STORY AND MINE
BEGAN IN 1960 NOT THAT I CAME MY UNCLE CAME HERE IN SAN
FRANCISCO IN 1960 WHICH MADE ME HAVE A LUSTFUL PATH TO BEING A
RESIDENT OF THIS CITY. SO I'M HERE IN SUPPORT OF ITEM
24 AND I WANT TO THANK MS. IKIMI AND EVERYONE ELSE THAT
HAS WORKED HARD TO BRING THIS BRING THIS TO THIS DAY FOR A
VOTE. SO I WOULD LIKE TO THANK YOU
GUYS FOR DOING THAT AND I ALSO THINK THIS CITY FOR ALWAYS
BEING A VOICE FOR THOSE THAT DON'T HAVE VOICE ELSEWHERE,
ESPECIALLY AT THIS VERY EMOTIONAL MOMENT FOR ALL
IRANIAN-AMERICANS. >> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS TO EVERYONE.
>> APPLAUSE IN THE CHAMBER. JUST REMEMBER NO AUDIBLE SOUNDS
IF YOU WOULDN'T MIND, JUST WAVE YOUR HANDS IN THE AIR AND THE
BOARD MEMBERS WILL SEE THAT THAT YOU SUPPORT THAT.
>> WELCOME TO OUR NEXT SPEAKER. OKAY.
THANK YOU. OUR MAYORS APPROACH TO PUBLIC
SAFETY IS IN ITSELF A PUBLIC SAFETY THREAT.
AS WE SAW LAST THURSDAY ON MARCH 5TH FOR $1 A YEAR OUR
MAYOR DANIEL LURIE, A WEALTHY WHITE MAN AND HEIR TO THE
LEVI'S FORTUNE GOT IN THE SUV WITH HIS SPEEDY BODYGUARDS
AND WENT TO THE TENDERLOIN. AND HE CAME OUT AND TOLD A
STORY ABOUT BEING ATTACKED BY MEN BLOCKING THE ROAD AND OF
BEING ATTACKED. >> THAT'S THE NARRATIVE OF WHAT
WENT NATIONWIDE WITH A BLACK MAN'S NAME AND PHOTO ALONG WITH
THAT STORY. WE LATER LEARNED THAT IT WAS
SFPD WHO ESCALATED WITH A PHYSICAL ASSAULT AND THE VIDEO
IS JUST IT'S HORRIBLE. >> THIS ALL SPEAKS TO OUR
MAYORS APPROACH TO PUBLIC SAFETY BULLYING, COERCION,
LYING AND VIOLENCE. HE GOES INTO THESE AREAS
AND DOES HIS OWN VIGILANTE. DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WORKS
SWEEPS. WHAT DOES HE ACTUALLY DO TO
HELP THESE PEOPLE THAT HE ENCOUNTERS?
OFFER THEM HOUSING, BASIC INCOME?
I DON'T I DON'T KNOW. YOU CAN TELL US.
I DON'T KNOW IF HE TAKES INTO ACCOUNT IN THIS PARTICULAR
SITUATION LAST WEEK THE DISTRESS AND DISCRIMINATION OF
BEING BLACK IN AMERICA, IN SAN FRANCISCO AND HOW THIS STORY
WOULD NEGATIVELY IMPACT AND STIGMATIZE THIS MAN
PROBABLY FOR THE REST OF HIS LIFE.
>> HE NEEDS TO HELP THIS MAN WHO HE HAS HURT.
>> THIS STORY ALSO CONVENIENTLY OVERSHADOWED ANOTHER STORY THAT
BROKE EARLIER THAT DAY WHERE THE FORMER DHS SECRETARY OF
HOMELAND SECURITY KRISTI NOEM CLAIMED TO HAVE CONVERSATIONS
WITH LURIE AND PRAISED HIS COOPERATIVELY.
THIS ATTACK HAS OVERTAKEN THIS ICE STORY STORY AND ALSO
EARLIER LAST WEEK A MOTHER OF TWO, ONE OF WHICH WAS A YOUNG
LITTLE KID WHO'S DEAF WAS ABDUCTED IN SOMA SAN FRANCISCO
DISAPPEARED AND DEPORTED FROM THE BAY AREA.
IT'S NO LONGER IN THE COUNTRY. HOW MANY ICE ABDUCTIONS ARE
PERMISSIBLE IN SAN FRANCISCO? I WOULD LIKE A CAP ACTUALLY.
CAN YOU GIVE ME A CAP ON HOW MANY ABDUCTIONS ARE ALLOWED
IN THE CITY? OUR MAYOR HAS A LOT TO ANSWER
FOR AND HIS SILENCE IS DAMNING .
>> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. WELCOME OUR NEXT SPEAKER.
I JUST HAD TO COME UP HERE AT THAT LADY TALK ABOUT THE MAYOR.
>> I CAME UP HERE TO TALK ABOUT LEE HILL HOODS BUT JUST
COMMENTED ON OUR MAYOR WHO REALLY DON'T CARE ABOUT US
BLACKS AT THAT PARTICULAR DAY AND IT'S GOING TO TAKE UP SOME
OF MY TIME. I ASKED A MAYOR.
CAN I TALK TO YOU THIS DAY? HE GOT US THE SECURITY GUYS GOT
JUMPED. HE CAME DOWNSTAIRS.
HE WOULDN'T SAY NOTHING TO ME. EVEN TODAY WHEN HE LEFT HE
WOULDN'T SAY NOTHING TO ME. THIS MAYOR DON'T CARE NOTHING
ABOUT THE FILLMORE OR THE BLACK COMMUNITY ANYWAY.
>> I'M HERE TO TALK ABOUT L.A. HEAL HUTCH COMMUNITY CENTER.
Y'ALL ALL BETTER PAY ATTENTION. PARTICULARLY MY SUPERVISOR
ELIHU HUTCHINS GETTING READY TO CLOSE DOWN AT THE YEARS OF
BEING A HUB FOR THE BLACK COMMUNITY BECAUSE OF THIS
ROGUISH COMMUNITY OF WHATEVER THEY CALL.
>> BUT WE ARE PUTTING TOGETHER A COMMITTEE THAT'S GOING TO BE
SELECTING A COMMITTEE OF A BOARD OF DIRECTORS AND A SELECT
BOARD. AND I WANT TO WORK WITH THE
CITY AS A CONDUIT TO HELP THIS COMMUNITY SOON TO COME BACK
TOGETHER. MY NAME IS ACE.
I'M ON THE CASE AND WE GOT TWO OTHER BROTHERS WHO'S GOING TO
TALK TO YOU ABOUT ALI HE'LL HUTCH.
SO YOU PAY ATTENTION, MR. SUPERVISOR, BECAUSE YOU DON'T
KNOW TOO MUCH ABOUT HILL HUTCH. >> WE ARE THE ONES THAT KNOW OF
HISTORY OF LEE HILL HUTCH COMMUNITY CENTER.
>> AND WE DON'T WANT THIS MAYOR COMING DOWN HERE CLOSING
THE DOORS ON LEE HILL HUTCH. >> THAT IS OUR CENTER.
JUST BECAUSE SOME ROGUISH PEOPLE TOOK ON IT BEFORE.
THAT IS OUR CENTER. WE TOOK IT BEFORE.
>> AND WE GOING TO TAKE IT BACK AGAIN.
MY NAME IS ACE. AND I AM THE FILLMORE CORRIDOR
AMBASSADOR AND THE CITY AND THE MAYOR BETTER PUT SOME RESPECT
ON THAT NAME. >> I'VE BEEN DOING POLITICS
PROBABLY WHEN HE WAS A KID. HE'S YOUNG ENOUGH TO BE MY SON.
. MY NAME IS ACE Y'ALL.
>> AND I'M ON THE CASE. THE FILLMORE CORDOVA IN BARSTOW
ARE THANK YOU, MR. WASHINGTON. >> WELCOME TO OUR NEXT SPEAKER
. PLEASE FIX WALK AWAY.
COME ON UP. DON'T BE SCARED.
>> THANK YOU, SUPERVISORS. FIRST THING IS, YOU KNOW AS I
KEEP SAYING TO OUR SUPERVISOR, IT'S BEEN 50, 60 YEARS.
YOU DON'T FALL ON HIS LAP. IT FALLS ON HIS LAP RIGHT NOW.
BUT WE REALLY NEED HELP IN THE FILLMORE AND I KNOW THAT WE
HAVE THIS NEW ACTION COMMITTEE BUT IT'S TIME FOR THESE ACTION
COMMITTEES TIME OUT FOR ALL THIS STUFF.
AND I'M REALLY HERE TODAY TO ACKNOWLEDGE AS YOU RECOGNIZE
WOMEN'S HISTORY MONTH AND I TOLD MYSELF ABOUT THIS THE
OTHER DAY IT'S A SHAME, COLLEAGUES THAT YOU LET YOUR
COLLEAGUES BUILDING ELIHU HUTCH AS WOMAN BLACK FIRST WOMAN
SUPERVISOR. HER BUILDING IS DETERIORATING
RIGHT AS THE FIRST BLACK SUPERVISOR I THINK ALL OF YOU
GUYS THAT ARE HERE NOW TO STAND ON THE PRINCIPLE OF DOING
SOMETHING ABOUT THAT BUILDING RIGHT THERE THE LETTERS ARE
FALLING OFF THE BUILDING. >> YOU GOT THE FROM THE OUTSIDE
YOU KNOW THE WALLS ARE BREAKING DOWN.
THE INSIDE IS LEAKING. YOU KNOW, I REALLY THINK THAT
WE NEED TO FAST FORWARD WHAT WE'RE DOING AS WE REBUILD SAN
FRANCISCO. RIGHT.
YOU'RE REBUILDING SAN CISCO BUT YOU'RE FORGETTING ABOUT THE
NEIGHBORHOOD THAT WAS FIRST DESTROYED, THE FIRST REMOVAL
RIGHT IN HISTORY REDLINING. RIGHT.
AND NOW WE COME WITH THIS THESE GRANTS AND THINGS TO REBUILD
BUT IT'S TIME OFF ALL THAT STUFF.
HOW COULD YOU GIVE ME A GRANT NOW TO MOVE IN A SPACE AT THE
RATE THAT IT IS NOW AND NOT AT THE RATE THAT YOU TOOK IT FROM
ME WHEN YOU READ LIKE MY DISTRICT MY GRANDMOTHER, YOUR
GRANDFATHER'S YOU YOU CAN'T MATCH UP TO THAT RIGHT NOW.
SO THAT'S A LOT THAT NEEDS TO BE DONE AND I DON'T THINK THIS
COMMITTEE THAT IS FORMED THIS I HOPE DEPARTMENT THERE'S ALL
THESE PLANNING DEPARTMENT I DON'T THINK IT'S GOING TO WORK
UNTIL WE REALLY GET SOME REAL DOWN SOLUTIONS.
BUT THE FIRST THING I'M HERE TO SAY IS PLEASE AND I AIN'T I
DON'T REALLY BEING NOBODY HERE BUT I MAY ACTUALLY DO SOMETHING
ABOUT YOUR COLLEAGUES BUILDING REALLY DO SOMETHING ABOUT YOUR
COLLEAGUES BUILDING. >> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
WELCOME TO THE NEXT SPEAKER IS HELLO PRESIDENT AND COMMISSION
I MEAN SUPERVISORS MY NAME IS RANDALL EVANS I CONSIDER MYSELF
A PUBLIC SPEAKER BUT I COULDN'T DO THIS IF I WANTED TO TO SPEAK
IN THREE MINUTES WOULD NEED TO BE SAID.
>> FIRST OF ALL IT WAS 4700 BLACK PEOPLE WAS JUST ERASED
FROM THE FILLMORE AREA. THEY CAME DOWN AND TOOK 883
BLACK BUSINESSES OUT OF THE FILLMORE AREA.
THEY KNOCKED DOWN 2500 VICTORIAN HOUSES
SIMULTANEOUSLY. >> THE CITY WAS GIVEN $50
MILLION TO DO SOMETHING ABOUT RE DEVELOPMENT OF THAT AREA
INSTEAD OF REDEVELOPMENT. I HAVE TO ADMIT THAT IT HAD TO
BE A PLAN. >> YOU LISTEN TO ALL THE
STORIES THAT WAS TOLD TODAY AND ALL THE AWARDS YOU GAVE OUT
TODAY TO ALL THE PEOPLE THEY'VE DONE ALL THE GREAT THINGS TO
YOUR KNOWLEDGE MEN AND YOU CAN EVEN STAND UP TO SAY ANYTHING
ABOUT THE WEST EDITION OF BLACK BEAUTIFUL WOMEN THAT WAS THERE
DOING THE THINGS AND BUT WHAT THEY BUSTLE TO TRY TO SAVE YOU
LIKE THE COLLINS THE WAY YOU PAY FOR ALL THE CANE IS OH
THERE'S A LIST OF THEM YOU KNOW I HAVE A PHOTOGRAPHIC MEMORY
ABOUT MOST OF THE HISTORY THAT TOOK PLACE IN THE FILLMORE
WITHOUT A RENEWAL AND SOME BLACKS WOULD CALL IT REMOVAL
RIGHT NOW IS UNDER A STATE OF EMERGENCY.
WE ARE REACHING ACROSS THE COMMUNITY ALL THE WAY TO
BAYVIEW HUNTERS POINT TO GET AS MANY PEOPLE AS POSSIBLE
INVOLVED IN SOME TO A LIST OF TOWN HALLS THAT WE'RE GOING TO
BE HAVING HERE RULES APPOINT TO TRY TO SAVE LEO THIS COMMUNITY
CENTER. WE NOT ONLY WANT TO JUST SAVE
IT, WE WANT TO REDEVELOP IT AND WE WANT TO REDEVELOP THE
WHOLE SQUARE BLOCK WE'RE GOING TO BE COMING DOWN HERE
AND LOADS TO GET YOUR SUPPORT AND YOUR UNDERSTANDING IS VERY
IMPORTANT THAT YOU RESPECT THE HISTORY OF THE FILLMORE AREA.
IT WAS THE GENTLEMAN BEHIND ME IN FRONT OF ME WAS MAKING THE
POINT THAT THE RED LINE THE AREA IT WAS A PLAN TO JUST MAKE
US DISAPPEAR AND IT'S NOT FAIR AT THIS POINT WE NEED A LOT
THANK YOU SIR, FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
THANK YOU. >> LET'S WELCOME OUR NEXT
SPEAKER. HELLO SUPERVISORS.
I'M TERESA DE LA LA WITH SO I'M KEN AND I'M ALSO A RESIDENT OF
SAN FRANCISCO COMMUNITY LAND TRUST AND DISTRICT SIX.
>> I'M HERE TO TALK AGAINST PROP II REPEAL THIS PROPOSAL
YOU KNOW TO REPEAL PROP II IS DEEPLY TROUBLING TO US BECAUSE
THIS IS A VOTER MANDATED FUNDING THAT SUPPORTS HOUSING
STABILITY PROGRAMS IN SAN FRANCISCO WHEN WE TALK ABOUT
REPEALING IT, WE'RE TALKING ABOUT CUTTING FUNDING THAT
DIRECTLY SUPPORTS THE EMERGENCY RENTAL ASSISTANCE SMALL SITES
ACQUISITION, AFFORDABLE HOUSING PRESERVATION AND THESE ARE ALL
THE TENANTS STABILITY PROGRAMS .
THESE PROGRAMS ARE NOT JUST THEORETICAL, THEY ARE
LIFELINES. >> ORGANIZATIONS LIKE SOM CAN
THE FCC, BISHOP WESTBY AND ALL THE OTHER AUTHORITIES YOU KNOW,
WORK WORK WITH RESIDENTS EVERY SINGLE DAY WHO ARE TRYING TO
STAY HOUSED AND WE'RE TRYING TO LIVE PEOPLE COME TO US WHEN
THEY'RE SCARED, WHEN THEY'RE FACING EVICTION, WHEN THEY
DON'T KNOW WHERE THEIR CHILDREN WILL SLEEP.
SO DOES THIS PROPOSAL FULLY ACCOUNT FOR HOW MANY PEOPLE
WILL BE DIRECTLY AFFECTED BY REMOVING THIS FUNDING BECAUSE
CUTTING HOUSING STABILITY PROGRAMS DOES NOT SOLVE THE
HOUSING CRISIS. >> IT DECREASES IT INCREASES
DISPLACEMENT, IT INCREASES HOMELESSNESS AND IT WIDENS THE
ECONOMIC DIVIDE IN OUR CITY. >> WE ALSO HAVE TO BE HONEST
WITH OURSELVES ARE WE EVEN MEETING THE STATE'S HOUSING
ELEMENT GOAL HOUSING GOALS PLAN THE ANSWER IS A BIG FAT NO.
YOU CANNOT BUILD THE AFFORDABLE HOUSING BY CUTTING THE FUNDING
THAT MAKES IT POSSIBLE. >> SAN FRANCISCO MUST REMAIN A
CITY FOR WORKING FAMILIES, SENIORS, IMMIGRANTS AND LONG
TIME RESIDENTS NOT JUST FOR THOSE WHO CAN AFFORD RISING
HOUSING COSTS. >> WE DO NOT WANT TO GIVE THE
MAYOR MORE POWER TO DESTROY OUR CITY.
WE RESPECTFULLY URGE THIS BOARD PLEASE THANK YOU FOR YOUR
COMMENTS. >> LET'S WELCOME OUR NEXT
SPEAKER. GOOD AFTERNOON, MADAM CLERK.
PRESIDENT MENDELSOHN AND MEMBERS OF THE BOARD OF
SUPERVISORS. >> MY NAME IS KYLE SMILLIE.
I'M THE POLICY DIRECTOR FOR THE SAN FRANCISCO COMMUNITY LAND
TRUST. I'M HERE TO SPEAK IN OPPOSITION
TO THE PROPOSAL TO CUT TAXES ON BILLIONAIRES WHO TRADE
BUILDINGS WORTH $10 MILLION OR MORE.
>> I'VE HEARD IN THE CASE TO CUT PROP THAT IT HAS FAILED TO
LIVE UP TO ITS PROMISE THAT IS NOT ACCURATE.
IN THE FIRST TWO YEARS THAT PROP II WAS IN EFFECT THIS
BOARD WISELY ALLOCATED MORE THAN $200 MILLION TO THE
INTENDED AFFORDABLE HOUSING PURPOSES THAT PROP I WAS MADE
FOR INCLUDING RENT RELIEF, HOUSING PRESERVATION AND LAND
BANKING. I WOULD ASK ANYONE WHO CLAIMS
THAT PROP EIGHT HAS FAILED TO TELL ONE OF THE 20,000 SAN
FRANCISCANS WHOSE HOMES WERE SAVED FROM EVICTION BECAUSE OF
PROP EIGHT BECAUSE WE STOOD UP THE MOST ROBUST RENT RELIEF
COVID PROGRAM IN THE COUNTRY TELL THEM THAT IT FAILED UNTIL
THE HUNDREDS OF PEOPLE WHOSE HOMES WERE TAKEN OFF THE
PRIVATE SPECULATIVE MARKET AND TURN INTO PERMANENTLY
AFFORDABLE HOUSING THAT PROP EIGHT HAS FAILED.
ASK THE HUNDREDS OF SAN FRANCISCANS WHOSE 100%
AFFORDABLE HOUSING IS BEING CONSTRUCTED RIGHT NOW BECAUSE
OF PROP. I TELL THEM THAT IT FAILED PROP
AI HAS AND SHOULD CONTINUE TO WORK THE CONVERSATION RIGHT NOW
SHOULD BE TO HOW WE SPEND PROP $8 TO ADDRESS THE AFFORDABILITY
CRISIS INSTEAD AT A TIME WHEN RENTS ARE RISING FASTER THAN
ANY CITY IN THE COUNTRY, EVICTIONS ARE AT AN ALL TIME
HIGH AND GROCERIES, GAS AND BASIC GOODS ARE
UNAFFORDABLE TO WORKING PEOPLE. THE POLICY PRESCRIPTION FROM
THIS BOARD OF SUPERVISORS IS TO CUT TAXES ON BILLIONAIRES.
THAT MAKES NO SENSE AND WE WILL FIGHT THIS EVERY STEP OF THE
WAY. THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU, KYLE. THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
WELCOME. AFTERNOON SUPERVISORS.
MY NAME IS CHRISTIAN CASSIUS. I AM A RESIDENT IN THE LOWER
HAIGHT AND A PROUD DEMOCRATIC SOCIALIST.
>> I'M HERE TO DEMAND THAT YOU OPPOSE THE REPEALING OF PROP I
TO SPEAK SPECIFICALLY TO PROP EIGHT AS ACCOMPLISHMENTS IT HAS
HELPED FUND THE STRONGEST COVID RENT RELIEF PROGRAM IN THE
COUNTRY AND MADE SURE THAT MORE THAN 20,000 SAN FRANCISCANS
WERE SAVED FROM EVICTION. >> AND THESE ARE THE SAME
PEOPLE WHO ARE WHO WOULD BE AT RISK OF HOMELESSNESS THAT THE
RICH TECHIES THAT WOULD BENEFIT FROM THE REPEALING OF US FROM
THIS PROPOSITION WOULD DON'T WANT TO SEE ON THEIR STREETS.
AND IN REALITY IF YOU DON'T WANT TO SEE HOMELESS PEOPLE ON
YOUR STREETS YOU SHOULD HOUSE THEM IF YOU WANT TO ENSURE THAT
THE PEOPLE THE WEALTHY PEOPLE WHO CALL THIS PLACE HOME WHO DO
NOT GIVE THEIR FAIR SHARE TO THE CITY AND ITS RESIDENTS ARE
HAPPY MAKE SURE THAT THE PEOPLE THAT THEY'RE STEPPING OVER HAVE
SOMEWHERE TO LIVE. IN ADDITION, IT HAS HELPED FUND
$40 MILLION FOR LAND BAKING WHICH HAS BEEN USED FOR MORE
THAN 550 AFFORDABLE HOMES AND $64 MILLION FOR A HOUSING
ACQUISITION THAT HAS TAKEN HUNDREDS OF HOMES OFF THE
PRIVATE SPECULATIVE MARKET. WE NEED AFFORDABLE HOUSING.
WE DO NOT NEED MARTHA RAYE OR ABOVE HOUSING FOR PEOPLE LIKE
ME WHO ARE FROM THE BAY AREA OUR ENTIRE LIVES WHO MOVED HERE
DURING SCHOOL TO SAN FRANCISCO SPECIFICALLY AND THEN HAVE
STAYED HERE. >> IT'S HARD TO FIND HOUSING
THAT IS AFFORDABLE. I WANT TO STAY WHERE I LIVE BUT
IF FOR WHATEVER REASON SOCIAL HOUSING GOES AWAY AND OUR
PRICES CONTINUE TO INCREASE THAT WOULD MAKE IT SO MUCH
HARDER. SO I'M ASKING ALL OF YOU I AM
ASKING MY SUPERVISOR BELOW MY GOOD TO MAKE SURE YOU OPPOSE
THE REPEALING OF PROP. >> I THANK YOU FOR YOUR
COMMENTS. WELCOME TO THE NEXT SPEAKER.
GOOD AFTERNOON MISS ALEPPO ELLIPTICAL I'M AN ARTIST
AND SOMEONE WHO'S BORN AND RAISED HERE IN THE BAY AREA
SPEAKING TO ITEM 24 I JUST WANTED TO EXPRESS MY GRATITUDE
FOR THIS BEING CONSIDERED. THIS KIND OF FORMAL RECOGNITION
MEANS A LOT FOR MY COMMUNITY SO THANK YOU SOCIALLY DURING THIS
TIME. THANKS.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. >> WELCOME TO OUR NEXT SPEAKER.
HI, MY NAME IS MIKE HEISLER. I AM HERE ON BEHALF OF THE SAN
FRANCISCO ANTI DISPLACEMENT COALITION TO ECHO SOME OF THE
EARLIER COMMENTS AND URGE YOU TO OPPOSE MAYOR LURIE
AND SUPERVISOR MAHMUD'S REPEAL OF THE REAL ESTATE TRANSFER TAX
PROP BY CALLING THIS POLICY A HOUSING SOLUTION IGNORES THE
REALITY THAT IT PRIMARILY BENEFITS LARGE SCALE REAL
ESTATE INVESTORS NOT THE TENANTS WHO MAKE UP THE
MAJORITY OF THE CITY. >> COMMERCIAL TRANSACTIONS NOT
HOUSING HAVE GENERATED THE MAJORITY OF NEARLY HALF $1
BILLION PROP II HAS RAISED. >> THIS IS NOT ABOUT UNLOCKING
HOUSING. IF WE WERE INTERESTED IN THAT
WE WOULD ENDEAVOR TO RAISE NEW REVENUE FOR THE MORE THAN
17,000 UNITS OF AFFORDABLE HOUSING THAT ARE READY TO BE
BUILT BUT LACK THE FUNDING MEETING THE URGENT NEEDS OF
TENANTS ACROSS THE CITY REQUIRES SIGNIFICANT PUBLIC
INVESTMENT IN ELIMINATING HUNDREDS OF MILLIONS OF DOLLARS
IN REVENUE WILL ONLY MAKE THOSE HOMES HARDER TO BUILD.
>> THANKS. THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
>> WELCOME TO OUR NEXT SPEAKER. GOOD AFTERNOON.
I WANT TO START I HAVE A HEAVY HEART.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND WHY THE COUNTRY CAN FIND SO MUCH MONEY
TO BOMB IRAN BUT WE CAN'T FIND MONEY TO BUILD HOUSING AND THAT
JUST A FEW INFURIATES ME AND I'M SPEAKING AGAINST THE
REPEAL OF PROP I. I WANT TO SAY I'M A RETIRED
TEACHER. WHEN I STARTED TEACHING I COULD
RENT A FLAT IN SEACLIFF FOR $600 A MONTH A FLAT BY MYSELF.
>> I COULD SAVE UP MY MONEY BY CUTTING OUT MY LATTES
AND CRESCENT. AND I BOUGHT A HOUSE IN BERNAL
HEIGHTS WITH THE HELP OF MY MOTHER.
NOT A LOT OF HELP BUT A BETTER HELP.
AND THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE TODAY. THERE IS NO TEACHER THAT CAN
AFFORD TO BUY OR EVEN RENT IN SAN FRANCISCO AT MARKET
RATES RIGHT NOW. THIS IS ABSURD.
AND IT'S NOT AND TEACHERS ARE AMONG THE BETTER OFF PEOPLE
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT OUR SERVICE WORKERS AND PEOPLE WHO MAKE
THIS CITY RUN. THEY CAN'T AFFORD TO LIVE HERE
. AND WE'RE GOING TO CUT THE
TAXES ON THE RICHEST SEVEN SISKIND SO THAT THEY CAN GET
MORE MONEY. >> IT'S RIDICULOUS.
YOU KNOW, MAYOR LURIE LURIE'S HOUSE IS WORTH $16.5 MILLION.
MY HOUSE AFTER MANY YEARS OF APPRECIATING IS WORTH MAYBE A
MILLION A MILLION AND A HALF. AND I KNOW I COULD GIVE A IF I
HAVE TO PAY EXTRA TAXES WHEN I SELL IT.
IF THAT PUTS PEOPLE IN HOUSING THEN WE SHOULD DO IT.
AND I THINK THAT THAT THIS THE SUPERVISORS AND THE MAYOR HAVE
TO REALLY THINK ABOUT WHAT'S GOING WRONG IN THIS CITY
BECAUSE THAT'S WHAT'S GOING WRONG.
>> AND THERE SHOULD BE NO TAX CUTS FOR MILLIONAIRES OR
BILLIONAIRES. THERE SHOULD BE NO TAX CUTS.
THEY SHOULD PAY MORE TAXES AND WE SHOULD BUILD MORE
HOUSING. >> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
WELCOME TO OUR NEXT SPEAKER. >> GOOD AFTERNOON.
BOARD OF SUPERVISORS. >> MY NAME IS RASHAD.
I'M A RESIDENT OF DISTRICT NINE AND THE MISSION.
AND I'M SPEAKING TODAY TO URGE YOU TO REJECT THE BILL TO ACT
AND TO OPPOSE ANY EFFORT TO REPEAL PROP I THE 2020 REAL
ESTATE TRANSFER TAX PASSED BY VOTERS.
>> SAN FRANCISCANS HAVE BEEN CLEAR ABOUT WHAT THEY WANT.
WE PASSED PROP K AFFIRMING OUR COMMITMENT TO SOCIAL HOUSING.
>> WE PASSED PROP EIGHT TO MAKE WEALTHY REAL ESTATE SPECULATORS
PAY THEIR FAIR SHARE. OVERTURNING THESE DEMOCRATIC
MANDATES AT THE BEHEST OF WEALTHY DONORS AND REAL ESTATE
INTERESTS IS A BETRAYAL OF THE VOTERS THIS BOARD IS SUPPOSED
TO REPRESENT. >> EVICTIONS ARE AT THEIR
HIGHEST LEVEL IN A DECADE. >> RENTS CONTINUE TO CLIMB
BEYOND WHAT MOST WORKING SAN FRANCISCANS CAN AFFORD.
MEANWHILE, THE REPEAL OF PROP EIGHT WOULD DELIVER A DIRECT
TAX WINDFALL TO THE VERY REAL ESTATE SPECULATORS DRIVING
THOSE EVICTIONS. >> THESE SAME SPECULATORS HAVE
ALREADY SEEN THEIR FEDERAL TAX BURDEN REDUCED SIGNIFICANTLY
UNDER THE TRUMP ADMINISTRATION .
>> THEY DO NOT NEED FURTHER RELIEF FROM THIS BOARD.
THE CLAIM THAT THE TRANSFER TAX SUPPRESSES HOUSING CONSTRUCTION
DOES NOT HOLD UP UNDER SCRUTINY .
THE VAST MAJORITY OF PROP I REVENUES COME FROM SALES OF
MAJOR EXISTING COMMERCIAL PROPERTIES SUCH AS PGE AND IS
SALE OF ITS $800 MILLION HEADQUARTERS IN 2021.
NOT FROM HOUSING TRANSACTIONS. >> GUTTING THIS REVENUE STREAM
DOES NOTHING TO BUILD HOUSING. IT SIMPLY PROTECTS THE PROFITS
OF LARGE PROPERTY HOLDERS. THE REAL OBSTACLE TO AFFORDABLE
HOUSING IS FUNDING AND PROP EIGHT PROVIDES IT.
>> WE JUST WATCHED 365 UNITS OF AFFORDABLE HOUSING DISAPPEAR
FROM THE POTRERO YARD MODERNIZATION PROJECT DUE TO
LACK OF FUNDS. THAT IS THE HOUSING CRISIS
IN CONCRETE TERMS. >> PROP EIGHT IS ONE OF THE FEW
TOOLS WE HAVE TO ADDRESS IT. >> SINCE ITS PASSAGE PROPER HAS
DELIVERED SO MUCH INCLUDING THE STRONGEST RENT RELIEF PROGRAM
THAT HAS PROTECTED 20,000 TENANTS FROM EVICTION.
>> LAND BANKING AND HOUSING ARE ACQUISITION TO KEEP HOMES OFF
THE SPECULATIVE MARKET. THESE ARE REAL RESULTS FOR REAL
FAMILIES. >> THE ROOT OF OUR HOUSING
CRISIS IS THE TREATMENT OF HOUSING AS A FINANCIAL ASSET
RATHER THAN A HUMAN NEED. >> THE BUILD ACT AND THE REPEAL
OF PROP EIGHT WOULD DEEPEN THIS PROBLEM NOT SOLVE IT.
>> I URGE YOU TO STAND WITH SAN FRANCISCO VOTERS REJECT THE
BUILD OR REJECT THE BUILD ACT PRESERVE PROP II.
>> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. >> WELCOME.
SUPERVISORS MY NAME IS HONEST CHARLIE BODKIN.
I'M THE PRESIDENT OF THE DISTRICT FIVE DEMOCRATIC CLUB
AND CO-FOUNDER OF SAN FRANCISCANS FOR SOCIAL HOUSING
WHO I'M REPRESENTING TODAY. OVER 1000 SAN FRANCISCANS FOR
SOCIAL HOUSING HAVE SIGNED OUR PETITION CALLING ON THIS BOARD
TO PASS ANOTHER RESOLUTION OF INTENT TO SPEND PROPERTY
TRANSFER TAX REVENUE ON SOCIAL HOUSING.
LAST WEEK I READ SOME OF THEIR NAMES.
SINCE THEN HUNDREDS HAVE SENT LETTERS REPEATING OUR
REASONABLE REQUEST. >> THIS WEEK I'D LIKE TO READ
THE NAME NAMES OF SOME DISTINGUISHED AND SAN
FRANCISCANS THAT ACTUALLY VOTED IN 2020 SPECIFICALLY TO CALL ON
THE MAYOR TO SPEND PROP EIGHT FUNDS ON A SOCIAL HOUSING
PROGRAM. THEIR NAMES WERE SANDRA LEE
FEUER, MATT HANEY, GORDON MA, AARON PESKIN.
DEAN PRESTON HILLARY RONEN ASHA SAFAI KATHERINE STEFANI.
NORMAN YEE. SHERMAN WALTON AND RAFAEL
MANDOLIN. THESE NOTABLE SAN FRANCISCANS
THEN SUPERVISORS AND FOR TWO OF YOU CURRENT SUPERVISORS STATED
FIRMLY IN A UNANIMOUS VOTE THAT IT WAS THEIR UNITED INTENT TO
USE THE MONEY FROM PROP II TO FUND A SOCIAL HOUSING PROGRAM.
THE BUILD ACT'S PROMISE IS TO SPEED UP DEVELOPMENT OF NEW
HOUSING. TO WHICH I SAY I'M REASONABLE.
I LOVE TO TALK ABOUT SPEEDING UP NEW HOUSING DEVELOPMENT.
>> LET'S BUILD BABY BUILD. BUT THAT'S NOT WHAT THIS ACT IS
CURRENTLY WRITTEN TO FOCUS ON. THIS ACT APPLIES TO ALL
PROPERTIES NOT JUST NEW DEVELOPMENTS.
THAT MEANS BILLION DOLLAR PROPERTIES LIKE 555 CALIFORNIA
WHICH DONALD TRUMP IS A CO-OWNER OF WOULD SEE MASSIVE
TAX CUTS IN SALE. UNDER THIS ACT THE CO-OWNER OF
THAT BUILDING, STEVEN ROTH TOLD INVESTORS LAST YEAR THAT THE
PROPERTY MIGHT BE FOR SALE AT THE RIGHT DEAL AT THE RIGHT
TIME. THE BUILD ACT WOULD SAVE STEVE
ROTH AND DONALD TRUMP TENS OF MILLIONS OF DOLLARS AND DO
NOTHING TO RESTORE FAITH IN SAN FRANCISCO GOVERNMENT THAT WHEN
IT SAYS IT'S GOING TO DO SOMETHING IT ACTUALLY DOES
SOMETHING. NOW ISN'T THE RIGHT TIME FOR
MASSIVE CUTS ON TAX CUTS ON BILLION DOLLAR PROPERTIES.
>> NOW IS THE TIME TO RESTORE FAITH IN THE WORD OF THE BOARD
OF SUPERVISORS. THANK YOU HONEST FOR YOUR
COMMENTS. WELCOME TO THE NEXT SPEAKER.
>> GOOD AFTERNOON. PRESIDENT MANDOLIN AND BOARD OF
SUPERVISORS SCOTT FEENEY DISTRICT NINE RESIDENT I
ALREADY SHARED WITH YOU MY POSITION ON REPEALING PROP II
LAST WEEK. I'M AGAINST IT.
I THINK YOU SHOULD SPEND THE FUNDS ON SOCIAL HOUSING.
BUT I WANT TO GIVE A LITTLE BIT MORE COLOR ON THAT.
SO IN DECEMBER SO NOW IN JANUARY THERE IS AN ARTICLE
IN THE S.F. STANDARD THAT WAS HEADLINED ONE FOR THE NIMBYS
SUNSET AFFORDABLE HOUSING ON HOLD.
AND IT TALKED ABOUT HOW A PROJECT WITH ALMOST 200 UNITS
OF AFFORDABLE HOUSING IN THE SUNSET 1234 GREAT HIGHWAY WAS
BEING PUT ON HOLD. BUT IT WASN'T BECAUSE OF A
HEIGHT LIMIT. IT WASN'T BECAUSE PERMITS WERE
TAKING TOO LONG. >> IT WASN'T BECAUSE OF
COMPLAINTS OVERSHADOWS ANYTHING LIKE THAT.
THIS PROJECT WAS PUT ON HOLD BECAUSE THERE WERE NO FUNDS FOR
IT. >> IN THIS PARTICULAR CASE THE
FUNDS WERE EXPECTED TO BE WITHHELD BY THE TRUMP
ADMINISTRATION. >> HOWEVER AFFORDABLE HOUSING
PROJECTS AS I'M SURE YOU ALL KNOW, ASSEMBLE FUNDING FROM A
WIDE VARIETY OF SOURCES AND SOME OF THE OTHER FUNDING
THAT WAS MAKING THAT PROJECT POSSIBLE AND MIGHT EVENTUALLY
LEAD TO IT HOPEFULLY GETTING CONSTRUCTED IN THE END IS
COMING FROM PROP II. SO I JUST WANT TO EMPHASIZE
THAT NOT FUNDING AFFORDABLE HOUSING IS A FORM OF NIMBYISM.
IT IS A WAY THAT NIMBYS WIN. >> AND IT IS ESSENTIAL IF YOU
WANT TO BUILD HOUSING IF WE WANT TO HAVE A SAN FRANCISCO
THAT OPENS ITS GOLDEN GATE FOR ALL WE HAVE TO PRESERVE
AND ENHANCE FUNDING FOR AFFORDABLE HOUSING.
PLEASE DON'T REPEAL PROP EIGHT BUT DEDICATED TO SOCIAL HOUSING
AS THE VOTERS INTENDED AS PREVIOUS SPEAKERS HAVE SAID.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH. THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
>> WELCOME TO OUR NEXT SPEAKER .
>> HELLO. MY NAME IS ERIC BRENNER.
I'M A 40 YEAR RESIDENT OF SAN FRANCISCO AND I'M A RETIRED
LIBRARIAN. AND I VOTED IN 2020 ALONG WITH
57.5% OF THE VOTERS FOR PROP I .
>> AND I'VE BEEN OUTRAGED ALMOST EVER SINCE TO SEE THAT
THE MONEY HAS BARELY BEEN SPENT ON AFFORDABLE HOUSING.
>> PEOPLE WHO VOTED FOR THIS I ARE OUTRAGED WHEN I TELL THEM
THAT THEY'RE TALKING ABOUT CUTTING BACK WHAT YOU GUYS
VOTED FOR. AND ANYBODY WHO HEARS ABOUT
THIS THAT I TALKED TO IS ABSOLUTELY OUTRAGED.
AND YOU GUYS SHOULD BE ASHAMED TO BE EVEN CONSIDERING THIS.
WE NEED MUCH MORE AFFORDABLE HOUSING.
AND THIS IS ABSOLUTELY GOING AGAINST THE WILL OF THE VOTERS
. >> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. LET'S WELCOME OUR NEXT SPEAKER
. >> HELLO BOARD.
GOOD AFTERNOON. MY NAME IS DESTINY SANTANA.
>> I'M A RESIDENT OF DISTRICT FIVE.
CAN YOU PULL THAT MICROPHONE DOWN TO YOU?
CLOSE. THANK YOU.
SORRY. IS THIS BETTER?
YES. OKAY.
MY NAME IS DESTINY SANTANA. I'M A DISTRICT OF A NUMBER OF
DISTRICT FIVE. AND I'M HERE TO OPPOSE THE
BUILD ACT LIKE MANY OF THE OTHER RESIDENTS WHO HAVE SPOKEN
BEFORE ME. >> SO I WILL REMIND YOU THAT
TWO WEEKS AGO THE BUDGET AND FINANCE COMMITTEE HEARD
FROM THE MAYOR'S OFFICE ON BUDGET INSTRUCTIONS.
THE MAYOR'S OFFICE OF PUBLIC POLICY AND FINANCE MADE IT
CLEAR THAT CITY SPENDING OUTPACES REVENUE BY A LOT.
>> THE CITY'S DEFICIT THIS YEAR IS 296.3 MILLION BY FISCAL YEAR
2029 TO 2023. THE DEFICIT WILL RISE TO 1.17
BILLION. THESE FIGURES DO NOT REFLECT
THE REDUCTION OF PROPERTY FUNDS THAT WOULD BE LOST BECAUSE THE
BUILD ACT PROBABLY MATTERS TO ME BECAUSE THE REAL ESTATE
TRANSFER TAX IS THE BIGGEST FUNDER OF THE CITY'S GENERAL
FUND AND MAKES SURE THAT EVERYONE PAYS THEIR FAIR SHARE.
LAST YEAR JUST 38 TRANSACTIONS RESULTED IN 144 MILLION
IN REVENUE FOR THE CITY. >> EVEN WITH THE FUNDS FROM
POPEYE, THE CITY IS FACING A MASSIVE BUDGET DEFICIT AND THE
MAYOR IS CURRENTLY CALLING FOR A $400 MILLION CUT IN CITY
SPENDING AND ELIMINATING NON CORE PROGRAMING.
WITHOUT FUNDS FROM PROP BY MANY RESIDENTS WILL FACE THE
CONSEQUENCES OF THESE SPENDING CUTS AND ELIMINATIONS.
>> FROM THE MAYOR'S OFFICE GIVING A TAX BASE TO THE
WEALTHY DEVELOPERS. >> SUPERVISOR MAHMUD HAS STATED
THAT THE BUILD OUT WILL JUMPSTART DEVELOPMENT
IN AFFORDABLE HOUSING. I WOULD LIKE TO SEE HOW MANY
REAL ESTATE COMPANIES COME TO THE BOARD ASKING YOU TO WAIVE
IMPACT FEES AND LOWER THE NUMBER OF INCLUSIONARY UNITS
BECAUSE THE ECONOMICS JUST DOESN'T PENCIL OUT.
THE BUILD ACT IS A GIVEAWAY TO REAL ESTATE DEVELOPERS WHO ONLY
BUILD UNAFFORDABLE HOUSING. >> I'M SURE THE MAYOR WILL
CONTINUE TO CALL FOR AUSTERITY BUT NOT AUSTERITY FOR ALL.
WHILE GIVING PUBLIC SUBSIDIES AWAY IN THE NAME OF COMMON
SENSE REFORM, PLEASE OPPOSE THE BUILD ACT.
>> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS .
NEXT SPEAKER PLEASE I MADAM MAYOR.
MR. PRESIDENT. MADAM SECRETARY, MY NAME IS
WILLIAM DUFFY. >> I WASN'T THE GUY WHO WASN'T
THE GUY WHO WAS SUPPORTING ALL THE CUTTING ALL THE COMMISSIONS
AND CUTTING IT DOWN TO THE BARE BONES.
WASN'T THAT WASN'T THAT MARK FARRELL AND AM I WRONG THAT HE
HE LOST THE ELECTION? >> YOU KNOW, AS A AS A BIG
PICTURE THING I MEAN I KNOW THERE ARE A LOT OF YOUNG
YOUNGER PEOPLE THAN MYSELF HERE ON THE BOARD NOW I THINK
EVERYONE ACTUALLY. >> BUT YOU KNOW, I THINK THAT
WE'RE TURNING A LOT OF WAYS THE BUDGETS THAT WE'RE TALKING
ABOUT NOW ARE TURNING THE CLOCK BACK TO A VERY MUCH MORE
DIFFICULT TIME THAN THE ONE THAT WE'RE IN NOW.
YOU KNOW, ALL OF THESE SOFT PROGRAMS AND THERE'S A WHOLE
BUNCH OF THEM IN THE TENDERLOIN THAT ARE GETTING CUT.
>> APPARENTLY, YOU KNOW, THEY PROTECT THE SAFETY OF THE
PEOPLE THAT LIVE THERE. >> THEY PROTECT THE SAFETY OF
THE PEOPLE THAT LIVE IN SAN FRANCISCO.
THE THE QUALITY OF LIFE, THE SAFETY.
>> IT'S A LARGE NUMBER OF THINGS.
BUT AND IT IS COMPLEX BUT THEY DO WORK AND I THINK THAT WE'RE
TALKING ABOUT TURNING THE CLOCK BACK TO THE 1960S AND RELIVING
ALL THAT TIME AND IT WAS A VERY VIOLENT TIME.
THERE'S A LOT OF POLITICAL VIOLENCE.
THERE WAS A LOT OF INTERPERSONAL VIOLENCE AND I
THINK THAT THIS ATTACK SO-CALLED ATTACK ON THE
MAYOR IS IT'S KIND OF EMBLEMATIC OF YOU KNOW, PEOPLE
ARE GOING TO BECOME MORE VIOLENT.
>> IS THAT IS THIS IS THAT THE RIGHT THING?
>> ONE MORE THING ABOUT DIAMOND DAVE.
I REALLY LOVED HIM. I NEVER HAD NO IDEA HE WAS SO
OLD. BUT WE WENT TO THE SAME CLINIC,
THE NATIVE AMERICAN HEALTH CLINIC TOGETHER AND HE TOLD ME
ONE THING. WORDS TO LIVE BY.
HE TOLD ME DON'T GO FOR DENTAL SERVICE ON COLUMBUS DAY.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. BEFORE THE NEXT SPEAKER I'LL
JUST ASK IF THERE ARE OTHER MEMBERS OF THE PUBLIC WHO'D
LIKE TO PROVIDE GENERAL PUBLIC COMMENT.
PLEASE LINE UP ON YOUR RIGHT HAND SIDE OF THE CHAMBER.
OTHERWISE THIS MAY BE OUR LAST SPEAKER.
>> WELCOME. >> BONJOUR.
WORK IT. IT WAS A TWO.
VIVE LA FRANCE. >> YOU ARE PRESENTLY A FUTURE
KILLER. YEP.
YES, YOU ARE BUTTIGIEG. I AUTOUR DE SAVOIR FAIRE.
>> BUT COMPETENCE THAT YOUR NERVOUS SYSTEM DID YOU JUST
RETORTED THAT WAS AGGRESSIVE TO WHAT EXTENT YOUR DUSTMAN OR
LUCIANO'S DON'T RELAPSE THE TALLER GIVE UP ON THE LOW TO
DESTRUCTION THE FULL POUVOIR ACTUAL BUCHHOLZ GO AND THE
OFTEN BUT GO
LESBIAN PLUSH ENTRANCE NOTES MAXWELL AT YOU ALL RIGHT MR.
PRESIDENT PUBLIC COMMENT IS NOW CLOSE MADAM CLERK LET'S GO TO
OUR FORD OPTIONAL THAT WITHOUT COMMITTEE REFERENCE AGENDA
PLEASE CALL ITEMS 23 THROUGH 32 ITEMS 23 THROUGH 32 WERE
INTRODUCED FOR ADOPTION BUT WITHOUT COMMITTEE REFERENCE A
UNANIMOUS VOTE IS REQUIRED FOR ADOPTION OF A RESOLUTION ON
FIRST READING TODAY ANY MEMBER MAY REQUIRE A RESOLUTION ON
FIRST READING TO GO TO COMMITTEE SURPRISED DORSEY I'D
LIKE TO SEVERAL ITEM 24 OR SUPERVISOR WALTON SENDING ITEM
28 TO COMMITTEE SUPERVISOR MELGAR I JUST WANTED TO BE
ADDED AS A CO-SPONSOR TO ITEM 24 PLEASE NOTED.
THANK YOU MADAM CLERK. SO SUPERVISOR FILNER THANKS
PRESIDENT. >> I WANTED TO BE ADDED AS A
CO-SPONSOR TO ITEM 24 ALSO NOTED ALL RIGHT MADAM CLERK ON
THE SO ON ALL OF THE ITEMS EXCEPT 24 AND 28 CAN YOU PLEASE
CALL THE ROLL? >> YES.
OKAY. HOLD UP.
SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD CO-SPONSORED A 24 AS WELL PLEASE.
>> LOOKS LIKE CHERYL WANTS TO BE ON THERE.
I THINK I AM ON THERE. ANYBODY ELSE?
OKAY. ALL RIGHT.
SO WHEN EVERYTHING EXCEPT 24 AND 28.
>> MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL THE ROLL.
>> YES, SUPERVISOR DORSEY. THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK.
>> COLLEAGUES, I AM ASKING YOU TO THE SUPERVISOR ROLL CALL.
>> OH, I'M SORRY. >> THIS IS ON THE FOCKER ITEMS
EXCEPT 24 AND 20 EIGHT DORSEY I SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER I
SUPERVISOR MY BOARD MAHMOOD I SUPERVISOR MANDOLIN HI
RANDLEMAN I SUPERVISOR MELGAR I MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SAUDER
SORTER I SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I SUPERVISOR WALTON
WALTON I SUPERVISOR ONE WONG I SUPERVISOR CHEN CHAN I
AND SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN I THERE ARE 11 EYES ALL RIGHT
THEN WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTIONS ARE ADOPTED AND THE
MOTION IS APPROVED. MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM
24 ITEM 24 THIS IS A RESOLUTION TO RECOGNIZE THE MONTH OF MARCH
2026 AS IRANIAN AMERICAN HERITAGE MONTH IN THE CITY
AND COUNTY OF SAN FRANCISCO. >> SUPERVISOR DORSEY OKAY,
THANK YOU PRESIDENT RANDLEMAN COLLEAGUES I AM TODAY ASKING
YOU TO JOIN ME IN SUPPORTING A RESOLUTION RECOGNIZING THE
MONTH OF MARCH AS IRANIAN-AMERICAN HERITAGE MONTH
AND I DO WANT TO EXPRESS MY APPRECIATION TO COLLEAGUES FOR
YOUR CO-SPONSORSHIP. I THINK WE HAVE RUN THE TABLE
AND I THINK THAT'S REALLY AN IMPORTANT STATEMENT FOR THE
COMMUNITY. OUR CITY IS HOME TO A THRIVING
IRANIAN-AMERICAN COMMUNITY WHICH INCLUDES SMALL BUSINESS
OWNERS, ENTREPRENEURS, DOCTORS, ENGINEERS, LAWYERS, EDUCATORS,
EDUCATORS AND SOME REMARKABLE PUBLIC SERVANTS.
ONE OF WHOM WE HEARD FROM IN PUBLIC COMMENT OUR FRIEND
AND FORMER COLLEAGUE SUPERVISOR FORMER SUPERVISOR OFFICER SAFAI
. TOGETHER THESE ARE SAN
FRANCISCANS WHO HAVE SHAPED AND BLESSED OUR CITY
IN NUMBERLESS WAVES WAYS THAT DESERVE TO BE NAMED
AND HONORED. THIS RESOLUTION DOES THAT BUT I
ALSO WANT TO ACKNOWLEDGE THE MOMENT WE ARE IN THE
IRANIAN-AMERICAN COMMUNITY LIKE SO MANY DIASPORA COMMUNITIES
IN THE CITY CARRIES A COMPLICATED RELATIONSHIP WITH
THE COUNTRY OF THEIR HERITAGE, LOVE AND GRIEF, ANGER AND HOPE
OFTEN ALL AT ONCE. EVENTS HAPPENING FAR AWAY HAVE
A WAY OF LANDING VERY CLOSE TO HOME AS WE HEARD IN PUBLIC
COMMENT AND IN MOMENTS LIKE THESE IT MATTERS MORE THAN EVER
WHAT THIS BOARD DOES. IT MATTERS THAT SAN FRANCISCANS
THAT SAN FRANCISCO AND SAN FRANCISCANS ARE ABLE TO SAY
UNEQUIVOCALLY YOU BELONG HERE, YOUR CULTURE IS VALUED AND YOUR
CONTRIBUTIONS ARE CELEBRATED REGARDLESS OF THE HEADLINES.
I ALSO WANT TO ACKNOWLEDGE MY LEGISLATIVE AIDE MOHANA
SOMEBODY WHO DRAFTED THIS RESOLUTION AND WHO HAS WORKED
CLOSELY WITH MEMBERS OF THE COMMUNITY TO HELP BRING IT
FORWARD. SAN FRANCISCO IS AT ITS BEST
WHEN WE MAKE STEAK SPACE FOR THE RICH DIVERSITY OF ALL WHO
CALL OUR CITY HOME. AND WHEN WE JOIN HANDS
IN CELEBRATING THE UNIQUE CULTURAL BLESSINGS OF
COMMUNITIES LIKE THE IRANIAN-AMERICAN COMMUNITY
WHICH CONTRIBUTE SO MUCH TO MAKING US WHO WE ARE, I URGE
YOUR SUPPORT. >> THANK YOU SUPERVISOR DORSEY.
>> WITH THAT I BELIEVE WE CAN TAKE THIS ITEM.
SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL. >> WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED. AND MADAM CLERK, I THINK THAT
TAKES US TO MY QUESTION OF WHETHER WE HAVE ANY IMPERATIVE
AGENDA ITEMS. >> THERE ARE NONE TO REPORT,
MR. PRESIDENT. >> COULD YOU PLEASE READ THE
IN MEMORIAM? YES.
>> ON BEHALF. WELL, TODAY'S MEETING WILL BE
ADJOURNED IN MEMORY OF THE FOLLOWING BELOVED INDIVIDUALS.
ON A MOTION MADE BY SUPERVISOR FIELDER FOR THE LATE DIAMOND
DAVE WHITAKER. A MOTION MADE BY SUPERVISOR
CHERYL FOR THE LATE LIEUTENANT FRANK SKIP LUCIER AND ON BEHALF
OF SUPERVISOR WALTON FOR THE LATE DR. KUMUD BIN MUFFIN
DRAGOMIR DAVE. >> AND MADAM CLERK.
I THINK THAT BRINGS US TO THE END OF OUR AGENDA.
DO WE HAVE ANY FURTHER BUSINESS BEFORE US TODAY?
>> THAT CONCLUDES OUR BUSINESS FOR TODAY.
WELL THEN WE ARE ADJOURNED